<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Perfection on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>https://simbatango.github.io/tags/perfection/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Perfection on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="https://simbatango.github.io/tags/perfection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost perfect</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/08/17/almost-perfect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2009 02:29:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/08/17/almost-perfect/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/stuckincustoms/3037394506/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3234/3037394506_61bff229a4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Anyone care for a dance? by Stuck in Customs, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/stuckincustoms/&#34;&gt; Stuck in Customs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was my first tanda in the milongas with her. In the break between two dances at the legendary milonga at Club Sunderland, I was chatting with la preciosa, who later became one of my dearest tango friends. She asked me if I knew who was dancing (the exhibition) that night, and I confirmed, that yes, of course I knew. It was the very reason I went there that night, in fact. I praised his elegance and skill (I had yet to see or meet his new partner). Yes, she sighed, he is **almost **perfect. I smiled. If someone would be close to perfect, it would be him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I talked to her later about this remark, and how good it was, then she would say no, no, he is perfect. Still, I liked the idea. No tango dancer is really &amp;lsquo;perfect&amp;rsquo;. We all dance our own way. There is no official standard, luckily the tango in the Argentine tradition has remained rich in variation and ways of expression. Becoming perfect is unachievable, yet we never give up trying. Sometimes you will get touched by a gleam of light of perfection, and go after it. If you dare. But clearly, some get much closer to perfection than others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once at a guided tour of a castle, the guide told us about the marvelous floor in the dancing hall, and how much effort was put into making it so beautiful for the king that resided there. Yet - he said - the craftsmen put in a deliberate mistake. They knew the danger of hybris, and were in no position to make it &amp;lsquo;perfect&amp;rsquo;. Almost perfect, yes. Perfect, no.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And after taking lessons with this incredible dancer, the same humbleness with respect to the tango is very striking. No bragging, no easy solution. Simply extremely good teaching. He definitely transformed my dancing. To the better, that is ;-). Through his teaching and his dancing, he reveals great respect for the tango and for the milongueros. And for the women in tango.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some dancers can get &amp;lsquo;too perfect&amp;rsquo;. Everything is right, still something is missing. Never miss a beat, always in balance, gancho here, boleo there, &amp;hellip;two three four, finale and bow to the applause. An element of humanity missing, of emotion, opening up to one&amp;rsquo;s partner, lowering the armor, showing a little vulnerability. &lt;strong&gt;That&lt;/strong&gt; is what moves me. So in this sense, almost perfect is much to prefer to &amp;lsquo;perfect&amp;rsquo; if you understand what I mean. Which is why I loved her comment so much. Simple, yet profound. As is his tango.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>