<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Slogan on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/tags/slogan/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Slogan on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/tags/slogan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>A Better Slogan</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/05/28/a-better-slogan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2010 20:50:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/05/28/a-better-slogan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/66164549@N00/2080363220/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2250/2080363220_d46ea28d4a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The King... by law_keven, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-sa/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/66164549@N00/&#34;&gt; law_keven&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time to upgrade my deejaying slogan. While I still sort of like the tongue in cheek fluffy deejay advertisment in-joke of **&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/01/06/keine-komische-musik/&#34;&gt;Keine komische Musik&lt;/a&gt;, **it has several problems. It is in German, and doesn&amp;rsquo;t really translate well. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure people get the joke, they may not even understand German. Also it may come off a bit negative. I would prefer a more positive note, so to speak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still in my somewhat sarcastic and protestish mood, I came up with **The Non-Alternative Alternative. **While it is probably somehow accurate, it also fails the non-negativity criterion, and while the recursive definition is all geeky and nice, it is sort of syllogistic, so better move on to something more straight to the point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resolving the recursion and going back to the basics, what about **Puro Tango &lt;strong&gt;or in English &lt;/strong&gt;Pure Tango**? This has the nice property that it translates well to English. It is close to the spirit of my milongas, tango pure and simple. The best music. But it is not quite true. Besides vals and milonga, I occationally play other music as well: Chacarera has recently become popular in my community, and I have played Cumbia in the past, some times Rock &amp;lsquo;n Roll, Swing or Salsa music. Despite rumors to the contrary I don&amp;rsquo;t even have a strict rule never to play electrotango, it&amp;rsquo;s just that I always find something better in my collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the last milonga I deejayed, a friend told me how one of the guys &amp;ldquo;complained&amp;rdquo; that he never got to rest. &amp;ndash;He&amp;rsquo;s killing me! That was a great compliment, I think, so maybe I could use it&amp;hellip;  **DJ Simba: **&lt;strong&gt;Killing You Softly.&lt;/strong&gt; That would be something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I deejay under a different alias, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work quite that well in that case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;****Then I remembered something from a &lt;a href=&#34;http://tangopilgrim.com/2010/04/danceable-music-and-dance-ability/&#34;&gt;discussion over at tangopilgrim&lt;/a&gt;. Great (tango) dance music should make you want to move, but it should also be &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/moving&#34;&gt;moving&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;La música que te mueve&lt;/strong&gt; could work. It translates well to English, for instance as &lt;strong&gt;Moving Music&lt;/strong&gt; or alternatively &lt;strong&gt;(The )Music that Moves You&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally at the essence of what it&amp;rsquo;s all about. It&amp;rsquo;s positive, I get an alliteration and it translates well, also to my native language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you think? How do you native speakers feel about the two last ones?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>