<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dancing for the Woman on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/categories/dancing-for-the-woman/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dancing for the Woman on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2010 21:13:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/categories/dancing-for-the-woman/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Fundamentals of Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/04/14/three-fundamentals-of-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2010 21:13:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/04/14/three-fundamentals-of-tango/</guid>
      <description>by Peter Forret
Whenever I hear the postulate that everything in tango is either a step forward, a step backwards or a side step, I get a little irritated. I know what they mean, and it&amp;rsquo;s not that it is entirely wrong, it&amp;rsquo;s rather that it is incomplete, and it tends to send people off in a very step oriented direction. But I have written about that before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How less becomes more</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/01/how-less-becomes-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 20:02:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/01/how-less-becomes-more/</guid>
      <description>by hooverine
There was something she said that stayed with me. So well put. &amp;lsquo;When he leads a step, say backwards for the woman&amp;rsquo;, Graciela said, &amp;lsquo;then there is one possibility: going backwards. There are not three possible steps. Not three, not two. One.&amp;rsquo;
All the time I see so called &amp;lsquo;advanced&amp;rsquo; dancers, throwing their partners around, the women looking like nervous chicken trying to guess the right thing to do for each and every step.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost perfect</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/17/almost-perfect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2009 02:29:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/17/almost-perfect/</guid>
      <description>by Stuck in Customs
It was my first tanda in the milongas with her. In the break between two dances at the legendary milonga at Club Sunderland, I was chatting with la preciosa, who later became one of my dearest tango friends. She asked me if I knew who was dancing (the exhibition) that night, and I confirmed, that yes, of course I knew. It was the very reason I went there that night, in fact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A morir</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/19/a-morir/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2009 01:24:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/19/a-morir/</guid>
      <description>by Xanboozled
   _--When a man walks nicely, the woman dies in his embrace._   --_When a man walks badly, the woman wants to die._ HT: yy</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pas de finesse...</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/19/pas-de-finesse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2008 12:55:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/19/pas-de-finesse/</guid>
      <description>by Jayanth Sharma
Staying in Buenos Aires for a few months provided several eye-openers. One of the great revelations was concerning the logic of the dance, or rather the lack of it, and how this adds spice to the dance:
We were taking lessons with various teachers, with very different philosophies with respect to tango, how to dance it and how to learn it. Gustavo Naveira, the great master, dissected each step carefully, explaining exactly how and why and which steps were crossed and which were open etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Follow the leader?</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/03/follow-the-leader/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2008 21:15:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/03/follow-the-leader/</guid>
      <description>Johanna&amp;rsquo;s comment and her subsequent post on leads and follows inspired me to write an entire post in addition to the comment in her blog. In her post (and follow-up) she argues why you would want to use the terms lead and follow for the two dancers in a tango embrace, and discuss howthey are surrounded with angst.
I find it to be the terms man and woman that are surrounded by angst, and that is probably the reason people use lead and follow as euphemisms for man and woman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Masquerade</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/31/masquerade/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2008 21:07:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/31/masquerade/</guid>
      <description>Who are you when you are dancing? Are you the leader? The follower? The man? The woman? I was once confronted with my using the terminology man/woman in class. The person complaining said that she was dancing a role (she was dancing the man&amp;rsquo;s part) and that was the role of the leader.
I know this easily gets messy, but I never liked the euphemism leader/follower when what we are talking about is a man and a woman in most cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Putting the baby to sleep</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/14/putting-the-baby-to-sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 20:49:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/14/putting-the-baby-to-sleep/</guid>
      <description>I quite recently became a father, and the poor child is exposed to a lot of tango music, naturally. (And I get out to dance less, hence the blog writing.) Before he was born, I used to talk about how we would practice walking together, he and I. Now this is how it turned out:
The scene: Unpatiant 12 days old boy, waiting for his mother to get ready for breast-feeding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confiteria La Ideal en BBC</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/23/confiteria-la-ideal-en-bbc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2008 20:49:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/23/confiteria-la-ideal-en-bbc/</guid>
      <description>Another good documentary about tango. I enjoyed it a lot. Some of the interesting scenes are available on youtube, but the documentary itself was quite hard to get hold of. As far as I could determine, it is not available for sale, not even on ebay, so you better know one of them pirates or use your imagination ;-)
I am quite impressed by how ordinary dancers are able to express what tango means to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clichés</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/06/cliches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2008 10:31:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/06/cliches/</guid>
      <description>Ever since I started dancing, the topic of tango clichés has fascinated me. The rose in mouth, castanets, head flicks, dramatic poses are all parts of what usually pops into people&amp;rsquo;s heads when they hear the word tango. Where did they come from, and why did they stick? Going through a lot of Hollywood production at least gives a partial answer, and Rudolph Valentino is one of the people to blame, the rose in mouth appears in the film Blood and sand, where he plays a bullfighter, while the film he dances the tango is _Four horsemen of the apocalypse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gavito Dixit</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/06/01/gavito-dixit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 15:26:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/06/01/gavito-dixit/</guid>
      <description>Gavito Dixit I ¿Bailaste el tango de tu vida esta noche? No bailes más… El tangauta #129
Gavito Dixit II El tango está entre paso y paso, allí donde se escuchan los silencios y cantan las musas. El tangauta #130
Gavito Dixit III El hombre debe saber que baila para ella,y al hacerlo, hace que ella se vea como una reina. Sólo así será el rey. El tangauta #131</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>