<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dancing For The Woman on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/categories/dancing-for-the-woman/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dancing For The Woman on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/categories/dancing-for-the-woman/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Fundamentals of Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/04/14/three-fundamentals-of-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2010 21:13:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/04/14/three-fundamentals-of-tango/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/pforret/4489579181/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4001/4489579181_e399aebb7b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Brussels Tango Festival - Saturday -Exhi by Peter Forret, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/pforret/&#34;&gt; Peter Forret&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever I hear the postulate that everything in tango is either a step forward, a step backwards or a side step, I get a little irritated. I know what they mean, and it&amp;rsquo;s not that it is entirely wrong, it&amp;rsquo;s rather that it is incomplete, and it tends to send people off in a very step oriented direction. But &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2008/11/09/nuevo-tools-nuevo-problems/&#34;&gt;I have written about that before&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me instead remind you of three quite different fundamentals in the tango, or maybe rather governing principles. It is a very important insight.  Simple, yet profound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dancing the tango, you have three partners. And tango is about embrace, embrace and embrace. In order to dance well, you need to embrace them all:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;embrace-your-partner&#34;&gt;Embrace your partner&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is all about the woman.  No partner, no dancing. Respect your partner, take care of her and protect her, make it a pleasant experience for her. Listen to her, feel her presence, wishes and desires&amp;hellip; In return, she will make you both beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;embrace-the-music&#34;&gt;Embrace the music&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The movement has to come from the music. Without music we would just stand there, hugging each other. That can be nice, too, of course, but it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be dancing. Listen to what the music tells you and find your inspiration there. Then embrace the music and dance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;embrace-the-dance-floor&#34;&gt;Embrace the dance floor&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are not alone on the floor. We are dancing with the other couples on the floor as well. Respect their space, keep moving at a reasonable pace and avoid dangerous movements. (The &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/KISS_principle&#34;&gt;KISS principle&lt;/a&gt; is apt here.)  In return you will feel the energy of the floor. Sometimes people complain about dancers not socializing enough, but as I see it, sharing the floor is also socializing. Embrace your fellow dancers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Naveira-Salas model may help you to learn steps. Which can be useful. &lt;em&gt;To learn to dance, you need to learn how to embrace your three partners.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS: I am talking about social dancing here. For performance/stage dancing, I guess you could substitute dance floor with audience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How less becomes more</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/01/how-less-becomes-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 20:02:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/01/how-less-becomes-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/hooverine/2802881741/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3199/2802881741_b187d6c530.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;less is more by hooverine, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/hooverine/&#34;&gt; hooverine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was something she said that stayed with me. So well put. &amp;lsquo;When he leads a step, say backwards for the woman&amp;rsquo;, Graciela said, &amp;lsquo;then there is one possibility: going backwards. There are not three possible steps. Not three, not two. &lt;strong&gt;One.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the time I see so called &amp;lsquo;advanced&amp;rsquo; dancers, throwing their partners around, the women looking like nervous chicken trying to guess the right thing to do for each and every step. It looks like they are thinking: Did he mean here, or here, or maybe here&amp;hellip; .Waiting till the last possible moment before moving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then they teach &amp;lsquo;active following&amp;rsquo;, taking the opportunity to teach women to take over control, thereby totally missing the point. It is like deciding which step next is more important than anything else, so we have to make sure we decide 50% each, and to make sure we pass control back and forth all through the tango. Yeah, that sounds nice. My turn! Your turn! My turn!&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the lead is absolutely crystal clear and make﻿s the woman 100% confident she knows exactly what step is led, she will feel like she has all the time in the world to shape the way she makes that step, thus enabling her to express the music. This is what giving the woman space is about, not sending control back and forth. It is a simplification, but we often say that in tango, the man decides &amp;lsquo;what&amp;rsquo;, the woman &amp;lsquo;how&amp;rsquo;. And you have probably heard that in tango, the &lt;strong&gt;how&lt;/strong&gt; is more important than the &lt;strong&gt;what&lt;/strong&gt;, no?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the man is actually listening (figuratively speaking) to the woman throughout the dance, he will feel her suggestions and ideas, maybe even before she knows it herself and vice versa. That is when the magic occurs. Passing a stick back and forth is not very magical. Well, maybe if it were a wand&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trouble is, I am afraid you have to dance with some really, really good dancers to understand what I mean. Then you may feel how by taking away, you add something. Remove some possibilities and open up for others. Remove the noise and free the signal. Removing all unnecessary cruft from one&amp;rsquo;s dancing is one of the things that make tango a life long project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the magic that arises makes it totally worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost perfect</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/17/almost-perfect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2009 02:29:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/17/almost-perfect/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/stuckincustoms/3037394506/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3234/3037394506_61bff229a4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Anyone care for a dance? by Stuck in Customs, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/stuckincustoms/&#34;&gt; Stuck in Customs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was my first tanda in the milongas with her. In the break between two dances at the legendary milonga at Club Sunderland, I was chatting with la preciosa, who later became one of my dearest tango friends. She asked me if I knew who was dancing (the exhibition) that night, and I confirmed, that yes, of course I knew. It was the very reason I went there that night, in fact. I praised his elegance and skill (I had yet to see or meet his new partner). Yes, she sighed, he is **almost **perfect. I smiled. If someone would be close to perfect, it would be him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I talked to her later about this remark, and how good it was, then she would say no, no, he is perfect. Still, I liked the idea. No tango dancer is really &amp;lsquo;perfect&amp;rsquo;. We all dance our own way. There is no official standard, luckily the tango in the Argentine tradition has remained rich in variation and ways of expression. Becoming perfect is unachievable, yet we never give up trying. Sometimes you will get touched by a gleam of light of perfection, and go after it. If you dare. But clearly, some get much closer to perfection than others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once at a guided tour of a castle, the guide told us about the marvelous floor in the dancing hall, and how much effort was put into making it so beautiful for the king that resided there. Yet - he said - the craftsmen put in a deliberate mistake. They knew the danger of hybris, and were in no position to make it &amp;lsquo;perfect&amp;rsquo;. Almost perfect, yes. Perfect, no.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And after taking lessons with this incredible dancer, the same humbleness with respect to the tango is very striking. No bragging, no easy solution. Simply extremely good teaching. He definitely transformed my dancing. To the better, that is ;-). Through his teaching and his dancing, he reveals great respect for the tango and for the milongueros. And for the women in tango.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some dancers can get &amp;lsquo;too perfect&amp;rsquo;. Everything is right, still something is missing. Never miss a beat, always in balance, gancho here, boleo there, &amp;hellip;two three four, finale and bow to the applause. An element of humanity missing, of emotion, opening up to one&amp;rsquo;s partner, lowering the armor, showing a little vulnerability. &lt;strong&gt;That&lt;/strong&gt; is what moves me. So in this sense, almost perfect is much to prefer to &amp;lsquo;perfect&amp;rsquo; if you understand what I mean. Which is why I loved her comment so much. Simple, yet profound. As is his tango.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A morir</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/19/a-morir/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2009 01:24:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/19/a-morir/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/xanboozled/1234201847/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1008/1234201847_ff1e1561e3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;More fun with Mantis by Xanboozled, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/xanboozled/&#34;&gt; Xanboozled&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

&gt; 
&gt; 

_--When a man walks nicely, the woman dies in his embrace._
&gt; 
&gt; 
--_When a man walks badly, the woman wants to die._&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HT: &lt;a href=&#34;http://tango.yyquest.net/techniques/2009/more-on-walking/&#34;&gt;yy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pas de finesse...</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/19/pas-de-finesse.../</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2008 12:55:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/19/pas-de-finesse.../</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jayanthsharma/501996653/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/202/501996653_a49cf868cc.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;There’s no charge to get charged by Jayanth Sharma, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/jayanthsharma/&#34;&gt; Jayanth Sharma&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Staying in Buenos Aires for a few months provided several eye-openers. One of the great revelations was concerning the logic of the dance, or rather the lack of it, and how this adds spice to the dance:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were taking lessons with various teachers, with very different philosophies with respect to tango, how to dance it and how to learn it. Gustavo Naveira, the great master, dissected each step carefully, explaining exactly how and why and which steps were crossed and which were open etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming then to another lesson with the quite different teachers, I asked once why I was to go with this foot, and not with the other, as I could not make any sense of this particular combination. Jorge looked at me, as if he did not understand the question. Why? Because the step is like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only later did it make any sense to me. It was actually when los Disparis showed another step. A step where the man deliberately hides which foot he has weight on. To make it less obvious which direction the turn will be.  Going in the not so logical direction. Or perhaps not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding a touch of finesse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember several years earlier, another tango teacher told us that the man should always have a little surprise for the woman, a sorpresita, to make her feel she was something special. And in the same way, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t hurt having a sorpresita for the spectators as well. At least if you are giving a show, that is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this leads to one reason I find a lot of performances unbearably boring. The dancers do a lot of things, trying to be innovative. But it shows a mile a head where they are going. No sorpresita. Lacking even the slightest hint of finesse.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Follow the leader?</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/03/follow-the-leader/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2008 21:15:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/03/follow-the-leader/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/11/shepherd.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/11/shepherd.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Johanna&amp;rsquo;s comment and her subsequent post on leads and follows inspired me to write an entire post in addition to the comment in her blog. &lt;a href=&#34;http://tangowritemight.blogspot.com/2008/11/lead-and-follow.html&#34;&gt;In her post&lt;/a&gt; (and &lt;a href=&#34;http://tangowritemight.blogspot.com/2008/11/lead-and-follow-part-2.html&#34;&gt;follow-up&lt;/a&gt;) she argues why you would want to use the terms lead and follow for the two dancers in a tango embrace, and discuss howthey are surrounded with angst.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find it to be the terms man and woman that are surrounded by angst, and that is probably  the reason people use lead and follow as euphemisms for man and woman. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know if I should laugh or cry when I heard an American guy that was quite tall say after watching the milonga dance floor: -Oh, there is a tall follow. What he meant was obviously a tall woman, one that he might want to dance with. Why couldn&amp;rsquo;t he just say that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The argentines never use these terms, the sometimes say the one that leads or the man leads and correspondingly the one that follows or the woman follows. And I prefer the terms man and woman, as I belive they refer to the entire person, and not just to one single aspect of the dance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why the need to argue about semantics? Of course it does not &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; matter, you may call it whatever you like, yin/yang, A and B or whatever. But language forms the way we think, and in my experience the leader/follower terminology is limiting rather than opening new possibilities. In the quest of making opening both roles for both men and women, something gets lost. When tango gets genderless, it loses much of its character and history. When changing parts, I prefer acknowledging what is happening, not pretending it has no history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I don&amp;rsquo;t like about the lead(er)/follow(er) terminology is the implicit expectation it often creates that one role is superior to the other (for some reason, being the leader appears to be more attractive). The other reason is that it puts so much emphasis on the acts of leading and following. I can understand the use in the classroom where you have to make a simplified point to get the message through, but I still prefer to use terms like &lt;em&gt;the one that follows&lt;/em&gt; and similar, as they make it clear that leading and following is just one part in many that is important to get in place in order to succeed in dancing. And I believe that what is learnt early tends to stick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think Johanna and I agree completely on the tango dancing part, just not on the terminology. The dance is very much like a conversation. But being a listener doesn&amp;rsquo;t share the same negative connotations as being a follower.  I don&amp;rsquo;t think it is enough to give an explanation why the terminology is perfectly allright when the results it produces are not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just one example, it is not enough to lead as a man, you have to follow as well (Gavito said: I lead, but I follow). The roles are not as clear cut, it is all more complex. And in the attempt to solve one imagined problem (that of gender), another is created.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/koalie/879806620/&#34;&gt;Photo&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/koalie/&#34;&gt;koalie&lt;/a&gt;@flickr, &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/deed.en&#34;&gt;CC-licensed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Masquerade</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/31/masquerade/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2008 21:07:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/31/masquerade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/10/masquerade.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/10/masquerade.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who are you when you are dancing? Are you the leader? The follower? The man? The woman? I was once confronted with my using the terminology man/woman in class. The person complaining said that she was dancing a &lt;em&gt;role&lt;/em&gt; (she was dancing the man&amp;rsquo;s part) and that was the role of the leader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know this easily gets messy, but I never liked the euphemism leader/follower when what we are talking about is a man and a woman in most cases. Being a follower implies being passive, and sort of gives the leader higher value. When it can easily be argued that it is quite the oposite. The man dances _ for the woman_, remember? &lt;em&gt;She&lt;/em&gt; is the high value part of the relationship. To be cherished and taken good care of. Embraced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, with love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few years back I took a class about communication and backleading. We were asked to try and verbalize what we were communicating in our dance. While I did not like the lesson much, something interesting came up. I tried finding the words, my mood maybe, happy or sad, if I had a good day at work and so on. The interesting part was the answer from another couple at the class. They dismissed the whole idea of the communication comprising more than &lt;em&gt;mere movements&lt;/em&gt;. While they were very good dancers, I think they miss out on something very important if they limit the dance to merely movements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a related note, Javier in a class talked about daring to enjoy embracing and walking together, and how using too many steps like sacadas etc would create a distance between the two in the couple. And he was not talking about the physical distance between the dancers, but about not connecting with your partner on a deeper level than merely doing steps together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lower the mask and dare dance as yourself. Don&amp;rsquo;t play games. Dare showing your true self. You might be lucky and get the same in return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&#34;http://flickr.com/photos/36291563@N00/&#34;&gt;August Rush&lt;/a&gt;@flickr, &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/deed.en&#34;&gt;CC-licensed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Putting the baby to sleep</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/14/putting-the-baby-to-sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 20:49:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/14/putting-the-baby-to-sleep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I quite recently became a father, and the poor child is exposed to a lot of tango music, naturally. (And I get out to dance less, hence the blog writing.) Before he was born, I used to talk about how we would practice walking together, he and I. Now this is how it turned out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scene: Unpatiant 12 days old boy, waiting for his mother to get ready for breast-feeding. Father to find something to entertain the child, and preferably also himself in the meantime. Time for tango. Di Sarli&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Nido Gaucho&lt;/em&gt; on the stereo, practicing the tango walk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boy seemed to enjoy the experience, I would say. Not as big eyes as with the milonga a few days earlyer (yes - really). After one tango and a half, he became more quiet. A few other songs from the same album, then the &lt;em&gt;Porteño y bailarín&lt;/em&gt; album from the start. The boy fell asleep in my arms. And I got to practice my walk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The funny thing about this, is that having a baby in your arms, getting it to sleep is a quite common metaphor for the way the woman should be held in the embrace. Soft, yet firm and secure.  I know at least El &amp;ldquo;Negro&amp;rdquo; Capello and Javier Rodríguez have used this metaphor. The thing is, I spent quite a lot of time practicing my tango embrace, but not making babies sleep. I got the idea, of course, but now I could apply the metaphor in the reverse direction, using my tango skills to get the boy to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, I fell asleep quite happily that night myself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confiteria La Ideal en BBC</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/23/confiteria-la-ideal-en-bbc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2008 20:49:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/23/confiteria-la-ideal-en-bbc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another good documentary about tango. I enjoyed it a lot. Some of the interesting scenes are available on youtube, but the documentary itself was quite hard to get hold of. As far as I could determine, it is not available for sale, not even on ebay, so you better know one of them pirates or use your imagination ;-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am quite impressed by how ordinary dancers are able to express what tango means to them. I always find it hard to describe what in tango I love so much or why I came to be obsessed with tango.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it made me long for Buenos Aires. A lot. And that hurt. But it was still a good experience, a tango experience I suppose.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/1TufSIR3onU&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;



&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/7r1mPWczWPk&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;



&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/y5CmBLdEY9A&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;



&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/T5_RnRny8kI&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clichés</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/06/clich%C3%A9s/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2008 10:31:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/06/clich%C3%A9s/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever since I started dancing, the topic of tango clichés has fascinated me. The rose in mouth, castanets, head flicks, dramatic poses are all parts of what usually pops into people&amp;rsquo;s heads when they hear the word tango. Where did they come from, and why did they stick? Going through a lot of Hollywood production at least gives a partial answer, and Rudolph Valentino is one of the people to blame, the rose in mouth appears in the film &lt;em&gt;Blood and sand&lt;/em&gt;, where he plays a bullfighter, while the film he dances the tango is _Four horsemen of the apocalypse. _The tango in &lt;em&gt;Some like it hot&lt;/em&gt; must have reinforced the image further into the public memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what lies behind the clichés, do they reveal something of interest, which we may overlook, just because the cliché is so easily dismissed? Could the tango have more important influence from the flamenco than is commonly acknowledged? The rose at least played a role in the real tango porteño in the way that the orchestra of Pugliese used a single rose on the piano during their performances to mark the maestro&amp;rsquo;s absence while he was held in prison for his political beliefs. The head flicks seem to come from the ballroom version of tango, and to my knowledge they have little relation to the &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; tango. Many of the dramatic poses, though, could have their roots in early tango moves such as cortes and quebradas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/images/pugliese_ausencia.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Osvaldo Pugliese in absentia&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, many sayings about tango, are often dismissed as being &lt;em&gt;merely clichés&lt;/em&gt;, but I have found that many of them go deeper than we first think. That tango is really about dancing for the woman is one such statement. Often heard, rarely seen outside Buenos Aires, is my experience. Even by those who say it.  I heard women talk about this for years, &lt;em&gt;X dances for himself&lt;/em&gt; etc. It took me many years before I started noticing what they were &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; talking about. But when I finally realized, it transformed my way of seeing tango, both my own and others&amp;rsquo;. It may appear superficial, a subtle adjustment, a cliché. In fact, what is needed is a fundamental change. Starting to dance for the woman, rather for one self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now read those &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/index.php/2008/06/01/gavito-dixit/&#34;&gt;Gavito quotes&lt;/a&gt; again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gavito Dixit</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/06/01/gavito-dixit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 15:26:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/06/01/gavito-dixit/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;gavito-dixit-i&#34;&gt;Gavito Dixit I&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;¿Bailaste el tango de tu vida esta noche?

No bailes más…&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://eltangauta.com&#34;&gt;El tangauta&lt;/a&gt; #129&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;gavito-dixit-ii&#34;&gt;Gavito Dixit II&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;El tango está entre paso y paso,
allí donde se escuchan
los silencios y cantan las musas.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://eltangauta.com&#34;&gt;El tangauta&lt;/a&gt; #130&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;gavito-dixit-iii&#34;&gt;Gavito Dixit III&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;El hombre debe saber que
baila para ella,y al hacerlo,
hace que ella se vea
como una reina.

Sólo así
será el rey.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://eltangauta.com&#34;&gt;El tangauta&lt;/a&gt; #131&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;gavito-dixit-iv&#34;&gt;Gavito Dixit IV&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;El hombre en el tango
es la columna,
es la fuerza, es la dignidad.
La mujer es la belleza
la sensualidad, la sinuosidad.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://eltangauta.com&#34;&gt;El tangauta&lt;/a&gt; #132&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;gavito-dixit-v&#34;&gt;Gavito Dixit V&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;El tango se baila al compás
del corazón: tic-tac.

Solamente el sentimiento le dá
comprensión y belleza
que es lo que se da entre lo musical
y lo poético, y lo diferencia
de lo burdo y lo mecánico.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://eltangauta.com&#34;&gt;El tangauta&lt;/a&gt; #133&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;gavito-dixit-vi&#34;&gt;Gavito Dixit VI&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Ser tu propio Picasso.
Buscar en la simplicidad
y belleza,
como una pintura de Matisse.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://eltangauta.com&#34;&gt;El tangauta&lt;/a&gt; #134&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;gavito-dixit-vii&#34;&gt;Gavito Dixit VII&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;La música, profunda inspiradora del canto
y del movimiento:
el bajo es el paso del hombre, el violín es el cuerpo de la mujer,
el piano es el paseo de la mano por el parque
y el bandoneón, al que no se lo sigue, es una pompa de jabón
y nos introducimos en ella sin romperla, sin tocarla, para no perder su magia y su espíritu.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://eltangauta.com&#34;&gt;El tangauta&lt;/a&gt; #135&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;gavito-dixit-viii&#34;&gt;Gavito Dixit VIII&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;El tango tiene su gramática.
Comienza con letra mayúscula,
pausa, exclamación,
admiración, acento y punto final.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://eltangauta.com&#34;&gt;El tangauta&lt;/a&gt; #136&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;gavito-dixit-ix&#34;&gt;Gavito Dixit IX&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Cuando dejás de bailar el tiempo,
es cuando comenzás a bailar el sentimiento.
El sentimiento no tiene tiempo:
tiene alma, tiene espíritu.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://eltangauta.com&#34;&gt;El tangauta&lt;/a&gt; #137&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>