<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Buenos Aires on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/categories/buenos-aires/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Buenos Aires on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2011 18:54:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/categories/buenos-aires/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of the Cabeceo Part III: When in Rome...</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/10/20/the-art-of-the-cabeceo-part-iii-when-in-rome/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2011 18:54:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/10/20/the-art-of-the-cabeceo-part-iii-when-in-rome/</guid>
      <description>by Bsivad
As the music of the cortina fades out, she glances over the tables on the opposite side of the dance floor. Refreshes her memory of where the different dancers she watched on the floor are seated. Preparing to try and catch the eye of one of her favorite partners as the music starts for the next tanda.
Her eyes move along the tables, she is nodding to her self, yes, yes, maybe&amp;hellip; her eyes reach the corner of the dance floor, and she quickly moves on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Campeones mundiales de tango salon 2010: Maria Ines Bogado &amp; Sebastian Jimenez </title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/09/19/campeones-mundiales-de-tango-salon-2010-maria-ines-bogado-sebastian-jimenez/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2010 21:16:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/09/19/campeones-mundiales-de-tango-salon-2010-maria-ines-bogado-sebastian-jimenez/</guid>
      <description>This is no longer news, of course, but I am finally catching up after being on vacations with no internet access (which was actually very nice!).
My congratulations to these beautiful dancers (that I wrote about before)!
The jury consisted of Eduardo Arquimbau, Julio Duplaa, Julio Balmaceda, el Nene Masci, Pablo Inza, Ana Maria Schapira y Javier Rodríguez, according to 2xtango.com. I appears that some find it shocking that someone so young won the championship (Sebastian is 18).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations! | ¡Felicitaciones!</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/05/23/congratulations-felicitaciones/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2010 07:13:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/05/23/congratulations-felicitaciones/</guid>
      <description>The final of the campeonato de la ciudad (formerly campeonato metropoletano) was last night, and I am happy to see that Sebastián &amp;amp; Ines did well. Felicitaciones, chicos!
The full list of the winners is available here. The winners are:
 Alberto Markus &amp;amp; Ana María Polito (&amp;ldquo;Tango Salon&amp;rdquo; Senior)
 Lucas Carrizo &amp;amp; María Paula Tejeda (&amp;ldquo;Tango Salón&amp;rdquo; Adulto)
 Ariel Manzanares &amp;amp; Daniela Cerquides (&amp;ldquo;Milonga&amp;rdquo;)
 Sebastián Jimenez &amp;amp; María Inés Bogado (&amp;ldquo;Vals&amp;rdquo;)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience the breadth of tango in Buenos Aires</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/03/24/experience-the-breadth-of-tango-in-buenos-aires/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 12:54:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/03/24/experience-the-breadth-of-tango-in-buenos-aires/</guid>
      <description>by Simba tango
A friend is going to Buenos Aires for the first time this week, and I sent her some information about where to go, encouraging her to experience the breadth of tango in Buenos Aires. So many people get stuck in one small part of the tango world and never experience anything else. When they come back, they believe they know how the tango in Buenos Aires is&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tempting...</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/01/13/tempting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2010 21:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/01/13/tempting/</guid>
      <description>by Leo T.
First day at work. First day in my old office for over nine months. On my desk is a roll of paper. I chat with the guy I&amp;rsquo;m sharing office with, and he tells me that my colleague in the office next door left it for me. Said colleague must have heard us talking, and enters the office. &amp;ndash;The organizer gave it to me, and I brought it back for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>P.H. Shoes</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/01/04/p-h-shoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2010 01:52:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/01/04/p-h-shoes/</guid>
      <description>I got the shoe factory P.H. recommended from several reliable sources, unfortunately I got the directions a little late, so we&amp;rsquo;ll see if I make it in time. Anyway, as a reference for next visit, here it is:
Grito de Asencio 3602, Pompeya - Buenos Aires
Tel/Fax: 4911-0295
The colectivo (bus) 160 goes there, according to the owner of the shoes in the bag above.
[xmlgm {http://maps.google.com/maps/ms?vps=2&amp;amp;jsv=196c&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;msa=0&amp;amp;output=nl&amp;amp;msid=112630563826716696064.00047bcc8224b458afdf1} width=500;height=400}]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buenos Aires (tango) murales</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/01/03/buenos-aires-tango-murales/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2010 01:12:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/01/03/buenos-aires-tango-murales/</guid>
      <description>by Simba tango
Several places in Buenos Aires, you will find paintings covering an entire wall, called &amp;lsquo;murales&amp;rsquo;. They have a long history in Buenos Aires, the oldest were painted for the churches of the city in the 1700s and 1800s. In the beginning of the 20th century, they were often used to portray fight against oppression, think Picasso&amp;rsquo;s Guernica. Less political, but as Buenos Aires is the home of tango, there are of course several paintings featuring tango music and dance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buenos Aires Street Art</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/28/buenos-aires-street-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2009 16:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/28/buenos-aires-street-art/</guid>
      <description>by Simba tango
I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share some photos from the streets of Buenos Aires where there you can often see the kind of graffitti made with stencils. Among the motifs I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered are tango in the incarnation of Osvaldo Pugliese and a new electrotango band called tranxgo, football icon Maradona, not so subtle drug references and lots of other stuff.
[flickr-gallery mode=&amp;ldquo;photoset&amp;rdquo; photoset=&amp;ldquo;72157622958599173&amp;rdquo;]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going, going, and...</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/10/31/going-going-and/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2009 23:55:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/10/31/going-going-and/</guid>
      <description>by Koluso
The airplane takes off with a roar.
Passing over woods.
Passing over cities.
Passing over lakes.
Passing over farmlands.
Passing over oceans.
Leaving a white stripe in the clear blue sky.
Going.
Going.
And gooone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango and Toddler in Buenos Aires</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/15/tango-and-toddler-in-buenos-aires/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2009 00:03:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/15/tango-and-toddler-in-buenos-aires/</guid>
      <description>by salvoguille
Dear readers: I need your advice: We consider ourselves to find our way around in Buenos Aires fairly well after several previous stays there. This time, however, there is something different. We are no longer a couple going to the milongas every night. We are a small family.
Strolling with or without purpose in the streets of our beloved city we can still do, enjoying café con leche while watching people walk past, too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comme il faut (the shoes)</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/26/comme-il-faut-the-shoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2009 03:24:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/26/comme-il-faut-the-shoes/</guid>
      <description>by Simba tango
What I do understand: People (men and women) are crazy about these shoes. They look (and are) extremely sharp, sexy, are light and well balanced. In other words perfect for dancing. An image of exclusivity also helps, although it has faded a little the last few years.
What I don&amp;rsquo;t understand: Why the competition hasn&amp;rsquo;t caught up. It surely can&amp;rsquo;t be that hard? After all, we are not talking rocket science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nueve de julio</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/09/nueve-de-julio/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2009 05:01:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/09/nueve-de-julio/</guid>
      <description>  by Simba tango
Happy independence day, Argentina!
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Body parts</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/22/body-parts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2009 20:02:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/22/body-parts/</guid>
      <description>by Balakov
Privates can be tough. Very useful, but tough.
On our first trip to Buenos Aires, my wife and I took privates with Julio &amp;amp; Corina, and we worked on the basics. Of course. We learnt a lot, but it was so much to think about. So much we did wrong. So much to fix.
For my own sake, it felt like they deconstructed my whole body, just to leave the parts on the floor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pas de finesse...</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/19/pas-de-finesse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2008 12:55:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/19/pas-de-finesse/</guid>
      <description>by Jayanth Sharma
Staying in Buenos Aires for a few months provided several eye-openers. One of the great revelations was concerning the logic of the dance, or rather the lack of it, and how this adds spice to the dance:
We were taking lessons with various teachers, with very different philosophies with respect to tango, how to dance it and how to learn it. Gustavo Naveira, the great master, dissected each step carefully, explaining exactly how and why and which steps were crossed and which were open etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango magazines -- preparing for Buenos Aires</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/19/tango-magazines-preparing-for-buenos-aires/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2008 22:19:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/19/tango-magazines-preparing-for-buenos-aires/</guid>
      <description>Some of our students are going to Buenos Aires tomorrow. Oh the memories&amp;hellip;
I made sure they were equipped with the latest editions of El tangauta and B.A. Tango, giving a good overview over the happenings in November and December. They were always hard to get, even if they are given away for free, it could easily take a couple of weeks before we got hold of an issue. Now, they are available online, and one can prepare for the first week at home or on the plane down there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 Tangos -- Adios Buenos Aires</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/19/12-tangos-adios-buenos-aires/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2008 17:06:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/19/12-tangos-adios-buenos-aires/</guid>
      <description>The documentary 12 tangos was just released in international version on DVD. It is a documentary, and the Adios Buenos Aires part of the title is somehow more accurate with regards to the content of the film. If you are looking for the Buena Vista Social Club of tango, you will be disappointed. There are no interviews with musicians, and only a few of the oldtimers participate in the orchestra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I started DJing</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/17/how-i-started-djing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2008 15:44:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/17/how-i-started-djing/</guid>
      <description>by AllegaertMe
When I started dancing tango, the &amp;ldquo;milonga&amp;rdquo; was in a café where we basically heard the same double cd over and over and over. In general, everybody knew exactly what song came next and started humming on the next song before it started. Knowing the music is all good, but, well&amp;hellip;
-I guess I would start djing, was the dry comment from an American dancer we met in Bs As a few years ago when I told this story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go before it&#39;s too late</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/28/go-before-its-too-late/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2008 22:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/28/go-before-its-too-late/</guid>
      <description>When should you go to Buenos Aires?I would say: as soon as possible. Go before it&amp;rsquo;s too late! You will gain nothing by waiting. You will not be good enough, anyway ;-) But do by all means go!
If you wait until you are ready, you risk missing out on the entire thing. Going to milongas in your neighborhood, you will believe you improve to become a good dancer, and that you know what tango is about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>¡Ahora, pollo!</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/26/ahora-pollo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2008 21:55:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/26/ahora-pollo/</guid>
      <description>Returning again to Buenos Aires, a lot more experienced and familiar with music and culture than the first time I had read that another Alberto was still live and kicking, Alberto Podestá that would be. We had some tango musicians from our city coming down, and thought it would be an excellent thing to do with them. Podestá is singing at the place La Cumparsita in San Telmo, but for some reason or another we never made it while our musicians were in town.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Café de los maestros</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/13/cafe-de-los-maestros/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2008 13:33:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/13/cafe-de-los-maestros/</guid>
      <description>Always looking out for new films about tango, both dance and music, I must say I am really looking forward to this one: Café de los maestros. It has been described as the tango equivalent to the _Buena Vista Social Club. I already got the soundtrack, so I know the music is excellent. Can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see it. _
When oh when will it become available on DVD? It will never be shown on the silver screen where I live I&amp;rsquo;m afraid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old tango hero</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/09/old-tango-hero/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2008 20:53:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/09/old-tango-hero/</guid>
      <description>On our first visit to Buenos Aires, we rented a room in San Telmo. Right in the neighborhood is the Centro Cultural Torquato Tasso. For some reason we never came around to go there, even if it was by far the closest milonga.
Until one evening, we finally found space in our schedule to visit El Tasso. There was to be live music, and we were quite excited. The place was packed with people, and all of a sudden an old man was announced, and with support from a couple of guys he entered the stage.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>