<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dance For The Woman on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/tags/dance-for-the-woman/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dance For The Woman on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/tags/dance-for-the-woman/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Masquerade</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/31/masquerade/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2008 21:07:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/31/masquerade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/10/masquerade.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/10/masquerade.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who are you when you are dancing? Are you the leader? The follower? The man? The woman? I was once confronted with my using the terminology man/woman in class. The person complaining said that she was dancing a &lt;em&gt;role&lt;/em&gt; (she was dancing the man&amp;rsquo;s part) and that was the role of the leader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know this easily gets messy, but I never liked the euphemism leader/follower when what we are talking about is a man and a woman in most cases. Being a follower implies being passive, and sort of gives the leader higher value. When it can easily be argued that it is quite the oposite. The man dances _ for the woman_, remember? &lt;em&gt;She&lt;/em&gt; is the high value part of the relationship. To be cherished and taken good care of. Embraced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, with love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few years back I took a class about communication and backleading. We were asked to try and verbalize what we were communicating in our dance. While I did not like the lesson much, something interesting came up. I tried finding the words, my mood maybe, happy or sad, if I had a good day at work and so on. The interesting part was the answer from another couple at the class. They dismissed the whole idea of the communication comprising more than &lt;em&gt;mere movements&lt;/em&gt;. While they were very good dancers, I think they miss out on something very important if they limit the dance to merely movements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a related note, Javier in a class talked about daring to enjoy embracing and walking together, and how using too many steps like sacadas etc would create a distance between the two in the couple. And he was not talking about the physical distance between the dancers, but about not connecting with your partner on a deeper level than merely doing steps together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lower the mask and dare dance as yourself. Don&amp;rsquo;t play games. Dare showing your true self. You might be lucky and get the same in return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&#34;http://flickr.com/photos/36291563@N00/&#34;&gt;August Rush&lt;/a&gt;@flickr, &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/deed.en&#34;&gt;CC-licensed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>