<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cc on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/tags/cc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cc on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2009 16:57:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/tags/cc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Buenos Aires Street Art</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/28/buenos-aires-street-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2009 16:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/28/buenos-aires-street-art/</guid>
      <description>by Simba tango
I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share some photos from the streets of Buenos Aires where there you can often see the kind of graffitti made with stencils. Among the motifs I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered are tango in the incarnation of Osvaldo Pugliese and a new electrotango band called tranxgo, football icon Maradona, not so subtle drug references and lots of other stuff.
[flickr-gallery mode=&amp;ldquo;photoset&amp;rdquo; photoset=&amp;ldquo;72157622958599173&amp;rdquo;]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Resistance</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/26/the-resistance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2009 00:42:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/26/the-resistance/</guid>
      <description>by mirsasha
Tangocommuter is constructive and a man of action. Simba likes that. Following up on his own idea to distribute the homage to the milongueros, he has created a flyer, and I am happy to host it here at simbatango.com.
The challenge is, in his own words:
   (...) print out a lot of copies, with an attractive picture, perhaps that of the entrance to Sin Rumbo, so that it looks like a regular leaflet, to leave on the table at the entry of every milonga we go to…    Quietly sneaking in a little education in the milongas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nueve de julio</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/09/nueve-de-julio/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2009 05:01:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/09/nueve-de-julio/</guid>
      <description>  by Simba tango
Happy independence day, Argentina!
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sabor a tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/12/sabor-a-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2009 20:22:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/12/sabor-a-tango/</guid>
      <description>by Simba tango
It is common to say that we taste four diffent tastes: sweet, salt, bitter and sour. Combinations of these make up all other tastes. Sounds familiar? You may be guessing what I&amp;rsquo;m getting at&amp;hellip;
The experience of taste, or should I say the experience of a meal, which we humans make for the pure pleasure of enjoying the different tastes and combinations, consists of a lot more than these four basic tastes (some also include umami, but that&amp;rsquo;s not the point).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gingerbread milonga</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/10/gingerbread-milonga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2008 16:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/10/gingerbread-milonga/</guid>
      <description>Some friends (also tango maniacs, of course) made this just before Christmas a couple of years ago. A really tasty milonga it was! Welcome to Club Grizelle!



I released the photos under a Creative Commons license, so feel free to use them for whatever non-commercial purpose you like :-) I appreciate a link and a comment if you find use for it.
Maybe they can be useful for invitations to your Christmas milonga?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>