<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Biagi on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>https://simbatango.github.io/tags/biagi/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Biagi on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="https://simbatango.github.io/tags/biagi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango Tunes</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2013/02/20/tango-tunes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 15:49:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2013/02/20/tango-tunes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/BIAGI_5621_A.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/BIAGI_5621_A.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;BIAGI_5621_A&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first results are trickling down from the TangoVia project. Tango Tunes is a Vienna based organisation, digitizing music with the help from TangoVia. They recently provided a preview of what they will offer, and I have to say I think it sounds very good. The Troilo sample in particular was very promising. The first songs available for purchase are &lt;a href=&#34;http://de.tangowiki.com/index.php/Biagi_100&#34;&gt;100 Biagi songs&lt;/a&gt;.  The price is EUR 100, which is expensive compared with commercial releases, but cheaper than the Japanese labels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What it comes down to then is selection and transfer quality. The really great thing is that they will offer lossless files in high resolution (96 kHz, 24 bit) for those that have time to spend restoring music. We others can just downsample to 44.1kHz, 16 bit. Unfortunately, Biagi is not high on my prioriy when it comes to repurchasing tango music. The commercial releases are already ok quality. Troilo on the other hand, will put me first in line. Same goes for De Caro, and probably also Di Sarli. D&amp;rsquo;Arienzo will also be interesting for many DJs, I think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know how they plan on rolling this out later, but making complete discographies available would be another thing to make them stand out. I&amp;rsquo;m crossing my fingers for complete Troilo later this year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>