<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 23:04:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Los Estilos Fundamentales de Tango 3</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2017/07/20/los-estilos-fundamentales-de-tango-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 23:04:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2017/07/20/los-estilos-fundamentales-de-tango-3/</guid>
      <description> The third season is well underway&amp;hellip; Enjoy!
El Choclo (2017-04):   Laurenz (2017-05)   Milonga (2017-06-14)   OT Piazzolla (2017-07)   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2017/03/17/moving/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 22:06:07 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2017/03/17/moving/</guid>
      <description>Here is a short meta update. The time for moving has come, both physically and technologywise. In a few months I will be moving back to my hometown, which happens to have a vibrant tango community. Looking forward to that. I do have some ideas for posts, but what little time I have for tango at the moment is spent actually dancing and djing.
Also, this blog has moved, for a variety of reasons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Los Estilos Fundamentales de Tango 2 | Miguel Caló</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2016/10/01/los-estilos-fundamentales-de-tango-2-miguel-calo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 17:54:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2016/10/01/los-estilos-fundamentales-de-tango-2-miguel-calo/</guid>
      <description>The latest video from the Los Estilos Fundamentales del Tango is up. This time featuring Miguel Caló. Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Los Estilos Fundamentales del Tango 2 | Fresedo</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2016/09/01/los-estilos-fundamentales-del-tango-2-fresedo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 20:08:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2016/09/01/los-estilos-fundamentales-del-tango-2-fresedo/</guid>
      <description>The video from the Fresedo seminar is up!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Los Estilos Fundamentales del Tango 2 | Francini-Pontier</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2016/07/25/los-estilos-fundamentales-del-tango-2-francini-pontier/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 19:58:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2016/07/25/los-estilos-fundamentales-del-tango-2-francini-pontier/</guid>
      <description>Video from the Francini-Pontier seminar is up: Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Los Estilos Fundamentales del Tango 2 | Julio De Caro</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2016/06/19/los-estilos-fundamentales-del-tango-2-julio-de-caro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2016 20:23:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2016/06/19/los-estilos-fundamentales-del-tango-2-julio-de-caro/</guid>
      <description>The video from the seminar last week on Julio De Caro is up. Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Los Estilos Fundamentales del Tango Series 2 | Elementos Básicos</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2016/05/22/los-estilos-fundamentales-del-tango-series-2-elementos-basicos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2016 09:07:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2016/05/22/los-estilos-fundamentales-del-tango-series-2-elementos-basicos/</guid>
      <description>Ignacio Varchausky is at it again with a new series of his excellent Los Estilos Fundamentales del Tango. Go there if you&amp;rsquo;re in Bs As, or listen/watch after the fact like the rest of us otherwise. Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dancing to the music of time</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2016/01/29/dancing-to-the-music-of-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 19:02:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2016/01/29/dancing-to-the-music-of-time/</guid>
      <description>But among so many lessons, with so many teachers, I find contradictions and clichés. My feet are shovels; my feet are paintbrushes. My feet must caress the floor, intensely; my feet are too firm against the floorboards. My embrace must be close, like the embrace of a lover; my embrace must leave space for the tension between us. I am a cat, I am a lion, I am a horse-rider. Carina tells me I need to work on my ochos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Los estilos fundamentales del tango por Ignacio Varchausky | Alfredo Gobbi</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2015/10/26/los-estilos-fundamentales-del-tango-por-ignacio-varchausky-alfredo-gobbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 19:43:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2015/10/26/los-estilos-fundamentales-del-tango-por-ignacio-varchausky-alfredo-gobbi/</guid>
      <description>The Gobbi seminar video is up!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podestá Godoy, cantores | Documentary</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2015/10/07/podesta-godoy-cantores-documentary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2015 13:28:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2015/10/07/podesta-godoy-cantores-documentary/</guid>
      <description>A new documentary on tango singers Alberto Podestá and Juan Carlos Godoy by Daniel Tonelli and Marcelo Turrisi looks interesting. Hope it gets released on dvd or video on demand.
HT: Janis</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Los estilos fundamentales del tango por Ignacio Varchausky | Horacio Salgán</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2015/09/19/los-estilos-fundamentales-del-tango-por-ignacio-varchausky-horacio-salgan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2015 15:40:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2015/09/19/los-estilos-fundamentales-del-tango-por-ignacio-varchausky-horacio-salgan/</guid>
      <description>This time with video. Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Last Tango -- Copes y Nieves</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2015/09/10/our-last-tango-copes-y-nieves/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 11:43:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2015/09/10/our-last-tango-copes-y-nieves/</guid>
      <description>Now this looks like something to look forward to:
In „Our Last Tango“ Juan and María tell their story to a group of young tango dancers and choreographers from Buenos Aires, who transform the most beautiful, moving and dramatic moments of Juan and Maria’s lives into incredible tango-choreographies. These beautifully-shot choreographies compliment the soul-searching interviews and documentary moments of the film to make this an unforgettable journey into the heart of the tango.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Los estilos fundamentales del tango por Ignacio Varchausky</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2015/08/23/los-estilos-fundamentales-del-tango-por-ignacio-varchausky/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2015 19:01:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2015/08/23/los-estilos-fundamentales-del-tango-por-ignacio-varchausky/</guid>
      <description>Ignacio Varchausky is doing a series of very interesting seminars on the style of different tango orchestras. Audio recordings of the seminars have been released with links in the facebook comments, and that means an opportunity to listen to them even when very lejos de Buenos Aires. They are in Spanish though, so you need to follow spoken Spanish reasonably well to make any use of it.
Apparently, they build on a seminar similar to the one that inspired this post on how to listen to tango, so you might want to check out that first, if you haven&amp;rsquo;t already.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Perfect Embrace</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2015/02/14/the-perfect-embrace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2015 19:22:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2015/02/14/the-perfect-embrace/</guid>
      <description>by virgoh
Of course, this is nothing new to tango dancers, but understanding the mechanisms is interesting:
A caress feels best when it is delivered with a small amount of force and a speed of about 1 inch per second. Stroke slower, and it feels like an unwelcome crawling bug; faster, and it feels perfunctory rather than loving.  Perform your caress not on the glabrous skin of the palm or sole, but on the hairy skin of the limbs where the caress sensing fibers are found.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fermin, Glorias del Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2014/10/06/fermin-glorias-del-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2014 20:44:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2014/10/06/fermin-glorias-del-tango/</guid>
      <description>http://vimeo.com/ondemand/fermin
Fermin, Glorias del Tango is now available for rental at Vimeo. Looks nice, I think. I haven&amp;rsquo;t had time to watch it, and I sort of wait for the download that was supposed to come with my Kickstarter support. Oh well.
EDIT: I worked it out with Oliver Kolker. Apparently I missed an email that was sent to all backers. Oliver promptly gave me access to the film and I experienced no further problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slow</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2014/09/25/slow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 18:31:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2014/09/25/slow/</guid>
      <description>by andy khouri
Insights about tango may be found where you least suspect it. Slow down and dance with me&amp;hellip; yeah..
Knew you&#39;d be here tonight So I put my best dress on Boy I was so right Our eyes connected Now nothing&#39;s how it used to be No second guesses Track in on this feeling Pull focus close up you and me Nobody&#39;s leaving Got me affected Spun me 180 degrees It&#39;s so electric Slow down and dance with me Yeah.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rise of the Tango DJ</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2014/09/05/the-rise-of-the-tango-dj/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2014 10:46:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2014/09/05/the-rise-of-the-tango-dj/</guid>
      <description>by sebastien.barre
I am thrilled to see the increased interest in djing and playing quality tango music for dancers the last few years. In trying to understand how it all came about, it is tempting to focus on the efforts of individuals to bring good dance music to their local community, but thereby we might miss the big picture.
Technological and economic changes can be transformative. Some of the most famous examples from the world of tango are the invention of the electrical recorder/the microphone, the fierce competition between orchestras during the golden age of tango and the selective pressure following from men largely outnumbering women in the milongas as the dance developed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Felix Picherna | Tengo una pregunta para vos</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2014/09/02/felix-picherna-tengo-una-pregunta-para-vos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 19:37:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2014/09/02/felix-picherna-tengo-una-pregunta-para-vos/</guid>
      <description>Felix Picherna is a legend, and he was clearly the first tango dj to make a lasting impression in me. Sitting with his cassette deck, rewinding the prepared tandas, live commenting the upcoming music with the microphone. Unforgettable.
Enjoy this video from the excellent &amp;ldquo;Tengo una pregunta para vos&amp;rdquo; series by Pepa Palazón, that I just recently found time to start watching. There are several gems there, and the most recent ones are subtitled in English (that includes this one).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encyclopedia of Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2014/04/19/encyclopedia-of-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2014 19:32:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2014/04/19/encyclopedia-of-tango/</guid>
      <description>Gabriel Valiente has released a dictionary of Tango which contains discographies of most tango orchestras. It was meant to be released as an ebook, but is only available in paper edition at the moment. I think it looks interesting, but find that kind of information is generally vastly more useful when available electronically, in a format that is searchable and sortable etc. I hope Gabriel finds a way to release the full dataset as well as his book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Masochism Tango | Tom Lehrer</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2014/04/11/masochism-tango-tom-lehrer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2014 19:31:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2014/04/11/masochism-tango-tom-lehrer/</guid>
      <description>This is a long term favorite, no wonder people have the freakiest ideas about us tango dancers&amp;hellip; It should clear up once and for all, that dancing tango is not any fun.
I never knew much about Tom Lehrer, though. I recommend this excellent BuzzFeed piece on Tom Lehrer, in addition to checking out his other oevre of course. It has generally aged pretty well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango Negro, The African Roots of Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2014/04/02/tango-negro-the-african-roots-of-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 20:53:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2014/04/02/tango-negro-the-african-roots-of-tango/</guid>
      <description>Now this looks interesting, a documentary about the African roots of tango. It&amp;rsquo;s featuring Juan Carlos Cáceres (of &amp;ldquo;Tango Negro&amp;rdquo; fame), of which I&amp;rsquo;m a great fan. One of the best concerts I ever attended was with Cáceres and band and Facundo &amp;amp; Kely Posadas performing.
You can read a bit more about the documentary at the ADIFF film festival pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Impossibility  of Re-Creating the Tango of Times Gone By</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2014/03/27/the-impossibility-of-re-creating-the-tango-of-times-gone-by/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2014 21:29:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2014/03/27/the-impossibility-of-re-creating-the-tango-of-times-gone-by/</guid>
      <description>by OldOnliner
There is a paradox concerning my relationship with tango, and maybe with tango itself. On one hand, I want to learn from the sources, learn the &amp;lsquo;true&amp;rsquo; tango. If that even exists. On the other hand, I want to see progress, to move on, and to find or invent &amp;lsquo;my own&amp;rsquo; tango. Which may not exist, either. This tension between a certain nostalgia and the Sisyphean quest for the authentic, and the longing for progress, a rational approach, the tension between being controlled by the tango and taking control over the tango is at once frustrating and tantalizing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glorias del Tango -- New Tango Feature Film</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2013/08/07/glorias-del-tango-new-tango-feature-film/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2013 20:58:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2013/08/07/glorias-del-tango-new-tango-feature-film/</guid>
      <description>This new project looks interesting, you can support it on kickstarter. Not sure I believe the story, but the flashbacks look promising. On the other hand, it sounds much more believeable than Assasination Tango.
&#34;Glorias del Tango&#34; is an ambitious and exciting feature film that will end the decade-long silence of tango on the silver screen. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to it. Time to revive the tango film club?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guide To Tango Music Stores</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2013/05/23/guide-to-tango-music-stores/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2013 16:24:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2013/05/23/guide-to-tango-music-stores/</guid>
      <description>by Telstar Logistics
Tangohub beat me to it. Head over there for a comprehensive guide to stores for buying tango music online. It&amp;rsquo;s written from a UK perspective, but most of the stores mentioned are international.
I would mention Tangostore also (aka Zival&amp;rsquo;s), but they have been offline for a while.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango Tunes Website Up</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2013/05/08/tango-tunes-website-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 04:34:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2013/05/08/tango-tunes-website-up/</guid>
      <description>The long awaited TangoTunes project website is now online and accepting purchases. I&amp;rsquo;ll start by checking out the few Troilo recordings they have available at the moment. The purchase went through very smoothly.
This is how they present themselves:
TangoTunes is an Austrian-Argentine project with the aim to preserve the music of Tango Argentino. This way, we also preserve and support a piece of Argentine culture, which was declared World Heritage several years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Fast Transfers</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2013/05/07/more-fast-transfers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 08:36:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2013/05/07/more-fast-transfers/</guid>
      <description>by Aleera*
I have previously discussed too fast transfers from 78s. Age Akkerman has a well researched take on Di Sarli&amp;rsquo;s El ciruja which he found to be about 5% too fast on the Euro Records transfer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rare Clips of Petróleo, Virulazo and others</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2013/03/31/rare-clips-of-petroleo-virulazo-and-others/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 14:43:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2013/03/31/rare-clips-of-petroleo-virulazo-and-others/</guid>
      <description>Amazing how these old clips slowly surface on youtube and facebook. Here are some clips that seem to be from an old documentary, posted by Victor Barrios and Cristina Benavidez:
      HT: @FerGaleraTango</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>El Papa Francisco</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2013/03/31/el-papa-francisco/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 07:20:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2013/03/31/el-papa-francisco/</guid>
      <description>Apparently the new pope is a tango lover, and now he got his own tango. Composition and lyrics by Daniel Ursini. Courtesy of Canciones para grabar.
Happy Easter, Papa Fracisco!
HT @milongaroom</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carlos Di Sarli Documentary</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2013/03/30/carlos-di-sarli-documentary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 08:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2013/03/30/carlos-di-sarli-documentary/</guid>
      <description>According to Realidad Bonaerense, there is a new documentary about Carlos di Sarli coming out, directed by Alberto Freinquel. No information about dvd or download edition, but there will be several public viewings in Buenos Aires and in Bahía Blanca, I think. The article mentions several dramatized sequences, which makes me a bit sceptical, but I guess you have to do something if there is little historical material available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BPM</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2013/03/29/bpm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 19:41:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2013/03/29/bpm/</guid>
      <description>by Paul Graham Raven
The advances in DSP and processing power since I started ripping my cds to store all my music on a computer drive are enormous.
Sometimes having an estimate of the BPM of a tango song can be useful, e.g. when searching for &amp;ldquo;slow&amp;rdquo; milongas, sorting by BPM would be useful. But tapping each song individually to store in tags &amp;ndash; no way it&amp;rsquo;s worth the effort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Audio Restoration from Multiple Copies</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2013/03/27/audio-restoration-from-multiple-copies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 18:53:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2013/03/27/audio-restoration-from-multiple-copies/</guid>
      <description>I was pondering the usefulness of noise removal based on several copies of a recording, possibly from different physical copies. A Google search reveals that such a technique is already patented:
The present invention provides a method for reducing noise using a plurality of recording copies. The present invention produces a master file with lower noise than the available recording copies, and avoids the problems of losing musical content caused by prior art pop and click removers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango Tunes</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2013/02/20/tango-tunes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 15:49:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2013/02/20/tango-tunes/</guid>
      <description>The first results are trickling down from the TangoVia project. Tango Tunes is a Vienna based organisation, digitizing music with the help from TangoVia. They recently provided a preview of what they will offer, and I have to say I think it sounds very good. The Troilo sample in particular was very promising. The first songs available for purchase are 100 Biagi songs. The price is EUR 100, which is expensive compared with commercial releases, but cheaper than the Japanese labels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>El Corte Documentary</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2013/02/19/el-corte-documentary/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2013 15:09:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2013/02/19/el-corte-documentary/</guid>
      <description>[vimeo 28409308 w=500]
I missed this when it came out. A doucumentary about the legendary El Corte in Nijmegen, The Netherlands. Eric Jørissen and El Corte have had a great influence on the European tango scene in general, and if I am not mistaken, on the tango marathon culture in particular.
HT: Veronica</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kung Fu Tango -- Learning From Bruce Lee</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2013/02/11/kung-fu-tango-learning-from-bruce-lee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2013 22:04:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2013/02/11/kung-fu-tango-learning-from-bruce-lee/</guid>
      <description>--What is the highest technique you hope to achieve? --To have no technique. It is impossible not to think of tango, hearing some of the conversations in the Bruce Lee film Enter the Dragon.
--Kick me (Bruce Lee to one of his students) student kicks --What was that? An exhibition? We need emotional content. Try again. student kicks again --I said emotional content. Not anger. Now, try again. With _me._ student kicks again --That&#39;s it, how did it feel to you?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find One Error</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2012/12/04/find-one-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2012 21:51:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2012/12/04/find-one-error/</guid>
      <description>This is a great idea! Trouvez l&amp;rsquo;erreur! from Les Pas Parfaits de Montréal. Simple, funny and well executed. Drawings by Véronique Paquette. My French is a bit rusty, but I believe the drawings are free to use for non-commercial purposes, and that it is allowed to translate them and incorporate translations in the images.
Makes me want to go to Montréal!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hope for CTA, AMP, Audio Park reissues?</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2012/11/15/hope-for-cta-amp-audio-park-reissues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2012 10:09:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2012/11/15/hope-for-cta-amp-audio-park-reissues/</guid>
      <description>by eerkmans
Many CTA discs and others are available in Europe through the Austrian DJ Bernhard Gehberger. He recently went to Japan and met with the guys behind CTA, AMP and Audio Park. From his report from that trip, it seems like he is working on facilitating reissues of these out-of-print discs. Which would be of great benefit to the tango community if he pulls it through. Today they are both hard to get and expensive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango Libre</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2012/11/07/tango-libre/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2012 15:49:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2012/11/07/tango-libre/</guid>
      <description>There is another tango film coming up. This Belgian production is starring Chicho, and although tango films can be a mixed bag, and I have my doubts how much drama it can yield, it looks sort of interesting. Apparently it won the Warsaw Film Festival Grand Prix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vero Tango Quotes</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2012/11/05/vero-tango-quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 21:28:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2012/11/05/vero-tango-quotes/</guid>
      <description>During a class. &#34;Good. Now that you know the move, try to enjoy it.&#34; &#34;What?&#34; &#34;Enjoy it!&#34; &#34;Oh shit.&#34; Enjoy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nostalgia</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2012/04/19/nostalgia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2012 21:10:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2012/04/19/nostalgia/</guid>
      <description>I some times muse over the multiple levels of nostalgia in tango. Today we are (at least to some degree) nostalgic about the golden age of tango, peaking in the 1940s. Tango, of course, was already nostalgic about the turn of the century during the golden age.
Now, I always thought of this as layered or maybe even recursive nostalgia, beging nostalgic about the nostalgia of the 1940s. Add the nostalgia being a long way from Buenos Aires and longing back to being nostalgic about how they were nostalgic about the fin de ciecle in the golden age, and you get the picture&amp;hellip; Even the nostalgia was better in the old days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Milonga&#34; -- tango short</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2012/02/20/milonga-tango-short/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2012 09:53:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2012/02/20/milonga-tango-short/</guid>
      <description>Well done, methinks.
HT Alex</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango Baby</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2012/02/09/tango-baby/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2012 19:46:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2012/02/09/tango-baby/</guid>
      <description>This post just became relevant again. Happy to bring some good news in 2012. This could mean more posts or less, we&amp;rsquo;ll see.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Losing a Friend</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2012/01/04/losing-a-friend/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 22:34:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2012/01/04/losing-a-friend/</guid>
      <description>by HocusFocusClick
Standing in front of the window, glancing out. The day had long since started, yet it was dark outside. It was pouring down, despite being mid-winter. He saw through the rain. He saw through the house across the street.
What he saw was her smile. Her dancing cumbia in the kitchen. Her explaining the concepts of &amp;ldquo;cheta&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;negro&amp;rdquo;. Her expertly preparing a mate. &amp;ldquo;Her standing on one leg in the Comme il Faut showroom, trying one shoe while putting on a second while asking for third pair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baldosa</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/12/10/baldosa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2011 18:20:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/12/10/baldosa/</guid>
      <description>I think they make the point very clear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More De Caro</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/12/07/more-de-caro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2011 18:58:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/12/07/more-de-caro/</guid>
      <description>Danza y Movimiento have released anotherbatch of De Caro collections. In addition to the places they were available the last time, they are also available on Spotify (links below).
I haven&amp;rsquo;t had time to listen carefully yet, but the few I have listened to seem to be transferred at the correct speed (unlike some of the older ones).
Just in time for the upcoming día del tango. Enjoy:
 Mocosita (#153)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Interesting Reading/Viewing Elsewhere</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/11/12/some-interesting-readingviewing-elsewhere/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2011 08:23:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/11/12/some-interesting-readingviewing-elsewhere/</guid>
      <description>by Smath.
Not much time to write at the moment, here are some interesting posts that you might enjoy that I want to keep track of for later for my own sake:
Interesting interview with Chicho Part 1, Part 2 and Part 3
Quite an interesting read. I could relate very well to his comments on why teachers don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily dance all the time at festivals. Apparently many people in my local community have difficulties understanding this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of the Cabeceo Part III: When in Rome...</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/10/20/the-art-of-the-cabeceo-part-iii-when-in-rome/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2011 18:54:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/10/20/the-art-of-the-cabeceo-part-iii-when-in-rome/</guid>
      <description>by Bsivad
As the music of the cortina fades out, she glances over the tables on the opposite side of the dance floor. Refreshes her memory of where the different dancers she watched on the floor are seated. Preparing to try and catch the eye of one of her favorite partners as the music starts for the next tanda.
Her eyes move along the tables, she is nodding to her self, yes, yes, maybe&amp;hellip; her eyes reach the corner of the dance floor, and she quickly moves on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TINT based filing and human readable with FUSE and pytagsfs</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/09/20/tint-based-filing-and-human-readable-with-fuse-and-pytagsfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2011 19:28:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/09/20/tint-based-filing-and-human-readable-with-fuse-and-pytagsfs/</guid>
      <description>├── Canaro, Rafael │ ├── HQCD 99 Buenos Aires to Paris - Argentine tango performers in France 1924-1938 │ │ └── La mélodie de notre adieu.flac │ ├── ORQ 232 Rafael Canaro en Francia (1936-1939) │ │ ├── 01 Alma de bandoneón (Mario Beltrán).flac │ │ ├── 02 Campanas del recuerdo.flac
│ │ ├── 21 Olvidame (Luis Mariano).flac │ │ └── 22 Callecita de mi novia (Luis Mariano).flac │ └── ORQ 233 1929-1945 │ ├── 01 Las vueltas de la vida.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valentino</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/09/16/valentino/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2011 20:49:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/09/16/valentino/</guid>
      <description>I have this weird interest in the popular culture image of tango, for a large part constituted by various more or less successful renditions of the tango on the silver screen.
As a matter of fact I have been looking for this particular rendition since I saw still photos in the tango book by Collier et al. And thanks to Tangocommuter, I realized Valentino (1977) by Ken Russell was released on DVD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of the Cabeceo Part II: Failing Gracefully</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/07/18/the-art-of-the-cabeceo-part-ii-failing-gracefully/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2011 20:17:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/07/18/the-art-of-the-cabeceo-part-ii-failing-gracefully/</guid>
      <description>There she was, the girl with the blue dress. I noticed here before, but I never managed to catch her eye. Her seat was all the way over at the other corner, so I started walking between the tables. As I approached slowly, I tried to establish eye contact. She changed her position. A slight turn of the head. I got closer. She looked down. Opened her purse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spotify Available in the US -- Tango Classics</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/07/14/spotify-available-in-the-us-tango-classics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 15:49:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/07/14/spotify-available-in-the-us-tango-classics/</guid>
      <description>US readers might be interested that widely acclaimed music service Spotify launches in the US today. And can start listening to the classics of Argentine tango right away. The playlists are mostly complete to the degree that the music is actually available on Spotify.
That&amp;rsquo;s all.
EDIT: New URL for Classics of Argentine tango on Spotify.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning From Early Music</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/07/10/learning-from-early-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 11:54:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/07/10/learning-from-early-music/</guid>
      <description>by madabandon
In a sense, dancing Argentine Tango in 2011 in a country far away from Argentina is an inescapable anachronism. How could it ever be authentic? Should it be? Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t any art form evolve and develop in a quest for ever improvement? In the (un)concious choice between opposing traditions, which would be the right to follow?
Now, these questions are not unique for tango of course:
The idea of revival has become a touchstone for the Early Music Movement, and consequently the fact that some styles of performance have been going on long enough to develop and build their own continuity presents some philosophical complications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letras de Non-Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/06/30/letras-de-non-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 18:23:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/06/30/letras-de-non-tango/</guid>
      <description>Maybe you remember my Letras de Tango post a while back, showing the most used words in tango lyrics. The possibility of doing something similar for other genres/pop music was raised in the comments. And the guys over at last.fm just did exactly that. So head over and have a look at their graphics for Blues, Country, Electronic, Folk, Goth, Hip-Hop, Indie, Metal, Rap, Rock and Soul. They also did some interesting distance charts, showing graphically how similar the lyrics of different genres are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Too Fast Transfers</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/06/15/too-fast-transfers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 21:23:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/06/15/too-fast-transfers/</guid>
      <description>I sort of promised to post a few samples of my results from slowing down some tracks that I believe are transferred at too high speed in the DyM Tango Classics collection.
Although I have suspected that several other transfers, most notably on the El Bandoneon label were transferred at too high speed, I never tried slowing them down myself because I knew it to be hard to find the correct speed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DyM Online | Tango Classics</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/05/07/dym-online-tango-classics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 20:27:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/05/07/dym-online-tango-classics/</guid>
      <description>by Todd Binger
I decided to check out the offerings of DyM a bit more closely after I noticed that some of them were available in lossless format from the French site Qobuz. I got a couple of De Caro compilations because they are hard to get by other places. These tracks are mostly from the late 20s and early 30s, so what I found out may or may not apply to other, later recordings issued in this series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baroque Zamba</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/04/11/baroque-zamba/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2011 20:59:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/04/11/baroque-zamba/</guid>
      <description>Going to Argentina for the tango, you end up falling in love with other things Argentine as well. One of these things is the Zamba, not to be confused with its Brazilian homonym homophone.
Imagine the surprised look on Simba&amp;rsquo;s face listening to a radio show reviewing some new &amp;lsquo;classical&amp;rsquo; releases. Suddenly they play an Argentine Zamba, or at least something very similar. The cd in question was the new release from the Clematis Ensemble with music by composer Mateo Romero.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango Recordings Through the Year</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/04/05/tango-recordings-through-the-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 19:22:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/04/05/tango-recordings-through-the-year/</guid>
      <description>When were the different tangos recorded? From the 9233 unique recordings identified with exact recording date in the tango.info database we can see that not surprisingly there is low activity during summer, more specifically during January and February, it then picks up with peaks in June, September and December. Splitting the numbers over the decades makes a slightly more confusing picture.
If you want to check out the recordings for one specific date, there is now a nifty feature over at tango.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rare Tango Tracks Available in DyM&#39;s &#39;Tango Classics&#39; Series</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/02/15/rare-tango-tracks-available-in-dyms-tango-classics-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2011 14:25:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/02/15/rare-tango-tracks-available-in-dyms-tango-classics-series/</guid>
      <description>I just learnt that the German label Danza y Movimiento (DyM) are issuing a new series called Tango Classics. It is based on the collection of the collector Klaus Johns. There seems to be quite a few tracks not available elsewhere, for instance by Julio De Caro, so it should be worth checking out for all you serious collectors out there :-) Also listed at tango.info.
Unfortunately, they only offer mp3 downloads at the time, flac or some other lossless option would be very nice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improved Loudness Correction With EBU R128</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/01/18/improved-loudness-correction-with-ebu-r128/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 21:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/01/18/improved-loudness-correction-with-ebu-r128/</guid>
      <description>by Niels Linneberg
Music mastered at different levels can be a pain when you&amp;rsquo;re a dj, as well as when listening to music at home. The great differences in loudness levels is in part due to what is sometimes called the &amp;ldquo;Loudness War&amp;rdquo;, but sometimes it is just inconsistent between different issuers. As long as you listen to a CD/compilation as it was designed from the issuer, there is no problem, it is when you start mixing tracks from different sources that the volume starts jumping up and down&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributing to the Digital Tango Archive</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/12/11/contributing-to-the-digital-tango-archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2010 13:46:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/12/11/contributing-to-the-digital-tango-archive/</guid>
      <description>by erielookingproductions
I have written about the effort of Tango Via to digitally archive the entire tango catalogue, and how I was impressed with their ambitions, the work so far and the significance of preserving the tango culture for the future.
This is an update to point your attention to their donation page, you can donate via Help Argentina if you are outside Argentina. If in Argentina, they suggest you get in touch with them to get instructions for donations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>¡Felíz día del tango!</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/12/11/feliz-dia-del-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2010 10:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/12/11/feliz-dia-del-tango/</guid>
      <description>Even Google in Argentina celebrates the day of tango!
HT: El Tangauta</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Documentary: Eyes Closed -- Ad occhi chiusi</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/11/17/upcoming-documentary-eyes-closed-ad-occhi-chiusi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2010 08:41:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/11/17/upcoming-documentary-eyes-closed-ad-occhi-chiusi/</guid>
      <description>I missed (at least) one on my last post on upcoming movies. This one is an Italian documentary. Here is a link to the film website for more information, and here is a link to the Italian version of the trailer for those who prefer. From the website:
This will be the story of Rossana, a young Italian artist, who rediscovers her femininity by means of the Tango, going through a real metamorphosis which is enhanced by the sparkle in her eyes when telling her story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classics of Tango Dance Music on Spotify</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/11/15/classics-of-tango-dance-music-on-spotify/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2010 17:14:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/11/15/classics-of-tango-dance-music-on-spotify/</guid>
      <description>I believe the only way to come to understand the tango is by listening a lot to tango music. Music appreciation classes are all great, but no substitute for putting in hours and hours of listening. For our beginning classes we have always encouraged our students to start listening to tango music right away. We used to give them a free cd, but while feeling quite ok about this morally, it was a bit on the gray side, legally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jorge Luis Borges</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/11/13/jorge-luis-borges/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2010 15:52:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/11/13/jorge-luis-borges/</guid>
      <description>[](http://www.wired.com/underwire/2009/12/hey-oscar-wilde/9/)[![](http://www.wired.com/images_blogs/underwire/2009/12/sci_fi_authors_9a.jpg)](http://www.wired.com/underwire/2009/12/hey-oscar-wilde/9/)
Jorge Luis Borges is mainly the man to blame for perpetuating the myth that tango was born in the brothels. Which is amazing, since he was not much if anything of a tanguero. He was Argentine, though, and easily the best known Argentine author.
In fact, my first encounter with Argentine culture was when I read an anthology of his short stories in high school. They were quite interesting, often playing mind games, exploring absurtities like a library of all combinations of letters, which would imply that it contain all texts already written, as well as those still unimagined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Tango Movies: &#34;Tanguero&#34; and &#34;La cantante de tango&#34;</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/11/12/upcoming-tango-movies-tanguero-and-la-cantante-de-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2010 17:16:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/11/12/upcoming-tango-movies-tanguero-and-la-cantante-de-tango/</guid>
      <description>A short update on a couple of upcoming tango movies. I find it somewhat promising that none of them seem to be about a middle aged dancer or hit man coming to Buenos Aires and there discovering tango and through it, themselves. Still, they may include other clichés such as lost love and finding oneself through tango:
Tanguero Omar, a Tango instructor, is forced to return to Buenos Aires because of an important phone call.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tango Cynic -- So You Want to Learn Tango?</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/10/31/the-tango-cynic-so-you-want-to-learn-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2010 20:24:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/10/31/the-tango-cynic-so-you-want-to-learn-tango/</guid>
      <description>I want to be consumed by the passion and the drama, LOL! This is so funny. Complete with appropriately utterly and completely messed up American computerized pronounciaction of everything Spanish.
HT: Laura</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gabriel Missé and Natalia Hills in NYTimes (Again)</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/10/27/gabriel-misse-and-natalia-hills-in-nytimes-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2010 20:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/10/27/gabriel-misse-and-natalia-hills-in-nytimes-again/</guid>
      <description>I meant to post this a while ago, and was reminded when I saw the amazing video from a performance at the Sydney Tango Salon Festival. Coincidentally, I met the organizers in Buenos Aires last year, small world it is :-) But that&amp;rsquo;s not the point, the point is that The New York Times once again publishes an interesting read about Gabriel Missé and Natalia Hills (The first view is for free, then you hit the paywall):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of the Cabeceo Part I: Are You Flirting With Me?</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/10/23/the-art-of-the-cabeceo-part-i-are-you-flirting-with-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2010 13:45:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/10/23/the-art-of-the-cabeceo-part-i-are-you-flirting-with-me/</guid>
      <description>by pedrosimoes7
&amp;ndash;Nobody asks me to dance, complained our Canadian classmate. We were sitting at our table in the Buenos Aires Golf Club, overlooking the dark course and the city skyline. We started chatting about the cabeceo, surely she knew the habit of the Porteño dancer to ask by catching a potential partner&amp;rsquo;s eye and confirming with a slight nod towards the pista?
Of course she didn&amp;rsquo;t. On the contrary, she brought her habit of avoiding to meet the eye of men she did not know, avoiding unwanted attention and flirts from strangers, as she did back home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fresh Supplies</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/10/15/fresh-supplies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 19:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/10/15/fresh-supplies/</guid>
      <description>by Simba tango
A box of goodies was waiting for me when I got back from work this afternoon: Cruz de Malta, Rosamonte mate&amp;hellip;. and Salamandra Dulce de Leche..
I ended up buying from mate-tee.de, it just took a few days, and the price all included was somewhere around 1o-12 dollars a kg. Which is a lot more reasonable than going on buying the world&amp;rsquo;s most expensive yerba.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango (the Dance) Genealogy</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/10/08/tango-the-dance-genealogy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2010 12:19:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/10/08/tango-the-dance-genealogy/</guid>
      <description>The evolution of tango has not followed a single, easy to track, path. It is rather quite a mess, so in an attempt to figure out how it all goes together, I tried putting my current understaning together in a chart (pdf) showing the main developments of the tango dance in all its incarnations.
Just to reiterate: in my opinion there are two distinctions that really matter in tango: Social vs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supply and Demand</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/10/07/supply-and-demand/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2010 16:44:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/10/07/supply-and-demand/</guid>
      <description>  by Gerrit Wenz
If I had asked people what they wanted, they would have said faster horses.   _Henry Ford_    Don&#39;t give them what they ask for, give them what they never dreamt of having...   _Orson Welles_    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Campeones mundiales de tango salon 2010: Maria Ines Bogado &amp; Sebastian Jimenez </title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/09/19/campeones-mundiales-de-tango-salon-2010-maria-ines-bogado-sebastian-jimenez/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2010 21:16:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/09/19/campeones-mundiales-de-tango-salon-2010-maria-ines-bogado-sebastian-jimenez/</guid>
      <description>This is no longer news, of course, but I am finally catching up after being on vacations with no internet access (which was actually very nice!).
My congratulations to these beautiful dancers (that I wrote about before)!
The jury consisted of Eduardo Arquimbau, Julio Duplaa, Julio Balmaceda, el Nene Masci, Pablo Inza, Ana Maria Schapira y Javier Rodríguez, according to 2xtango.com. I appears that some find it shocking that someone so young won the championship (Sebastian is 18).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The World&#39;s Most Expensive Yerba?</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/09/19/the-worlds-most-expensive-yerba/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2010 21:03:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/09/19/the-worlds-most-expensive-yerba/</guid>
      <description>by Benjamin Pender
We always bringyerba mate back from Buenos Aires. It has become another habit as a biproduct of the passion for tango. Everywhere you will see porteños with their little thermoses and the cup with a metal straw, the bombilla, sipping away. In the queue, in the park, on the bus, in tango classes etc etc.
Anyway &amp;mdash; we ran out of the stuff after a couple of months after our return, and went to the specialist tea and coffee store in town.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Years Anniversary</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/09/07/10-years-anniversary/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2010 13:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/09/07/10-years-anniversary/</guid>
      <description>It is exactly 10 years since I first put a hesitating foot on a festival dance floor today. So I thought it would be fun to refresh my memories and reflect a bit on where I was then, and what I still keep from that time.
We were just entering the local tango scene, and didn&amp;rsquo;t really know anything about tango at all. We had seen Carlos Saura&amp;rsquo;s Tango, maybe Sally Potter&amp;rsquo;s Tango Lesson, but probably not yet at that time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extraordinary dancing, thoughts about tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/08/23/extraordinary-dancing-thoughts-about-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2010 19:51:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/08/23/extraordinary-dancing-thoughts-about-tango/</guid>
      <description>This extraordinary video gave me some food for thought and made me finish a line of reasoning that started after noticing a youtube comment. Complaining that the dancing was all acrobatics, but had no feeling for the music. Sounded very familiar, only this time it was not tango dancers, but b-boys they were complaining about.
Hip hop and tango have quite some things in common (and obvious differences, of course).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now playing...</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/08/03/now-playing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2010 08:34:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/08/03/now-playing/</guid>
      <description>Most djs follow a reasonably predictable scheme when they play, grouping the music in tandas of the same orchestra and from the same period. Also some variation of a repeating pattern is common when it comes to the sequence of the tandas.
However, new dancers often don&amp;rsquo;t know this (doesn&amp;rsquo;t anyone teach about how a milonga works?), and they don&amp;rsquo;t know the music. And as the incentives to learn it all alone are not as they were in the old days in Buenos Aires, many djs provide an extra service to their community in displaying what they are playing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated MusicBrainz Picard Plugins for tango.info</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/07/23/updated-musicbrainz-picard-plugins-for-tango-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2010 17:09:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/07/23/updated-musicbrainz-picard-plugins-for-tango-info/</guid>
      <description>by Sebastian Niedlich (Grabthar)
I had a couple of requests for the plugins for MusicBrainz Picard in the last months. I haven&amp;rsquo;t used them much myself, as there sadly are few contributers on tango music to the MusicBrainz metadata database.
However, I just checked whether they worked with the current format of tracks.csv from tango.info and the newest release of Picard (0.12.1). With one minor adjustment, they now do, and I uploaded the new versions to be found on thetagging with MusicBrainz Picard page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rodolfo &amp; Maria Cieri and others @ Dailymotion</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/07/22/rodolfo-maria-cieri-and-others-dailymotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2010 20:50:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/07/22/rodolfo-maria-cieri-and-others-dailymotion/</guid>
      <description>** **_I just discovered several early nineties videos at dailymotion, uploaded by tanguito94. If I&amp;rsquo;m not mistaken, this is filmed at the now defunct milonga El Akarense. _In addition to this one with Rodolfo &amp;amp; Maria Cieri from 1994, there is one with Pupi &amp;amp; Graciela, Pepito &amp;amp; Gilda and Stella Barba &amp;amp; Victor Romero.
Enjoy!
HT: Jorge</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Body Mechanics and Other Buzzwords</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/07/19/advanced-body-mechanics-and-other-buzzwords/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2010 12:13:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/07/19/advanced-body-mechanics-and-other-buzzwords/</guid>
      <description>Clearly, they got something out of all these body mechanics workshops&amp;hellip;
There is something about the fluffy prose of the tango advertising that is either funny or tragic. Maybe both. Why is it that the ones teaching &amp;lsquo;quality of movement&amp;rsquo; have nothing of the sort? What exactly is &amp;lsquo;organic tango&amp;rsquo;? (Tango Voice does a great job in dissecting that term). What about &amp;lsquo;body mechanics&amp;rsquo;? Apparently these are often used together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the Code</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/07/16/breaking-the-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2010 17:48:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/07/16/breaking-the-code/</guid>
      <description>by Onechis1
-- Using your eyes is the simplest if you feel a bit uncertain. -- See how the other guests behave. Everybody participates in a kind of theatre, where the guests, too, play their parts. That means that you are a part of the other people&#39;s experience, just like the others&#39; behaviour is a part of your experience. That is why behaving properly is a way of showing respect for the others&#39; experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simba tango on Facebook</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/07/16/simba-tango-on-facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2010 15:58:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/07/16/simba-tango-on-facebook/</guid>
      <description>by Spencer E Holtaway
If you already subscribe in some way or another, skip this post entirely. I added a facebook page for Simba tango in case you would like to get updates from this blog there.
Other subscription options include therss feed, rss feed for all comments, email subscription via feedburner and twitter.
That&amp;rsquo;s all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The &#39;Inventor of Jazz&#39; Plays the Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/07/14/the-inventor-of-jazz-plays-the-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2010 20:24:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/07/14/the-inventor-of-jazz-plays-the-tango/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ndash;There is this guy&amp;hellip;. and he plays the tango, too. I was at a Christmas party, sharing table with a guy that was writing his thesis on stride piano or pianists. Somehow the topic of tango had come up (strange, isn&amp;rsquo;t it?), and he was delighted to enlighten me about this early tango reference in American music. He promised to make me a copy, but that never materialized.
Nevertheless, I managed to track down the recordings myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nightmare</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/07/04/nightmare/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2010 22:25:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/07/04/nightmare/</guid>
      <description>The latest in tango fashion. Tell me it isn&amp;rsquo;t so&amp;hellip;
From the product pages:
   Either it’s after work, while studying or on a hung-over Sunday morning, this is a garment with a real statement: - Who cares!    This has got to be the ultimate subversive fashion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning the Language of Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/06/27/learning-the-language-of-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2010 17:30:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/06/27/learning-the-language-of-tango/</guid>
      <description>by Simba tango
If you don&amp;rsquo;t know the language of tango, you&amp;rsquo;ll miss out on a lot, and for once, I don&amp;rsquo;t mean in a metaphorical sense. One anecdote I remember from my early days of tango was being told of a workshop that started with the following announcement: &amp;rdquo;This is an advanced class, hence it will be taught in Spanish&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;m not sure who it supposedly was that said it, but I have a similar experience with Gustavo Naveira teaching in Buenos Aires with lots of foreigners present: &amp;ndash;Is there anyone here that speaks absolutely no Spanish?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Style</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/06/21/on-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2010 20:07:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/06/21/on-style/</guid>
      <description>by tdietmut
To do a dull thing with style--now **that&#39;s** what I call art.   _Charles Bukowski_    Few topics stir as much emotion among tango people as that of styles&amp;hellip; My style is better than yours, my teacher is stronger than yours, people dancing like this are like that&amp;hellip;
Or equally frustrating, claiming that styles do not exist. We all dance tango, only the others don&amp;rsquo;t get it&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango &amp; Football</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/06/18/tango-football/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2010 09:34:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/06/18/tango-football/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a little late to post about tango and football, they have been playing for a week already in the World Cup. I deejayed on the opening night and made sure to play a couple of football-related songs, Independiente Club and Racing Club. Don&amp;rsquo;t think anyone noticed though. Since I&amp;rsquo;m not really into football, I sort of cheer for Argentina, and they are doing well so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mickey Mousing</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/06/02/mickey-mousing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2010 19:47:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/06/02/mickey-mousing/</guid>
      <description>It seems to be spreading, a new way of interpreting music in tango. Every so often I hear people rave about some couple&amp;rsquo;s outstanding musicality and more often than not it translates to their mimicking every little plink and plonk in the music with a corresponding movement. Naturally, it requires good knowledge of the song to do this, but does it really demonstrate such great musicality?
I once heard this way of dancing called Mickey Mousing, as it was like this music was often used in animations, many from the 1930s and the 1940s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Better Slogan</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/05/28/a-better-slogan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2010 20:50:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/05/28/a-better-slogan/</guid>
      <description>by law_keven
Time to upgrade my deejaying slogan. While I still sort of like the tongue in cheek fluffy deejay advertisment in-joke of **Keine komische Musik, **it has several problems. It is in German, and doesn&amp;rsquo;t really translate well. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure people get the joke, they may not even understand German. Also it may come off a bit negative. I would prefer a more positive note, so to speak.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Birthday, Argentina!</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/05/25/happy-birthday-argentina/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2010 08:02:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/05/25/happy-birthday-argentina/</guid>
      <description>by globevisions
Argentina is turning 200 today and there are celebrations all over the country. Visit the official site for the bicentenario, where you can vote for the main symbols of Argentina, what defines the Argentinian. Interesting to see which symbols they have selected, and there are quite a few tango related, including the tango itself. From my experience the notion of the homeland (patria) is rather strong in Argentina so I guess this will be a great party!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Funny Animation by Artur Marcol</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/05/24/funny-animation-tango-argentino-by-artur-marcol/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2010 05:01:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/05/24/funny-animation-tango-argentino-by-artur-marcol/</guid>
      <description>A friend just sent me this Polish piece, called Tango Argentino, and I thought you might enjoy it as well. Did anyone say dancing for the woman&amp;hellip;?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations! | ¡Felicitaciones!</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/05/23/congratulations-felicitaciones/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2010 07:13:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/05/23/congratulations-felicitaciones/</guid>
      <description>The final of the campeonato de la ciudad (formerly campeonato metropoletano) was last night, and I am happy to see that Sebastián &amp;amp; Ines did well. Felicitaciones, chicos!
The full list of the winners is available here. The winners are:
 Alberto Markus &amp;amp; Ana María Polito (&amp;ldquo;Tango Salon&amp;rdquo; Senior)
 Lucas Carrizo &amp;amp; María Paula Tejeda (&amp;ldquo;Tango Salón&amp;rdquo; Adulto)
 Ariel Manzanares &amp;amp; Daniela Cerquides (&amp;ldquo;Milonga&amp;rdquo;)
 Sebastián Jimenez &amp;amp; María Inés Bogado (&amp;ldquo;Vals&amp;rdquo;)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tango Hustle</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/05/14/the-tango-hustle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2010 18:39:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/05/14/the-tango-hustle/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ndash;So&amp;hellip; what are these guys up to? There I was, attending my very first tango festival. I did not know very much about tango, but I did know enough to notice this couple. They were dancing, but they were doing something quite different&amp;hellip; Different indeed. Yet there was something tangoish over it. Not quite ballroom tango, not quite Argentine tango, still a hint of tango.
Only watching Saturday Night Fever probably years later, did I realize: What they had been doing was the tango hustle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The origins of &#39;Tango Nuevo&#39;</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/05/01/the-origins-of-nuevo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 17:55:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/05/01/the-origins-of-nuevo/</guid>
      <description>When I heard about the Dinzel book, I thought it was sort of a curious project. Working through all possibilities of tango steps, charting them out in elaborate diagrams with circles and arrows in all directions demonstrating the vast space of choreographic possibilites. I had a look at the book at a friend&amp;rsquo;s place several years ago, but it felt somehow disconnected to how I experienced the dance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution?</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/04/27/evolution-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2010 20:35:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/04/27/evolution-2/</guid>
      <description>I hear it every so often: that tango technique, especially for women, has gone through a tremendous evolution since the resurgence in the early 1980s. Let&amp;rsquo;s just say I&amp;rsquo;m not quite convinced. Watch this clip from the 1988 movie Tango Bar, and draw your own conclusions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bocca Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/04/24/bocca-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2010 19:23:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/04/24/bocca-tango/</guid>
      <description>Make no mistake. This is ballet. Julio Bocca is a famous ballet dancer, and was praised by Juan Carlos Copes in Tango: Bayle Nuestro, so to watch his take on tango, Bocca Tango was intriguing. (You can get it @ ebay)
What I didn&amp;rsquo;t know before watching it was that this performance leads me back to the very beginnings of my own tango journey. It was performed at the Maipo theatre in 2001, and I think it was on at the time of my first visit to Buenos Aires.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confronting the Past</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/04/21/confronting-the-past/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2010 10:19:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/04/21/confronting-the-past/</guid>
      <description>by willposh
As tango lovers we want to love Argentina. But Argentina is a country with many problems and a difficult past, making it a country hard to love unconditionally.
It was therefore good news to hear that now that the official Argentina finally faces the horrors of the dirty war, the last dictator of Argentina, Reynaldo Bignone, has been sentenced to 25 years in prison (also covered by the BBC &amp;amp; NYT).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maria Ines Bogado &amp; Sebastian Jimenez</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/04/19/maria-ines-bogado-sebastian-jimenez/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2010 19:56:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/04/19/maria-ines-bogado-sebastian-jimenez/</guid>
      <description>I just had to share this lovely performance by these talented dancers who will no doubt be familiar to anyone frequenting the práctica at Sunderland. Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Music Instinct</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/04/18/the-music-instinct/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2010 19:43:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/04/18/the-music-instinct/</guid>
      <description>You know more about music than you think. You start picking up the rules from the day you are born, yes even before. And part of what makes music enjoyable is this knowledge of what to expect and the delight when your expectations are fulfilled, or some times bent a little before they find resolution.
This is part of the message of a fascinating book about music, The Music Instinct by Philip Ball, (read reviews for instance in The Economist, or in The Guardian) a book that I finally had time to finish reading this week-end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adiós Maestro</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/04/18/adios-maestro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2010 19:03:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/04/18/adios-maestro/</guid>
      <description>by Simba tango
Friday morning brought more sad news from Buenos Aires. It is time to complete the biography of El &amp;ldquo;Turco&amp;rdquo; José Brahemcha. Another great milonguero is gone.
He had been sick for a while, so in a sense it was no surprise, and we did wonder if we were ever to see him again as we parted for the last time from his apartment in Buenos Aires.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Fundamentals of Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/04/14/three-fundamentals-of-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2010 21:13:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/04/14/three-fundamentals-of-tango/</guid>
      <description>by Peter Forret
Whenever I hear the postulate that everything in tango is either a step forward, a step backwards or a side step, I get a little irritated. I know what they mean, and it&amp;rsquo;s not that it is entirely wrong, it&amp;rsquo;s rather that it is incomplete, and it tends to send people off in a very step oriented direction. But I have written about that before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hurrying slowly</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/03/30/hurry-slowly/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2010 10:42:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/03/30/hurry-slowly/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ndash;So when are you guys going on tour? &amp;ndash;Well. I don&amp;rsquo;t know. It&amp;rsquo;s no hurry&amp;hellip;
A few months later, they are teaching and performing in Hong Kong. Never in a hurry, but moving along nicely. Just as it is supposed to be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letras de tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/03/29/letras-de-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2010 09:14:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/03/29/letras-de-tango/</guid>
      <description>We all know that tango is about lost love, broken hearts, right? Well &amp;ndash; now we can check it out. Hans at Amsterdam tango club put all the 13,000 lyrics they got in their online database in a single html file, which made it rather easy to do some statistics. I wrote a small script, counting the occurrences of each word, and the figure above is a representation of the results, but leaving the very shortest words like y, o, el, lo etc out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience the breadth of tango in Buenos Aires</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/03/24/experience-the-breadth-of-tango-in-buenos-aires/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 12:54:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/03/24/experience-the-breadth-of-tango-in-buenos-aires/</guid>
      <description>by Simba tango
A friend is going to Buenos Aires for the first time this week, and I sent her some information about where to go, encouraging her to experience the breadth of tango in Buenos Aires. So many people get stuck in one small part of the tango world and never experience anything else. When they come back, they believe they know how the tango in Buenos Aires is&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whiskey Tango Foxtrot</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/03/11/whiskey-tango-foxtrot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2010 20:09:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/03/11/whiskey-tango-foxtrot/</guid>
      <description>by hdeb89
I was dancing a nice tanda with a friend of a friend, and while it was not exactly my favorite music, we were doing fine. We were having a good time. There were lots of people dancing, nobody got hurt, and we were dancing peacefully among the other couples. So far so good&amp;hellip;
I appreciated the festival organizers&amp;rsquo; effort to give some extra credit to the djs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;El Turco&#34; José Brahemcha -- a short biography</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/03/09/el-turco-jose-brahemcha-a-short-biography/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2010 19:23:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/03/09/el-turco-jose-brahemcha-a-short-biography/</guid>
      <description>El &#34;Turco&#34; José -- as he is commonly known -- was born in Buenos Aires, in the neighborhood of Saavedra, July 17 1931. He was a dedicated bicycle rider when he was a kid, until his mother (who was a tango singer) suggested that he learn to dance &#34;to get to know some girls&#34;. At the age of 16, he started to practice with his friends from his neighborhood in the house of one of them, where they had a gramophone player.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DJing again</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/03/04/djing-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2010 22:01:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/03/04/djing-again/</guid>
      <description>by The unnamed
After a break of almost two years, I&amp;rsquo;m djing again this Weekend. I must say I look forward to it, knowing I will like the music at the milonga is always nice ;-) I got so much new music that I&amp;rsquo;m eager to use. While setting up my computer again (which was reinstalled after a breakdown a year ago) and doing some preparations, I listened to some of my favorite music, which was really nice, too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango Audio Restoration</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/03/01/tango-audio-restoration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 21:29:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/03/01/tango-audio-restoration/</guid>
      <description>Tango music was recorded with equipment much inferior to what is available today. Adding to that, the record companies threw away the master&amp;rsquo;s leaving us with reproductions based on the shellac records that further deteriate the sound.
For many of the commercial releases of tango music, the Reliquias series, the 78RPM series etc, the transfers have been cleaned and the noises removed for the music to become more clear and easy to listen to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do the Argentines have it in their blood?</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/18/do-the-argentines-have-it-in-their-blood/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2010 18:13:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/18/do-the-argentines-have-it-in-their-blood/</guid>
      <description>by themanwithsalthair
&amp;ndash;You have to realize, Simba, that there are great non-Argentine teachers, too! This argument came up in a heated debate, and while I agree in principle, the teachers she had in mind were mediocre at best, so it didn&amp;rsquo;t really change my opinion much. In an online debate along similar lines, I once noticed an attempt to ridicule the ones pointing out the Argentines&amp;rsquo; comparative advantage in tango by comparing them to people holding the view that the &amp;lsquo;negroes had it in their blood&amp;rsquo; (when talking about rhythm, obviously).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Look! No hands!</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/17/look-no-hands/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2010 21:07:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/17/look-no-hands/</guid>
      <description>by mag3737
There seems to be a common misunderstanding that you are not supposed to use your arms when dancing tango.
That is wrong on so many levels. I can see where it comes from, as it is a common mistake among beginners to do try leading with their hands, and not using the rest of their bodies. But one thing is to make point to beginners and quite another to elevate it to a universal truth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Essence of Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/16/tango-essence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2010 19:30:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/16/tango-essence/</guid>
      <description>When we watched the milongueros dancing years ago, we could perceive the mystery behind what they did, no matter if it was easy or difficult. Therefore, technique has to be understood first, then it can be copied, but the goal is to get to its essence. If you use the word &#34;technique&#34; less in class, and instead use words like &#34;essence&#34; and &#34;sensation&#34;, students can perform the movement with a more natural attitude and will learn faster than if you speak about numbers, diagonals or muscles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experiment shows: walking heel first more efficient</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/16/experiment-shows-walking-heel-first-more-efficient/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2010 17:51:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/16/experiment-shows-walking-heel-first-more-efficient/</guid>
      <description>This will not, of course, settle the agelong debate of whether to walk toe first or heel first in tango. Still, I found it interesting that there has recently been published research on the efficiency of the human walk, specifically investigating walking heel first versus walking toe first. If you are striving for the most efficient walk, their conclusion might be worth noting:
   When human subjects walked with their heels slightly elevated in a ‘low-digitigrade’[toe first] posture, COT [cost of transport] increased by 53% above that of normal plantigrade [heel first] walking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;El Turco&#39; José Brahemcha</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/14/el-turco-jose-brahemcha/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2010 11:38:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/14/el-turco-jose-brahemcha/</guid>
      <description>I have only one great regret in tango, and that it not taking classes with Gavito. Of course there are others as well, but with Gavito we had the opportunity, we passed, and shame on us for it. Of course, at the time we simply didn&amp;rsquo;t know better.
Determined not to make same mistake again, we decided to take our teachers&amp;rsquo; advice and try to get in touch with the legendary &amp;lsquo;El Turco&amp;rsquo; José.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Audio Myths</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/09/audio-myths/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2010 21:22:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/09/audio-myths/</guid>
      <description>Now, this may be only remotely relevant to tango, but tango music and hence its reproduction is important for dancers and djs in particular, so here it goes. I think the lessons from this video are most relevant when it comes to making decisions about equipment such as sound cards for djing, lossless versus lossy encoding of music and quality of transfers and restorations.
If you hang out at hydrogenaudio, this will all be familiar, but I have to say actually performing an abx was a humbling experience with regards to what I can and can&amp;rsquo;t hear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How less becomes more</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/01/how-less-becomes-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 20:02:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/01/how-less-becomes-more/</guid>
      <description>by hooverine
There was something she said that stayed with me. So well put. &amp;lsquo;When he leads a step, say backwards for the woman&amp;rsquo;, Graciela said, &amp;lsquo;then there is one possibility: going backwards. There are not three possible steps. Not three, not two. One.&amp;rsquo;
All the time I see so called &amp;lsquo;advanced&amp;rsquo; dancers, throwing their partners around, the women looking like nervous chicken trying to guess the right thing to do for each and every step.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What does it mean to dance with &#39;good musicality&#39;?</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/01/22/what-does-it-mean-to-dance-with-good-musicality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2010 19:41:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/01/22/what-does-it-mean-to-dance-with-good-musicality/</guid>
      <description>by mhowry
Tango dancers often discuss the importance of dancing to the music, having &amp;lsquo;good musicality&amp;rsquo; etc. But what exactly does it mean to dance musically? I tried noting some possibilities, and since some are very basic, while other are more advanced (and should be used sparingly).
I tried to classify them within the usual trichotomy of beginner/intermediate/advanced, thinking that you have to know the very basics, and you should master basically everything in the intermediate before venturing out into the advanced concepts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango™</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/01/17/tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2010 20:43:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/01/17/tango/</guid>
      <description>by ehfisher
   ## (...)[L]ife&#39;s most vital meeting (...)   (...)[I]nspired by the meeting of male and female: man and woman. The feminine in the masculine subconscious (Anima) and the masculine in the female subconscious (Animus), and the complementary in the two archetypal sides. Tango (...) exudes passion, pride, love and attraction (...) Take pleasure in the dance (...) Not about a class or show, but about salt and pepper mills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tempting...</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/01/13/tempting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2010 21:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/01/13/tempting/</guid>
      <description>by Leo T.
First day at work. First day in my old office for over nine months. On my desk is a roll of paper. I chat with the guy I&amp;rsquo;m sharing office with, and he tells me that my colleague in the office next door left it for me. Said colleague must have heard us talking, and enters the office. &amp;ndash;The organizer gave it to me, and I brought it back for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tristeza</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/01/10/tristeza/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2010 22:45:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/01/10/tristeza/</guid>
      <description>It is all too much. It is so frikkin&amp;rsquo; cold, reality slaps us in the face, and then this. The loss of a brilliant dancer, so young. How sad for a mother to outlive her son. Too much.
Que en paz descanse. We will miss you.
Video tip by TP</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>P.H. Shoes</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/01/04/p-h-shoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2010 01:52:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/01/04/p-h-shoes/</guid>
      <description>I got the shoe factory P.H. recommended from several reliable sources, unfortunately I got the directions a little late, so we&amp;rsquo;ll see if I make it in time. Anyway, as a reference for next visit, here it is:
Grito de Asencio 3602, Pompeya - Buenos Aires
Tel/Fax: 4911-0295
The colectivo (bus) 160 goes there, according to the owner of the shoes in the bag above.
[xmlgm {http://maps.google.com/maps/ms?vps=2&amp;amp;jsv=196c&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;msa=0&amp;amp;output=nl&amp;amp;msid=112630563826716696064.00047bcc8224b458afdf1} width=500;height=400}]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quality of CTA bootlegs</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/01/03/quality-of-cta-bootlegs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2010 22:47:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/01/03/quality-of-cta-bootlegs/</guid>
      <description>Usually, I don&amp;rsquo;t buy bootlegs, but when it comes to tango music, there is some material that is not available from the commercial releases like Reliquias, Tango Argentino etc. I always concentrated on the commercial releases, but now that I have most of the interesting material from these releases, I have moved on the the more exotic releases, like the Club Tango Argentino by Akihito Baba. They are unfortunately hard to get by, and several are out of print.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buenos Aires (tango) murales</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/01/03/buenos-aires-tango-murales/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2010 01:12:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/01/03/buenos-aires-tango-murales/</guid>
      <description>by Simba tango
Several places in Buenos Aires, you will find paintings covering an entire wall, called &amp;lsquo;murales&amp;rsquo;. They have a long history in Buenos Aires, the oldest were painted for the churches of the city in the 1700s and 1800s. In the beginning of the 20th century, they were often used to portray fight against oppression, think Picasso&amp;rsquo;s Guernica. Less political, but as Buenos Aires is the home of tango, there are of course several paintings featuring tango music and dance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is it not in the public domain?</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/01/02/why-is-it-not-in-the-public-domain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2010 01:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/01/02/why-is-it-not-in-the-public-domain/</guid>
      <description>by Ioan Sameli
Entering a new year, it can be wise to give thought to how things could have been. Most of the world follows the USA when it comes to copyright laws, and they keep extending the copyright terms again and again. Which makes very little sense from a society stand point. Extending the copyright on the 1930s recordings of Juan D&amp;rsquo;Arienzo isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly making him pour out new hit records every month&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Champagne tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/31/champagne-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2009 19:11:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/31/champagne-tango/</guid>
      <description>by Simba tango
The Argentines have this thing about champagne. Not usually the real thing, but their own version. Which is actually quite good, and of course much cheaper. Going shopping in our closest super market makes this very clear, they have coolers, a fridge with pre cooled &amp;lsquo;champan&amp;rsquo; (as they like to call it), rows and rows of different brands and special promotions: Buy this and that and get half a bottle for free!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buenos Aires Street Art</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/28/buenos-aires-street-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2009 16:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/28/buenos-aires-street-art/</guid>
      <description>by Simba tango
I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share some photos from the streets of Buenos Aires where there you can often see the kind of graffitti made with stencils. Among the motifs I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered are tango in the incarnation of Osvaldo Pugliese and a new electrotango band called tranxgo, football icon Maradona, not so subtle drug references and lots of other stuff.
[flickr-gallery mode=&amp;ldquo;photoset&amp;rdquo; photoset=&amp;ldquo;72157622958599173&amp;rdquo;]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cachafaz alfajores</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/23/cachafaz-alfajores/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2009 02:17:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/23/cachafaz-alfajores/</guid>
      <description>Did you ever get the alfajores of Havanna in Buenos Aires recommended? And they did not live up to your expectations? Well, maybe I can tell you why.
First, an alfajor is a sort of biscuit or cookie, normally two layers with dulce de leche in between. They exist in different varieties, the main ones are the ones covered with chocolate, and the ones of maizena (of which I prefer the latter).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inside the digital archive</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/22/inside-the-digital-archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2009 01:45:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/22/inside-the-digital-archive/</guid>
      <description>by Erica_Marshall
After Ignacio Varchausky gave his musicality seminar at theCasa de tango here in Buenos Aires, where the TangoVía project resides, he was kind to show us around the premises and demonstrate the current state of the digital archive.
They have a very nice set of equipment, he showed us the machine they use to clean the discs properly before doing the transfers, the different turntables for different kinds of discs, amplifiers and ADC as well as tape equipment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to listen for in tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/20/what-to-listen-for-in-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2009 01:29:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/20/what-to-listen-for-in-tango/</guid>
      <description>by ~Oryctes~
Knowing what to listen for can greatly improve how much you appreciate music. I had the opportunity to attend a workshop with Ignacio Varchausky on listening to tango music. It was very interesting, and it turned out that it corresponded with a post I was planning to write as soon as I got back to my copy of Aaron Copland&amp;rsquo;s What to listen for in music.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>El Tangauta interviews Chicho</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/16/el-tangauta-interviews-chicho/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2009 03:28:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/16/el-tangauta-interviews-chicho/</guid>
      <description>Another interesting interview with Chicho, and he elaborates on some of the same things as in theprevious interview.
[The] milongueros had respect, delicacy and sensibility, it was totally different. I know my role is contradictory, because I also collaborated in generating this young movement. In its moment I got tired of the strict milonguero codes that didn’t correspond with my time and to rebel I tried to make my way. Today I’m a milonguero again (laughter); I’m against the people who do not cabecear (nod), who don’t have codes or respect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treating the symptoms</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/06/treating-the-symptoms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2009 00:41:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/06/treating-the-symptoms/</guid>
      <description>by Dradd.
I had a laugh when I read this part by MovementInvitesMovement. In their wonderful, provocative style, they wrote an entire post about something that I hinted at in a comment in my post about clothes and tango.
Some hard core dancers would say that if it gets too warm with the jacket on, you are waisting energy ![;-)](http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif) When my beloved wife read that, her immediate reaction was: hard core dancers?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not so easy</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/11/30/not-so-easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2009 01:10:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/11/30/not-so-easy/</guid>
      <description>by Simba tango
A teacher and his former student, on his first trip to Buenos Aires, run into each other outside La Glorieta and starts to chat. Suddenly the student bursts out:
**A:** (about the music) This is milonga, right? **S: **No, this is tango. The conversation is drawing to an end, as the teacher is heading home. They talk for another minute, until the next song of the tanda starts and the student is eager to dance more:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hola Papa Noel...</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/11/25/hola-papa-noel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2009 02:32:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/11/25/hola-papa-noel/</guid>
      <description>Did you check your list twice? This is old, but I saved it for Christmas time. Not really related to tango, except we were introduced to it by tango people. In spring. My wife&amp;rsquo;s pregnancy was just becoming official, and the unborn baby instantly earned his first nickname: Jorgito. &amp;ndash;But don&amp;rsquo;t name him Jorgito, that&amp;rsquo;s not nice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Mariano &#39;Chicho&#39; Frumboli</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/11/23/interview-with-mariano-chicho-frumboli/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2009 23:14:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/11/23/interview-with-mariano-chicho-frumboli/</guid>
      <description>by parakulturado
   [T]oday there is a new generation that learned to dance 2,3 or 5 years ago, who only know how to do the new styles, the ganchos, the colgadas, but who are not in contact with everything that came before, and I go to the milongas and I see people that know how to move but that don’t know how to dance, people don’t breathe tango like they did before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance Insights</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/11/16/performance-insights/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2009 13:52:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/11/16/performance-insights/</guid>
      <description>As I was uploading a couple of new videos at youtube, I noticed the &amp;lsquo;Attention&amp;rsquo; ranking of my videos in the &amp;lsquo;Insights&amp;rsquo; section. The video with most attention (showed by a red bar like in the illustration top centre) is a video showing Jorge Dispari and María &amp;lsquo;La Turca&amp;rsquo; del Carmen at Confitería Ideal. At the time of writing, this video has been viewed 11 852 times.
Youtube describes the calculation of the video &amp;lsquo;hot spots&amp;rsquo; like this: &amp;rdquo;The ups-and-downs of viewership at each moment in your video, compared to videos of similar length.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roxana Suarez &amp; Sebastián Achaval en la Baldosa</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/11/14/roxana-suarez-sebastian-achaval-en-la-baldosa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2009 18:34:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/11/14/roxana-suarez-sebastian-achaval-en-la-baldosa/</guid>
      <description>A beautiful night at La Baldosa in Flores, chatting and dancing with friends and the wonderful performance by Roxana &amp;amp; Sebastián.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tailored for Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/11/06/tailored-for-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2009 23:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/11/06/tailored-for-tango/</guid>
      <description>by wmacphail
&amp;ndash;Come back here! You are not entering the floor without buttoning your jacket! Her voice left no doubt, and the young aspiring dancer stepped back, buttoned his jacket and went back on the dance floor. He was smiling, but he would not commit the same error again.
In one of my very first tango lessons, I was told that the Argentine dancers would never take off their jacket for dancing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful foobar2000 formatting strings</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/useful-foobar2000-formatting-strings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2009 14:18:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/useful-foobar2000-formatting-strings/</guid>
      <description>Formatting for djing TINT $num(%barcode%,14)-$num($max(1.%disc%),2)-$num(%track%,2)  Date To display dates from tango.info properly (only confirmed dates with correct formatting)
$if2($greater($strstr(%date%,&#39;--&#39;),0),$date($left(%date%,10)))  Album To get album names including catalognumber and artist, e.g. &amp;lsquo;CTA261 Adolfo Carabelli Vol.1 (1931-1933)&amp;lsquo; I use this formatting string with the %album_pubcode% and %album_name% and %artist% from tango.info:
$replace($replace(%catalognumber%,&#39; &#39;,),&#39;-&#39;,) %artist% %album%  Use the above with the automatically fill values tool from the properties dialogue. Choose source &amp;lsquo;Other&amp;rsquo; and set the above as source.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your most underrated skill set</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/11/03/your-most-underrated-skill-set/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2009 16:28:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/11/03/your-most-underrated-skill-set/</guid>
      <description>Eye contact. According to American Airlines. Funny coincidence I saw this ad just a couple of days before we left for Buenos Aires, as we were flying AA. The photo is taken in San Telmo if I am not mistaken.
Does this mean AA know the cabeceo?
They canceled our flight, by the way, and the car seat did not fit in the seat, and they put us in the very back, so I can&amp;rsquo;t say we were very happy with them, hence no temptation to think it was destiny or anything&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going, going, and...</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/10/31/going-going-and/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2009 23:55:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/10/31/going-going-and/</guid>
      <description>by Koluso
The airplane takes off with a roar.
Passing over woods.
Passing over cities.
Passing over lakes.
Passing over farmlands.
Passing over oceans.
Leaving a white stripe in the clear blue sky.
Going.
Going.
And gooone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ignacio Varchausky interview</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/10/30/ignacio-varchausky-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2009 00:03:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/10/30/ignacio-varchausky-interview/</guid>
      <description>by smiling_da_vinci
Keith over at totango.net just published an interview with Ignacio of El Arranque, Orquesta Escuela de tango &amp;amp; TangoVia, and you can download it from his page. He doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide a permalink for his post, so for future reference, the files can be found here part one, part two and part three.
I haven&amp;rsquo;t had time to check it out myself yet, maybe on the plane&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New CD from OT Fernández Fierro</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/10/21/new-cd-from-ot-fernandez-fierro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2009 02:08:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/10/21/new-cd-from-ot-fernandez-fierro/</guid>
      <description>by Simba tango
The punk kids of tango just released another album. It looks like it is called Fernández Fierro, and is available at Zival&amp;rsquo;s/Tangostore. I used to be very enthusiastic about these guys, but after their last release Mucha Mierda (the photo above is from the release party at la Trastienda), I was a bit disappointed, much like Michael Lavocah was. Too harsh, brutal and little variation. But then, that is what they said about D&amp;rsquo;Arienzo in the 30s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Golden Age Visualized</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/10/17/the-golden-age-visualized/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2009 03:28:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/10/17/the-golden-age-visualized/</guid>
      <description>Golden Age of Tango When was the Golden Age of tango, exactly? It is fairly common to say 1935-1955 mas o menos, but while I was playing around with the data at tango.info, I thought it would be fun to make a plot to **see when the Golden Age was. And here it is. **
These are the number of unique recordings in the database, so if a recording is issued on several cds, it is only counted once.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bring out your lion</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/10/13/bring-out-your-lion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2009 03:26:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/10/13/bring-out-your-lion/</guid>
      <description>by digitalART2
How could Simba not like a workshop that started by working with bringing out your inner lion? Not the little cute one, but the grown up, strong one?
The day started rather low, though. &amp;ndash;I am not feeling well, and I had been looking forward to this for so long. La princesa went straight back to bed and needed to stay there, it seemed. I was taking our little guy to his arts class, and she would go to the women&amp;rsquo;s technique class with Graciela.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting out of the quagmire</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/10/09/getting-out-of-the-quagmire/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2009 03:40:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/10/09/getting-out-of-the-quagmire/</guid>
      <description>I was considering using a grandiose title for this post. Something like Return of a King or The Comeback or something along those lines. But it doesn&amp;rsquo;t quite feel that way. I feels more like finally getting a kick in the butt, and slowly getting out of the quagmire, one millimeter at the time.
Actually it was rather two kicks in the butt. The first was that a couple we know here that is in the same situation as us actually went to a tango dance before us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Japan Update</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/10/01/japan-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 01:49:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/10/01/japan-update/</guid>
      <description>Finally somevideos of the new champions. Bear over with the person holding the camera not being able to keep still, and make sure you get the milonga at the end. The Argentine newspaper Clarin has a short interview with them.
I mentioned in a previous post that Japan was important because of the collectors of tango music there, and Royce recently posted several posts (here, here and here [UPDATE: She added part 4, part 5 and part 6] ) on this topic that are well worth a read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Panther Tango (1967)</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/28/the-panther-tango-1967/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2009 02:26:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/28/the-panther-tango-1967/</guid>
      <description>Now someone is having a ball, evidently&amp;hellip; (From an ad for rum in LIFE - Nov 3, 1967)
Anyone knows what the Panther Tango at the Plaza in 1928 refers to? It sure can&amp;rsquo;t be Pantera tanguera by Cuarteto Almagro (on the album Hemisferios)&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Important difference</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/27/important-difference/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2009 02:44:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/27/important-difference/</guid>
      <description>by Peter Forret
As much as I love embracing the beautiful women in tango&amp;ndash;there is nothing quite like being embraced by the beautiful women in tango.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thrill your partners...  (1940)</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/26/thrill-your-partners-1940/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2009 02:21:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/26/thrill-your-partners-1940/</guid>
      <description>**Jim used to wonder** why he never enjoyed dancing---why he hesitated whenever he asked a friend to be his partner. One evening when he was trying to make up his mind to ask a very charming young lady to dance, he suddenly realized that if his dancing were more modern... he would get more enjoyment out of life. Jim took a few lessons at the Arthur Murray Studios. Today he is not only an excellent dancer, but he has also gained poise and confidence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old fashioned dance report</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/25/old-fashioned-dance-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2009 01:58:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/25/old-fashioned-dance-report/</guid>
      <description>by wallyg
We are so used to watching youtube videos from dancers&amp;rsquo; exhibition all over the world, and I thought I would share an enthusiastic review using words to describe the impact seeing one of the talented young tango couples can have on a spectator without a background in tango (I think).
She and he combine gorgeously. No acrobatic lifts (no lifts at all, if I remember rightly), no high kicks; just two bodies scarcely sundered while dancing in unbroken streams of changing ideas to the music.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homero Manzi, un poeta en la tormenta</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/23/homero-manzi-un-poeta-en-la-tormenta/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 23:35:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/23/homero-manzi-un-poeta-en-la-tormenta/</guid>
      <description>A new film about the tango poet Homero Manzi was just released in Argentina. Manzi is the author of famous tangos like Malena, Sur and Barrio de tango. He worked with Troilo for several years, and in cooperation with Sebastián Piana, he revitalized the milonga genre with Milonga sentimental in 1931.
The film is apparently a combination of archive material and reconstruction of scenes from his life. It will be interesting to watch, I will probably wait until it is available on dvd, hopefully it won&amp;rsquo;t take that long.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s in a name?</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/23/whats-in-a-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 03:21:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/23/whats-in-a-name/</guid>
      <description>by ricmcarthur
There is this new milonga in the the town I grew up, and of all things they have called it La colgada. Now, that gives me all the wrong associations when it comes to a milonga, but from how I know the tango scene there, I guess it is merely truth in advertising.
But come on, naming a milonga after a step/figure? Why on earth would you do that?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obsessive?</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/22/you-say-it-like-its-a-bad-thing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2009 02:52:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/22/you-say-it-like-its-a-bad-thing/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m not in the market for a new car, but somehow the heading of this ad struck a nerve&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango and Toddler in Buenos Aires</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/15/tango-and-toddler-in-buenos-aires/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2009 00:03:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/15/tango-and-toddler-in-buenos-aires/</guid>
      <description>by salvoguille
Dear readers: I need your advice: We consider ourselves to find our way around in Buenos Aires fairly well after several previous stays there. This time, however, there is something different. We are no longer a couple going to the milongas every night. We are a small family.
Strolling with or without purpose in the streets of our beloved city we can still do, enjoying café con leche while watching people walk past, too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on a popular embrace</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/07/notes-on-a-popular-embrace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2009 03:07:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/07/notes-on-a-popular-embrace/</guid>
      <description>by Peter Forret
I have seen quite a few dismissive comments of a certain embrace lately, someone calling it &amp;lsquo;Reaching for the man&amp;rsquo;s back pants pocket&amp;rsquo;-embrace just recently (in the comments, here). Which doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound very nice to me. I assume it is the one pictured above that is referred to, although I would have to say she is a little off if she is going for this pockets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quality and snobs</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/05/quality-and-snobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2009 02:30:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/05/quality-and-snobs/</guid>
      <description>by 96dpi
Food (and drinks) metaphors for tango seem to be popular lately, so here in another one: My brother and I have two very distinct wine quality stories that I find very amusing when seen together. Each involves a young woman, at the age where going to parties and flirting with alcohol is at its most exciting, somewhere just before or just after going to university.
#1: A rather simple red wine was served with the main dish at a dinner party with the entire class of that year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zapatillas de tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/02/zapatillas-de-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2009 22:26:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/02/zapatillas-de-tango/</guid>
      <description>Guess what was in the mailbox for our little son the other day? A nice pair of &amp;lsquo;shoes&amp;rsquo; made by a friend back home. She has specialized in this kind of baby footwear perfect for developing small feet and new walking skills.
All hand made, she makes an effort in always finding a new twist, theming them with butterflies, elephants or monsters. Or creating the very first tango shoes for a tangobaby.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big in Japan</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/01/big-in-japan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:05:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/01/big-in-japan/</guid>
      <description>by skyseeker
Seeing the reactions from many after the Japanese couple Hiroshi &amp;amp; Kyoko Yamao won the mundial de tango salón as the first non-Argentines, it seems many in the tango world are unaware of the long traditions of tango in Japan. Or maybe some practice selective memory&amp;hellip;
Todotango has an interesting article on the rise of tango in Japan. While the tradition is certainly shorter in terms of years since the first impact than in Europe (Megata&amp;rsquo;s first contact with tango was in Paris in the 1920s), it does not lack much, and in a way it represents a tradition closer to the original than in Europe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Campeones mundiales de tango salon 2009: Hiroshi &amp; Kyoko Yamao (JP)</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/30/campeones-mundiales-de-tango-salon-2009-hiroshi-kyoko-yamao-jp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2009 01:27:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/30/campeones-mundiales-de-tango-salon-2009-hiroshi-kyoko-yamao-jp/</guid>
      <description>I have wondered whether the Argentine would ever select a non-argentine couple to win the tango salon category. Now I know, the fabulous Japanese couple Hiroshi &amp;amp; Kyoko just won the first prize! Great dancers and great people! Felicitaciones!!!
UPDATE:
2xtango got pictures and video from the last ronda with Hiroshi and Kyoko and a nice post about the winners. Also Hiroshi and Kyoko have some pictures at their blog (machine translated from Japanese).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reviving the art of improvisation</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/29/reviving-the-art-of-improvisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2009 20:52:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/29/reviving-the-art-of-improvisation/</guid>
      <description>by paula moya
As a nice apropos to the recent discussion I had with Tangocommuter about improvisation in tango, there is an interesting article in the current issue of The New Yorker about the possible return of the improvised cadenza in western art music:
The art of embellishment—improvising cadenzas, adding ornaments, taking other opportunities for creativity in performance—is a hot topic in classical music these days. For generations, conservatories preached absolute fidelity to the score: do what the composer wrote and nothing more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>¡Mucha mierda en el mundial!</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/29/mucha-mierda-en-el-mundial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2009 18:19:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/29/mucha-mierda-en-el-mundial/</guid>
      <description>by Simba tango
Tonight is the night of the final of the mundial (world championship) of tango salon. While I always found the idea of a competition in social dancing somewhat absurd, it happens that for the last couple of years several friends have been among the finalists, and that made it all more interesting.
It all starts at 1900 local time, and rumors have it there will be live broadcast, and I will try to catch it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango in music videos</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/29/tango-in-music-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2009 01:47:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/29/tango-in-music-videos/</guid>
      <description>Old but good: tango (the dance) is used to sell musical forms that may have little in common with tango. These examples show that cliches can be treated elegantly and with humour. Not to say that the dancing is necessarily very elegant&amp;hellip;
My favorite: the Van Damage. The gotan one is quite cool, too.
          </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The structure of a tango, choreography and how it might improve your dancing</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/28/the-structure-of-a-tango-choreography-and-how-it-might-improve-your-dancing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2009 01:46:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/28/the-structure-of-a-tango-choreography-and-how-it-might-improve-your-dancing/</guid>
      <description>by aperte
If you prefer your naïve, pure emotional interpretation of the tango, you might not want to read this. If, on the other hand you think that knowing a little about how tango music is organized might increase the breadth or depth of your musical appreciation, then this could be for you.
Like Tangocommuter writes in the discussion of how a tango became approximately three minutes long, a prototypical tango has the structure ABA:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango @ Times Square</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/23/tango-times-square/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2009 02:31:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/23/tango-times-square/</guid>
      <description>
Above: Simba @ Times Square
Below: Los Hermanos Macana @ Times Square
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost perfect</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/17/almost-perfect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2009 02:29:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/17/almost-perfect/</guid>
      <description>by Stuck in Customs
It was my first tanda in the milongas with her. In the break between two dances at the legendary milonga at Club Sunderland, I was chatting with la preciosa, who later became one of my dearest tango friends. She asked me if I knew who was dancing (the exhibition) that night, and I confirmed, that yes, of course I knew. It was the very reason I went there that night, in fact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango Vía in El Tangauta</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/11/tango-via-in-el-tangauta/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2009 03:13:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/11/tango-via-in-el-tangauta/</guid>
      <description>by Leo Reynolds
If youfound the Tango Vía project interesting, there is a full article in the current edition of El Tangauta (No 178). You can get the entire magazine as pdf if you register at their website. All quotes are from English version of the interview in that edition. In addition, there is a lot of interesting reading on the Tango Vía project&amp;rsquo;s web site (in Spanish) about how they do the digital copies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mickey Mouse -- The Gallopin&#39; Gaucho (1928)</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/10/mickey-mouse-the-gallopin-gaucho-1928/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2009 03:02:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/10/mickey-mouse-the-gallopin-gaucho-1928/</guid>
      <description>HT: ShelleyDelaine</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homenaje a los milongueros -- the show</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/10/homenaje-a-los-milongueros-the-show/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2009 02:30:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/10/homenaje-a-los-milongueros-the-show/</guid>
      <description>Marisa Galindo was directing a show in honor of the milongueros, and she is now posting footage from this show on youtube for all of us to see! The show was filmed on the 16th of October 1991, Homenaje a los Milongueros de Buenos Aires.
I have seen fragments of this show before, but didn&amp;rsquo;t know the source, and this seems to be much better quality and I think complete. Truth to be told, I haven&amp;rsquo;t had time to watch it all yet, but I will, and I will watch it again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In search for the authentic</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/07/in-search-for-the-authentic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2009 02:18:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/07/in-search-for-the-authentic/</guid>
      <description>by MR38
We love our Argentine Tango (or maybe Tango Argentino) to be sure. Do not bastardize it, please. We want the real thing!
On the other hand, there is no one tango. Tango is a living expression of the people who play, sing, listen to and dance it. My tango is different from yours, or I sure hope so. Not too different, but a little different. That&amp;rsquo;s what makes it interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking on high heels</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/04/walking-on-high-heels/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2009 02:10:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/04/walking-on-high-heels/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;599&amp;rdquo; caption=&amp;ldquo;Cinderella discovers the risk involved in dancing too wildly while wearing glass shoes&amp;rdquo;][/caption]
Sure he was great, but don&#39;t forget that Ginger Rogers did everything he did, backwards... and in high heels. I had the pleasure of dancing with a woman in Buenos Aires who really knew how to operate her feet. She worked in television in her country, and was known as &amp;rsquo;the woman that knows how to walk on high heels&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>--A labour of love that needs more lovers</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/31/a-labour-of-love-that-needs-more-lovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2009 20:59:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/31/a-labour-of-love-that-needs-more-lovers/</guid>
      <description>by alexkerhead
Man of action. Man of ambition:
[Tango Vía](http://www.tangovia.org/), the organization this tango double-bass player from the famous [Orquesta El Arranque](http://www.orquestaelarranque.com.ar) presides, is up to nothing less than archiving every single tango recording in a super-high definition, archive-grade digital format, following strict technical processing that will drastically enhance the sound quality to make it an almost-perfect match to the pristine original.   [Buenos Aires Herald](http://buenosairesherald.com/PrintedEdition/View/4262)    Wonder how we could help them succeed with this project, arranging some sort of fund raiser or something?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From &#39;Band Union&#39; to bandoneón?</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/28/from-band-union-to-bandoneon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 14:54:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/28/from-band-union-to-bandoneon/</guid>
      <description>by Rüdis Fotos
What is the origin of the word bandoneón? Two competing theories exist. They both agree that the instrument is somehow named after the assumed inventor, Heinrich Band.
 The name &amp;lsquo;Band Union&amp;rsquo; was used by Heinrich Band and partners, and it got mispronounced and reinterpreted in Argentina as bandoneón.
 The name was invented by Band or others based on the naming of other instruments such as the accordion, Band + ion was transformed into bandonion, which in turn became bandoneón in Argentina.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comme il faut (the shoes)</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/26/comme-il-faut-the-shoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2009 03:24:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/26/comme-il-faut-the-shoes/</guid>
      <description>by Simba tango
What I do understand: People (men and women) are crazy about these shoes. They look (and are) extremely sharp, sexy, are light and well balanced. In other words perfect for dancing. An image of exclusivity also helps, although it has faded a little the last few years.
What I don&amp;rsquo;t understand: Why the competition hasn&amp;rsquo;t caught up. It surely can&amp;rsquo;t be that hard? After all, we are not talking rocket science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Resistance</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/26/the-resistance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2009 00:42:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/26/the-resistance/</guid>
      <description>by mirsasha
Tangocommuter is constructive and a man of action. Simba likes that. Following up on his own idea to distribute the homage to the milongueros, he has created a flyer, and I am happy to host it here at simbatango.com.
The challenge is, in his own words:
   (...) print out a lot of copies, with an attractive picture, perhaps that of the entrance to Sin Rumbo, so that it looks like a regular leaflet, to leave on the table at the entry of every milonga we go to…    Quietly sneaking in a little education in the milongas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valentina&#39;s Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/25/valentinas-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2009 03:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/25/valentinas-tango/</guid>
      <description>I got a tip about this film that I never heard about, starring rightly famous tango dancer Guillermina Quiroga, arguably one of the best female show dancers of our time. Browsing the reviews online, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really sure this was something for me, but as it was available on Netflix, I decided to give Guillermina a chance. This is what Netflix writes about the film:
Teetering on the edge of madness, striking dancer Valentina (Guillermina Quiriga) keeps the obsessive love she has for her husband, Eduardo (Jordi Caballero), in check by dancing the tango with him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cadencia</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/23/cadencia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2009 01:01:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/23/cadencia/</guid>
      <description>by Kanaka&amp;rsquo;s Paradise Life in Hawaii
If you have to ask, you will never know.   _Luis Armstrong when asked &#39;what is jazz?&#39;_    &amp;ndash;You see, that is not the way to make it &amp;lsquo;swing&amp;rsquo; in tango. I was looking out onto the group of people standing around us with question marks painted all over their faces. &amp;ndash;Well, I don&amp;rsquo;t know the right word, but the corresponding to swing in tango.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;New&#39; tango music on eMusic</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/21/new-tango-music-on-emusic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2009 02:48:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/21/new-tango-music-on-emusic/</guid>
      <description>by emilybean
Just as I was seriously considering quitting eMusic for good &amp;ndash; they deleted my plan, essentially making it more expensive, after I forgot using my credits in time, they just added a load of tango albums, making it somewhat tempting to stay a while longer anyways. Several of the &amp;lsquo;Grandes del Tango&amp;rsquo; albums published by Lantower were recently added and also some others. They also changed it so you can buy an entire album for 12 credits, which works out well for tango albums often with 20+ songs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get that nice picture next to your comment</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/17/how-to-get-that-nice-picture-next-to-your-comment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2009 00:54:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/17/how-to-get-that-nice-picture-next-to-your-comment/</guid>
      <description>by Daniel Semper
Some weeks ago, I got a question from another blog how I got the picture next to my comment on their site. It is really easy, all you have to do is to sign up for free at gravatar, upload your photo, and it will appear next to your comments on a wide range of sites, including most blogs powered by Wordpress (like this is). From the gravatar site:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homenaje a los milongueros</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/16/homenaje-a-los-milongueros/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2009 02:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/16/homenaje-a-los-milongueros/</guid>
      <description>by Simba tango
As you enter the cathedral of tango, the milonga Sin Rumbo, among the things hanging on the wall is this piece written by Marisa Galindo as a homage to the milongueros. It may serve as guiding principles or ideals for all tango dancers:
Los milongueros&amp;hellip;  son quienes saben hacer la ronda
 son quienes un oido musical increible
 son los que conocen cada orquesta y a sus cantores y a veces cantan despacito al oído.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>El Celulareo</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/11/el-celulareo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2009 19:38:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/11/el-celulareo/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_577&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;539&amp;rdquo; caption=&amp;ldquo;El Celulareo?&amp;rdquo;][/caption]
Based on the recent discussion on mobile phones in the milongas. This is the cartoon I mentioned, from B.A. Tango No 198.
&#34;It is astounding Brown. The mobile phone has invaded even the milongas.&#34; &#34;Shall we dance, Rosita?&#34; &#34;Yes, José!&#34; &#34;I&#39;ll finish my coffee and we&#39;ll dance.&#34; &#34;I&#39;ll be waiting for you, Adriana&#34; PS: You can subscribe to B.A. Tango by email by sending an email to abatango@yahoo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to walk</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/11/learning-to-walk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2009 13:15:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/11/learning-to-walk/</guid>
      <description>by Café du Monde
After spending a lot of time relearning how to walk, and teaching others to do the same, it is refreshing to watch a (very) young man learning to walk, in fact learning basically everything.
Following him from being unable to hold his own head, through rolling around and sitting up, getting up by means of whatever furniture or grown up legs are in his proximity is fascinating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nueve de julio</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/09/nueve-de-julio/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2009 05:01:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/09/nueve-de-julio/</guid>
      <description>  by Simba tango
Happy independence day, Argentina!
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technological advances in tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/09/technological-advances-in-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2009 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/09/technological-advances-in-tango/</guid>
      <description>by carrotcreative
I have to say I feel a bit like an oldie, writing this, but I am kind of old-school when it comes to tango, so I guess that&amp;rsquo;s ok..
I can&amp;rsquo;t help but notice how many things have changed since I first started with tango. Not the dance itself, but things around it. Technological changes that the newcomers in tango seem to take for granted, were simply not available only a few years back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>La Cumparsita</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/05/la-cumparsita/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2009 13:27:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/05/la-cumparsita/</guid>
      <description>by Simba tango
Niño Bien has always been one of my favorite milongas, and when I found the picture I used for illustration of my post on organizing a milonga, I was reminded that, unlike the photographer, I have never been there early, before the milonga really starts. For some reason, we always arrive late..
&amp;hellip;and possibly stay late. Although not often so late as to hear the dj put on La Cumparsita, the tango often used to round off the night at Buenos Aires milongas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great tango shorts</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/25/great-tango-shorts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2009 00:58:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/25/great-tango-shorts/</guid>
      <description>None of these are exactly new, but Tanghi Argentini just became available on youtube about a week ago, thanks a lot to Janis for the tip! Nominated for the Academy Awards 2008 for best live action short:
  And this animated one is not so light hearted, but no less romantic:
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango Uruguayo</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/23/tango-uruguayo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2009 02:41:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/23/tango-uruguayo/</guid>
      <description>Apropos good neighbours, the Argentines are apparently constantly quarreling with the Uruguayans about things tango related. Given that La cumparsita was composed by an Uruguayan and the birth place of Gardel is still a matter of discussion.
So here is an example of the excellent tango uruguayo, presented by the eminent Walter and Waldo. Hilarious.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Día del padre/Father&#39;s Day</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/21/dia-del-padrefathers-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2009 18:14:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/21/dia-del-padrefathers-day/</guid>
      <description>Look what Simba got for Father&amp;rsquo;s Day! Guess which is now the favourite book for the night-time reading? Even beats That&amp;rsquo;s not my Dinosaur. The daddy frog and the froglet seems to be my son&amp;rsquo;s favourite part of this book, though.
The book is by Anne Gutman and Georg Hallensleben, published by chronicle books.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nice film tangos</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/20/nice-film-tangos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2009 20:44:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/20/nice-film-tangos/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;600&amp;rdquo; caption=&amp;ldquo;From Happy Together&amp;rdquo;][/caption]
Fortunately, tango is not always portrayed as completely kitsch in films. So I found that a handful of very nice films, with equally nice tango mandated a post of its own. These are all highly recommended, tango or not.
First Happy together by Wong Kar-Wai. He is actually one of my favourite directors, and uses tango as one way to tell us about the relationship and love between two people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>El otro camino</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/19/el-otro-camino/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2009 02:50:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/19/el-otro-camino/</guid>
      <description>by i_gallagher
Una vez, tocando con una pequeña orquesta en la escuela de música popular -- eran estudiantes; yo me sentí, tocando con ellos, me sentí cómodo. Pero físicamente cómodo, como cuando uno se siente con la ropa de entrecasa. Y dije: &#34;¿Que me pasa? Y de pronto, la orquesta estaba tocando, esa orquesta de la escuela en un concierto y salen a bailar algunas personas. Y yo ví eso y dije: &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why the Chileans love tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/16/why-the-chileans-love-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 23:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/16/why-the-chileans-love-tango/</guid>
      <description>by f _ d a y
--Do you know why the Chileans love tango? I have made a couple of Chilean friends lately, and that means opportunities to practice my castellano. In all countries, the residents make jokes about their neighbours, and one of my new friends told me this one.
Another invited us to his asado (or bbq as they say here), and kept insisting on me saying** **tu, not vos like in Argentina.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archive</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/archive/archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2009 01:28:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/archive/archive/</guid>
      <description>[smart_archives]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to organize a Milonga</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/07/how-to-organize-a-milonga/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2009 19:20:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/07/how-to-organize-a-milonga/</guid>
      <description>by Chris and Sue
Starting a milonga is easy, right? You just need a place to dance, put some music on, and there you go&amp;hellip;
&amp;hellip;well not exactly. There are lots of small and not so small details that work together to create a good environment for social dancing. Based on my experience as organizer of both unsuccessful events and much more successful events and experience from various milongas and practicas over the world, I attempt to gather some advice on how to approximate the authentic milonga in your own community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cristhian Sosa &amp; Lida Montovani</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/04/cristhian-sosa-lida-montovani/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2009 01:48:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/04/cristhian-sosa-lida-montovani/</guid>
      <description>Wow! First place both in milonga and vals! I am impressed, but not surprised. They were in a different class entirely as far as I could judge from the videos posted over at 2xtango.
Felicitaciones!
Here they are performing at La Viruta. A milonga and a vals, of course.
    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anniversary</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/01/anniversary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 05:01:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/01/anniversary/</guid>
      <description>by smcgee
One year of simbatango.com Yay!
I checked the stats for what would be the most popular regular posts, and they appear to be:
 Rose in mouth
 Alejandro Hermida &amp;amp; Maria Jose Grattarola
 Tango film club
 On circulation
 Entering the milonga
  At feedburner, keeping track of my subscribers (thanks to all of you for reading!) the top five are:
 Competition</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eating the marshmellow</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/27/eating-the-marshmellow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 23:41:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/27/eating-the-marshmellow/</guid>
      <description>by Sarah Marafi (мυƒƒιησσн™)
I just read a very interesting article in the New Yorker about research on people&amp;rsquo;s ability to deter satisfaction, and how it could be a character treat determined very early. The researchers performed an experiment where children were given the choice of eating a marshmellow now, or wait fifteen minutes, waiting in front of the marshmellows, and get two marshmellows. Some kids were able to find ways of distracting themselves, earning the extra marshmellow in the end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango in popular culture</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/24/tango-in-popular-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2009 20:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/24/tango-in-popular-culture/</guid>
      <description>There is something about the word tango that seems to have a power in itself. Everybody seems to share the idea that tango is something special. Tango&amp;rsquo;s strong image in the public conscience is not quite the same as we tango addicts have, as we actually know the authentic tango culture and (I suppose) think of it when we hear the word.
To a large degree, the image the general public has of tango is imposed from the depiction of tango in popular culture, and movies in particular.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ROOOAAAAAAAAARRR!!!</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/24/roooaaaaaaaaarrr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2009 01:26:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/24/roooaaaaaaaaarrr/</guid>
      <description>by Tambako the Jaguar
Simba.. is trapped in a cage. Yes, he has youtube, he has his music collection. But something is missing. Grrrrrrr.
Will someone please take Simba for a walk. A Di Sarli walk. Or if that&amp;rsquo;s not possible, maybe some comforting words&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A morir</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/19/a-morir/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2009 01:24:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/19/a-morir/</guid>
      <description>by Xanboozled
   _--When a man walks nicely, the woman dies in his embrace._   --_When a man walks badly, the woman wants to die._ HT: yy</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sport and Culture</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/15/sport-and-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2009 13:02:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/15/sport-and-culture/</guid>
      <description>by Wigwam Jones
People often think of ballroom dancing when they hear I dance tango. Assuming I participate in competitions. And we would not want anybody to think that, would we?
It appears absurd to me, but it occurred to me the other day that they assume dancing is about sports. Which it is obviously not. It is all about culture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Necessary</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/14/necessary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2009 01:13:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/14/necessary/</guid>
      <description>by OpenThreads
Breaking the dance of tango down to its smallest parts is a popular exercise. Why stop at forward-side-back-steps? What it really comes down to is one simple concept. If you can do it, you can tango. Or at least you need to be able to do it to dance it.
Standing on one leg.
For a week-end class, we had one student with some condition that made it impossible for her to stand on one leg.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breathtaking</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/12/breathtaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 20:04:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/12/breathtaking/</guid>
      <description>I was so excited to see how it worked out with Stella and Javier on their tour this year. And this is just soooo beautiful! My piano teacher used to tell me when I practiced the hard parts: don&amp;rsquo;t forget breathing! This left me breathless, so dear reader, unless you can keep your breath for three minutes: don&amp;rsquo;t forget breathing!
  HT: nyctango</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The illusion of effortlessness requires a great effort indeed</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/11/the-illusion-of-effortlessness-requires-a-great-effort-indeed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2009 14:34:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/11/the-illusion-of-effortlessness-requires-a-great-effort-indeed/</guid>
      <description>by mjzitek
Elegance. You know it when you see it, but it can be hard to point your finger at exactly what it is that makes a couple elegant.
Effortlessness. Natural movement. Simple, clean and concise. No wasted energy.
It doesn&amp;rsquo;t come easy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bright side</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/11/bright-side/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2009 02:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/11/bright-side/</guid>
      <description>by renatela
It occured to me, that the topic of whom we dance with stirs up a lot of negative feelings. Or rather, with whom we do not dance. We are all concerned about being rejected, having someone not ask us to dance, or saying no when we ask (using the cabeceo, of course!).
A milonga is a place to enjoy ourselves, and everybody should dance with whoever they want to dance with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On circulation</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/11/on-circulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2009 00:57:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/11/on-circulation/</guid>
      <description>by pdcawley
Ms Hedgehog is researching the dynamics of flow in the ronda, comparing with traffic and pondering about the importance of song length.
While song length can probably have some influence, I believe other factors are much more significant. And it is kind of hard to perform real experiments, even though she deserves credit for the attempt.
According to Jorge Dispari, the flow on the dance floors of Buenos Aires used to be much better than today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The dual nature of tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/04/the-dual-nature-of-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2009 02:49:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/04/the-dual-nature-of-tango/</guid>
      <description>by airpark
I often wonder why tango is so attractive, why I (and others with me) got so obsessed with it. Why we never tire of it.
In part, I think it has to do with the infinite depth that can be found within it, and part of the source of this I believe is the dual nature of tango, or its apparent paradoxes. Making it difficult to explain or describe what tango is and isn&amp;rsquo;t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Film search</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/03/film-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2009 17:34:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/03/film-search/</guid>
      <description>by?Auntie P
Even after gathering quite a collection of tango movies, there are always some missing. Some are not available commercially, and that makes it hard. If anyone knows how to get any of these, I would be happy to know!
 Naked tango
 Flop (featuring Miguel Angel Zotto &amp;amp; Milena Plebs)
 Sur
 Tangos, exilio de Gardel
  Thanks to tango commuter for making me aware of the last two.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Luna de Avellaneda</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/03/luna-de-avellaneda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2009 13:05:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/03/luna-de-avellaneda/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;460&amp;rdquo; caption=&amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;Castillo&amp;rdquo; singing at club &amp;ldquo;Luna de Avellaneda&amp;rdquo;&amp;ldquo;][/caption]
Speaking of tango films, there are several films where tango is not a main theme, but with some interesting tango scenes. The film Luna de Avellaneda is quite nice, and stands out in that respect. For tango lovers, the opening scene is not to be missed, as it reconstructs the grand party of a community milonga in the golden age of tango.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stuff without the stuff</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/04/27/stuff-without-the-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 01:11:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/04/27/stuff-without-the-stuff/</guid>
      <description>by?Simba tango
There was a discussion on the tango dj mailing list a while ago about people wanting &amp;ldquo;stuff without the stuff&amp;rdquo;. In other words, tango (dance) without tango (music). An oxymoron, one would think.
Stephen Brown put it so well with his little story:
   A number of years ago, I was in a coffee shop that offered coffee prepared many different ways. One of the ways was decaffeinated coffee with artificial sweetener and artificial cream.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silencio</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/04/25/silencio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2009 13:19:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/04/25/silencio/</guid>
      <description>by entropiK
El que hace bien el silencio, hace bien el tango (Who plays the silence well, plays the tango well)   Osvaldo Requena      My favorite quote from the outstanding Café de los Maestros documentary. I just wanted to watch it all over again as soon as it was finished. ¡Que sentimiento! ¡Que pasión!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 x Squeezebox</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/04/25/3-x-squeezebox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2009 12:50:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/04/25/3-x-squeezebox/</guid>
      <description>by Simba tango
Maybe it it time to go back to Debian. Then I could listen to Aníbal playing the squeezebox (by Arnold), streamed to my squeezebox (by Slim Devices/Logitech) from my squeezebox (running Debian).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango Film Club</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/04/19/tango-film-club/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2009 15:26:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/04/19/tango-film-club/</guid>
      <description>by atomicjeep
I was planning to write a separate post for each of those, but I never seem to find the time&amp;hellip; The recent posts by tangocommuter prompted me to write up this list of my favorite tango films. I never was all that interestesd in instructional videos, but films about the culture I find fascinating. In our small community we arranged public showings in an informal tango film club to make these gems available to the rest of the community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mateando</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/04/06/mateando/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2009 23:19:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/04/06/mateando/</guid>
      <description>by Simba tango
First things first. Got to get the essensials in place. Like espresso cups and what&amp;rsquo;s needed for preparing mate.
And &amp;ndash; apparently, tea is the new coffee. But I think they forgot to count mate, both the new tea **and **coffee ;-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lluvia de abril</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/04/06/lluvia-de-abril/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2009 02:14:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/04/06/lluvia-de-abril/</guid>
      <description>by Simba tango
  by Simba tango
Spring is coming to the northern hemisphere, and outside our window, the magnolia is just about to burst into bloom. We had a wonderful walk in the April rain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nice floor</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/04/05/nice-floor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2009 01:09:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/04/05/nice-floor/</guid>
      <description>by Simba tango
Simba found a new cage. It has the most lovely hardwood floor. Parquet. Yum-ba! We&amp;rsquo;ll see how much milongas there will be in the new town, but Simba already started patrolling the new territory with enrosques and paradas thrown in here and there. And it is smooooth! So at least some private dancing inside the cave, while guarding the offspring.
I must admit floors mean a lot more to me after dancing tango for a while than they did before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EE.UU.</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/03/20/eeuu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2009 23:07:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/03/20/eeuu/</guid>
      <description>by ladybugbkt
Simba is moving, and so is simbatango.com. Please bear over with us if there is a period of radio silence.
Edit: Moved to new server, will have to fix rest of configuration later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Death of the Prodigy dancer</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/03/16/death-of-the-prodigy-dancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2009 21:40:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/03/16/death-of-the-prodigy-dancer/</guid>
      <description>by Mickal
Tango is full of nostalgia, even sentimentality. We long for the times that were. Even sentimentality was better in the 40s. How can it be for the real milongueros, who were young in that time?
Not to say it is the same, but the thought struck me the other day. I just bought the new Prodigy album, playing it loud and dancing around the kitchen. (I do this a lot, usually to tango music these days) This was the music of my youth, when we went out to party, that was the best.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The paradox of style</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/03/12/the-paradox-of-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2009 20:03:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/03/12/the-paradox-of-style/</guid>
      <description>We strive to stand out with our own style. Distinctive. Not being part of the masses. Not so easy. Photos from Exactitudes by Ari Versluis and Ellie Uyttenbroek.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Song numbers</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/03/11/song-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2009 20:12:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/03/11/song-numbers/</guid>
      <description>by Stewf
Some songs are more popular than others, and some are harder to find than others. Sometimes you have to buy an entire disc full of songs you already have to get just that song. So my library of tango music has a lot of duplicates. And more, is there a word like elevenicates?
So the most popular songs are probably available on a lot of records, I figured, and out of curiosity, I checked which were the most popular in my collection, this is for all songs that I have the recording date (from tango.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My name is Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/03/10/my-name-is-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2009 19:54:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/03/10/my-name-is-tango/</guid>
      <description>by Alex Basnett
The neverending discussions of styles in tango often leave me baffled, as the idea that one is to choose one of a small number of predefined styles seems perpendicular to my idea of tango. Which is it going to be? Traditional or modern? We have to remember that tango is a quite modern dance &amp;ndash; it always was.
And no book deals better with the issue of style and the clash of modern and traditional than My name is red by Orhan Pamuk, the author was awarded the Nobel price of literature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Up and down</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/03/02/up-and-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2009 15:29:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/03/02/up-and-down/</guid>
      <description>by Scott Ableman
-Have you been practicing tango nuevo? Guilty as charged.
He knew immediately. And it was not because I used an open embrace, we were practicing milonga, using a very confined embrace.
I often wonder why people get so hang up on the somewhat arbitrary distinction between open and close embrace (all teachers, both &amp;ldquo;nuevo&amp;rdquo; and others usually promote very close embrace at times, but for some figures it is not possible to maintain the closest embrace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Competition</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/03/01/competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 09:04:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/03/01/competition/</guid>
      <description>by Alaz-
For some reason, people often assume I dance competitions when they hear I&amp;rsquo;m a tango dancer. Not so, I tell them. The only competition is to get to dance with the best dancers.
And while I still believe that to be true to some extent, a friend (who is an excellent dancer himself), put me on a better track. Why is it so important to dance with the &amp;ldquo;best&amp;rdquo;, he asked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Color -- like no other</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/26/color-like-no-other/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2009 21:32:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/26/color-like-no-other/</guid>
      <description>The world is not black and white, there are grays in between&amp;hellip; it is often said when some take a clear position in a debate. And they do have a point of course. But they also sometimes miss the point entirely.
Tango is not gray, it is full of colour! You just have to open your eyes and take them in.
I am thinking of the &amp;ldquo;nuevo&amp;rdquo; versus &amp;ldquo;traditional&amp;rdquo; debate, of course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Super super dulce...</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/24/super-super-dulce/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2009 20:24:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/24/super-super-dulce/</guid>
      <description>httpv://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VFx02G3kg9E
The Argentines are crazy about sweets, and so will you be after staying there for a while. Take care, the alfajores de Havanna are dangerously good. The cones are for the conoisseurs&amp;hellip;
httpv://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QT6JHS5lgQM
And while you are relaxing before going out for the milongas, they got a tv show just for making sweets and desserts, called super dulce. I did not find it on youtube, the theme song is hilarious, and you can find a short sample on the super dulce home page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Urban dance</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/24/urban-dance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2009 20:09:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/24/urban-dance/</guid>
      <description>by lrargerich
Tango is and always was a very urban culture. The dance even more so. Sometimes visitors to Buenos Aires that are tango dancers somehow expect everybody they meet to be a dancer, and taxi drivers to know all the milongas by name.
Not so.
Even in Buenos Aires, tango dancing is very much a niche activity, and the world of the milongas is very small even in the great city with millions of inhabitants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Body parts</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/22/body-parts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2009 20:02:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/22/body-parts/</guid>
      <description>by Balakov
Privates can be tough. Very useful, but tough.
On our first trip to Buenos Aires, my wife and I took privates with Julio &amp;amp; Corina, and we worked on the basics. Of course. We learnt a lot, but it was so much to think about. So much we did wrong. So much to fix.
For my own sake, it felt like they deconstructed my whole body, just to leave the parts on the floor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>White powder vs. Tango Argentino</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/21/white-powder-vs-tango-argentino/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2009 14:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/21/white-powder-vs-tango-argentino/</guid>
      <description>Powder Mountain Perspective from Ian Provo on Vimeo.
Common (could be pro or con, depending&amp;hellip;):
 Balance
 Rhythm
 Dissociation
 Improvisation
 Flow
 Max 12 min. rush
 Addictive
  Skiing pros  Fresh air
 Beautiful mountains
 Keeps you in shape
  Skiing cons  Avalanches
 Weather dependent
 Cold, dress accordingly
 Tough ascents
 Heavy on the knees
 Practical clothing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alejandro Hermida &amp; Maria Jose Grattarola</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/15/alejandro-hermida-maria-jose-grattarola/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2009 18:40:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/15/alejandro-hermida-maria-jose-grattarola/</guid>
      <description>httpv://www.youtube.com/watch?v=utwv5HDehOU
httpv://www.youtube.com/watch?v=04TYG1TlwS8
Alejandro Hermida (Campeon de milonga, 2007) &amp;amp; Maria Jose Grattarola on their first European tour. Muy lindo! Felicitaciones!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rose in mouth</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/13/rose-in-mouth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2009 22:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/13/rose-in-mouth/</guid>
      <description>by alyssathiele
The tango cliché of dancing with a rose in the mouth is quite fascinating. It is everywhere, and everybody doing argentine tango wants absolutely nothing to do with it. But where does it come from?
I have often seen it associated with the silent movie star Rudolph Valentino, and suggested that it first appeared in the movie Four Horsemen of the Apocalypse (1921). So being curious, I had to check this out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/12/evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2009 08:51:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/12/evolution/</guid>
      <description>by Kaptain Kobold
It&amp;rsquo;s the year of Darwin this year. In a radio show, different scientists were discussing Darwin&amp;rsquo;s impact on their fields. The art historian made a point out of the fact that after Darwin, people no longer expected the evolution to be linear, or directed towards a specific goal. Always improving. It became clear that modern art would change, take different forms. The direction of change would be an other matter entirely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classic Couples: Geraldine &amp; Javier</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/10/classic-couples-geraldine-javier/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2009 09:44:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/10/classic-couples-geraldine-javier/</guid>
      <description>         </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No-one will talk to you at parties</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/06/no-one-will-talk-to-you-at-parties/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2009 10:03:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/06/no-one-will-talk-to-you-at-parties/</guid>
      <description>by Thomas Hawk
Being serious about tango doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you have to take yourself too seriously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empty movement</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/04/empty-movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2009 20:43:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/04/empty-movement/</guid>
      <description>by bass_nroll
As you probably know, tango is not merely a dance. Among other things, the dance is also a language. It is not like a language, because the different movements have different meanings, which can be used for actual communication. It is not a metaphor. However, when people copy movements without realizing the underlying meaning, the result is movements with no meaning. Empty movement.
Or even worse, you may be saying something without knowing it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last.fm cleaning up</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/29/lastfm-cleaning-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2009 21:45:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/29/lastfm-cleaning-up/</guid>
      <description>by aldask
Last.fm are finally cleaning up their metadata, or at least they have started. If you are on last.fm, why don&amp;rsquo;t you help out by voting for Rodolpho Biagi to redirect to Rodolfo Biagi? (follow the link to faulty spelling, vote at the bottom right). And while you are at it, if you are also a tango dj, why don&amp;rsquo;t join the group tangodj?
Information on tango music has gotten better lately, and a sample from top Pugliese tracks seems reasonable:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More on reinvention</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/28/more-on-reinvention/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2009 21:01:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/28/more-on-reinvention/</guid>
      <description>by oschene
After discussing my short post on reinvention in the comments, I decided to write a new post discussing the matter. Here is the quote again:
&#34;Those who don&#39;t understand [Tango] are condemned to reinvent it, poorly.&#34;   – Henry Spencer (about Unix)      First I thought of it as a warning against setting out to reinvent or improve something that you do not fully understand, as it will be futile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marathon</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/27/marathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2009 19:14:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/27/marathon/</guid>
      <description>by darkmatter
So what&amp;rsquo;s with this marathon thing that seems to be spreading across Europe? I never found anything positive about marathons, running and sweating for hours on asphalt with no break and being totally destroyed afterwards?
Of course, people may dance as they like. Myself, I prefer a nice milonga, champagne at the table, nice and clean clothes, nice and calm. Having a ball. Walking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Un beso...</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/26/un-beso/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2009 17:33:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/26/un-beso/</guid>
      <description>by Kevin Steele
Buenos Aires is not like home. And when in Rome, drive like the Romans&amp;hellip;
And the Argentines kiss when they meet. Better get used to it.
(...) would lean over, ready to commit the act that, I thought, was reserved only for girlfriends and, on occasion, family. This guy used a few months it seems, but has written a really entertaining account of the argentinian kissing habits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The code</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/25/the-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2009 10:56:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/25/the-code/</guid>
      <description>by anthonygrimley
It can be difficult to learn tango. In addition to learning to know the music, leading and following and the basic vocabulary, there are the rules. So many rules to remember. Or codigos, as some prefer to call them. Codigos de la milonga.
And there are some that think way too much attention devoted to these &amp;ldquo;rules&amp;rdquo;. Ancient rules from Buenos Aires, we can manage very well without them, thankyouverymuch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reinvention</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/16/reinvention/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2009 15:31:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/16/reinvention/</guid>
      <description>by pallotron
&#34;Those who don&#39;t understand [Tango] are condemned to reinvent it, poorly.&#34;   – Henry Spencer (about Unix)    I believe Miguel Angel Zotto to have said something along the same lines, that if you do not understand tango, how can you possibly improve it? I can&amp;rsquo;t seem to find the reference, though.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classic Couples: Miguel Angel Zotto &amp; Milena Plebs</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/15/classic-couples-miguel-angel-zotto-milena-plebs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2009 10:19:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/15/classic-couples-miguel-angel-zotto-milena-plebs/</guid>
      <description>httpvh://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=jSFkVrTJ_Ig
httpvh://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=pL9r4NURca0
httpvh://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=hgcRo0m1Yn8
[](http://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=hgcRo0m1Yn8)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sabor a tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/12/sabor-a-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2009 20:22:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/12/sabor-a-tango/</guid>
      <description>by Simba tango
It is common to say that we taste four diffent tastes: sweet, salt, bitter and sour. Combinations of these make up all other tastes. Sounds familiar? You may be guessing what I&amp;rsquo;m getting at&amp;hellip;
The experience of taste, or should I say the experience of a meal, which we humans make for the pure pleasure of enjoying the different tastes and combinations, consists of a lot more than these four basic tastes (some also include umami, but that&amp;rsquo;s not the point).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>La familia dell Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/11/la-familia-dell-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2009 22:03:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/11/la-familia-dell-tango/</guid>
      <description>While tidying up the home office, I came over tha 2004 calendar of La familia dell Tango, by Gustavo Reinoso. Which is very cool. I have looked around for cartoonish drawings of tango that might be suitable for using on flyers etc, and this is the best I have seen so far.
Very little information available on the web, it seems, but I found a little at www.ideasamedida.com/ and at www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 40</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/11/top-40/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2009 11:36:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/11/top-40/</guid>
      <description>by Ger Audrey
I loved the think top 40 part of Alex&amp;rsquo; rant after attending a festival. The dj should think hits, hits and more hits to please the dancers. And maybe throw in a little surprise. Not all the time, but we need a little variation. But in general, play the good stuff. People are not interested in you digging up some weird music that you think maybe will work for tango.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The real stuff</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/10/the-real-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2009 15:12:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/10/the-real-stuff/</guid>
      <description>by oed
Ah -- you dance **real** milonga (echte Milonga). After struggling with my milonga for years, this was the ultimate sign I was finally getting somewhere. And one of my favorite compliments ever. I got a tip from the Argentine host to ask this woman to dance, he thought I should dance with someone good. So I did. And was not disappointed. Starting almost right out with a milonga, which would have terrified me only a year earlier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Humbleness</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/09/humbleness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2009 20:16:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/09/humbleness/</guid>
      <description>by herval
I just heard this story, and found it hilarious, about a dancer complaining to the dj. The conversation went something like this:
-Ur music sux, man! -Allriiiight... which song would you like me to play? -! -Just name one song you would like me to play... -!! -Sooo... you don&#39;t actually know any songs, do you... Needless to say; before complaing, you ought to know what you are talking about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volume adjustments for tango music</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/07/volume-adjustments-for-tango-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2009 13:55:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/07/volume-adjustments-for-tango-music/</guid>
      <description>There was some discussion on the tangodj mailing list about the use of Replay Gain for tango music. I have used it for several years, and found it to be immensely useful. As you can see from the histogram above, the loudness of cd releases varies a lot, and Replay Gain makes automatic adjustments to make the loundess more or less the same. It does a lot better than I do, that&amp;rsquo;s for sure, and frees up time for the more interesting parts of the djing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keine komische Musik</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/05/keine-komische-musik/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2009 22:22:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/05/keine-komische-musik/</guid>
      <description>by emurray
I was warned once in a milonga in Central Europe: We have to dance **now, **this is milonga, he won&amp;rsquo;t play much of it. Later there will only be _komische Musik _(comical music).
This is the best excuse I have ever heard for asking someone (me) to dance! And she was right. The dj had no clue whatsoever and played a lot of &amp;ndash; well, komische Musik.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy New Year!</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/01/happy-new-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 13:47:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/01/happy-new-year/</guid>
      <description>by basibanget
Ready for a new year of tango? Remember that if you want to improve, there is no secret, all you have to do is to follow three simple steps:
 Learn from the best
 Practice (a lot)
 Listen to lots of music
  Nobody ever said it was gonna be easy ;-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cristhian Sosa &amp; Samantha Dispari</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/30/cristhian-sosa-samantha-dispari/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2008 12:11:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/30/cristhian-sosa-samantha-dispari/</guid>
      <description>At last at youtube: Cristhian Sosa &amp;amp; Samantha Dispari:
httpvh://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=FDda9gi_jmk&amp;amp;feature=related
httpvh://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=_iXqfsmicXs&amp;amp;feature=related
httpvh://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=_rQqPGDH1II&amp;amp;feature=related</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tagging with MusicBrainz Picard</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/tagging-with-musicbrainz-picard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2008 22:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/tagging-with-musicbrainz-picard/</guid>
      <description>As your tango collection grows, the need to get more accurate and consistant meta information increases. To tag your music from an online database greatly reduces your effort.
I prefer using MusicBrainz Picard, as it provides data for my non-tango music as well. The tango.info database provides a wealth of information and a guide for masstagging.
To combine MusicBrainz Picard with genre and recording dates from tango.info, you can use these plugins for MusicBrainz Picard:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ripping CDs for the tangoDJ</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/ripping-cds-for-the-tangodj/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2008 21:48:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/ripping-cds-for-the-tangodj/</guid>
      <description>Windows For Windows, I would recommend dbPoweramp, foobar2000 or EAC. Both support AccurateRip, which makes sure your rip is good (provided it already exists in the database). A new and interesting project is CUETools which also supports error correction if the disc is in their database (unfortunately not so likely with most tango cds at this time).
Both CUETools and foobar2000 support checking previously ripped tracks against the AccurateRip database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TangoDJ</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/tangodj/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2008 20:58:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/tangodj/</guid>
      <description>Useful online resources for the tangoDJ:
Discussion list TangoDJ mailing list
About tango music Stephen Brown&amp;rsquo;s pages about tango music
Michael Lavocha&amp;rsquo;s guide to tango music
About audio formats Hydrogenadio
Where to buy tango music Tango store (Zival&amp;rsquo;s)
Tango music at emusic</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foobar2000 for the TangoDJ</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/foobar2000-for-the-tangodj/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2008 20:57:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/foobar2000-for-the-tangodj/</guid>
      <description>About Foobar2000 Foobar2000 is a lightweight audio player that is excellent for the tangodj on Windows. Free as in beer and quite usable out of the box, the possibilities for customizations are endless.
Prelistening For prelistening, install two instances of the player, and configure one for each sound device. If the sound from the internal sound card is good (which is often the case with recent laptops), you can use a usb headset, which is cheaper than buying an extra soundcard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fb2k for the tangoDJ</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/26/fb2k-for-the-tangodj/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2008 20:57:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/26/fb2k-for-the-tangodj/</guid>
      <description>by duncan Foobar2000 just came out in version 0.9.6, making it a lot easier to configure for tangodjing purposes. I have written a short guide on how to configure fb2k for the tangoDJ. I will update the main article with new information, and suggestions for improvements are most welcome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tangueros del Norte: Inspiración</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/24/tangueros-del-norte-inspiracion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2008 00:21:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/24/tangueros-del-norte-inspiracion/</guid>
      <description>Imagine a tango orchestra of really young and talented musicians, forming a small orquesta típica with members ranging from the age of 10-14. Three bandoneóns, three violins, double bass and piano. Playing tango, and not only Piazzolla. Playing together for several years to get the music under their skin. Where would this happen if not in Buenos Aires?
In Norway! In a cold small town in the middle of nowhere, or in the heart of Norway as some would say.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chasing cucarachas</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/20/chasing-cucarachas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2008 16:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/20/chasing-cucarachas/</guid>
      <description>by seretuaccidente
Speaking of lack of finesse&amp;hellip;
What&amp;rsquo;s with the watching the floor all the time, checking the floor before each step, head moving from side to side, constantly, as if chasing cucarachas. I did not come up with this description myself, but it is very fitting, I think.
Whoever came up with this new &amp;lsquo;style&amp;rsquo; (or rather lack thereof)? Somebody near them should tell them that it looks ridiculous.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pas de finesse...</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/19/pas-de-finesse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2008 12:55:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/19/pas-de-finesse/</guid>
      <description>by Jayanth Sharma
Staying in Buenos Aires for a few months provided several eye-openers. One of the great revelations was concerning the logic of the dance, or rather the lack of it, and how this adds spice to the dance:
We were taking lessons with various teachers, with very different philosophies with respect to tango, how to dance it and how to learn it. Gustavo Naveira, the great master, dissected each step carefully, explaining exactly how and why and which steps were crossed and which were open etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Entering the milonga</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/17/entering-the-milonga/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2008 15:45:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/17/entering-the-milonga/</guid>
      <description>by Untitled blue
The moment or should I say process of entering a milonga is very special for me. I think savoring the moment is something very important in tango, and for me it starts at the moment I am standing outside the milonga entrance. There is a certain amount of expectation for the night even before, of course, but this is when I really start enjoying the sensation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boleos helados</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/15/boleos-helados/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2008 21:34:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/15/boleos-helados/</guid>
      <description>by Hettie McFarlane
Limerick&amp;rsquo;s post on boleos made me think of the concept of boleos helados, or frozen boleos. I went to a workshop with Chicho and Lucía a couple of years back, and while the frozen boleos were sort of fun, it ruins your boleo technique if you shape your boleos that way. Methinks.
The intrigueing thing about boleos is their free flowing unmanaged quality. Or as Limerick says:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classic Couples: Roberto &amp; Vanina</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/15/classic-couples-roberto-vanina/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2008 10:39:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/15/classic-couples-roberto-vanina/</guid>
      <description>httpvh://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=dxD2IMBWEww
httpvh://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=4cl-cFnbUYE
httpvh://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=JiWPtHZoH0c
httpv://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=YzL9xATtjYY</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Showing off</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/10/showing-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2008 22:12:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/10/showing-off/</guid>
      <description>by - mika -
Who hasn&amp;rsquo;t been tempted&amp;hellip;
&amp;hellip; to do some flashy moves when someone sitting next to the dance floor watches.
&amp;hellip; to show all the tricks of the trade when getting to dance with a really good dancer
&amp;hellip; to play some obscure gem from the record collection when djing
&amp;hellip; to play some music to be innovative
The problem is, it does not impress anyone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Popularity contest: dancers@youtube</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/07/popularity-contest-dancersyoutube/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2008 21:24:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/07/popularity-contest-dancersyoutube/</guid>
      <description>by strollerdos
Following up on the first popularity contest, I wanted to check how popular these dancers are on YouTube&amp;hellip; I used the 20 most popular from the google search numbers. Searching first for name and tango, then selecting the number of views from the most viewed video.
Here are the results: 1 

Julio Balmaceda 
520,941   2 

Juan Carlos Copes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Under pressure</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/06/under-pressure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2008 19:30:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/06/under-pressure/</guid>
      <description>by notinponce
Comparing tango with other dances, salsa for instance, some find the other dances so much fuller of life. Sparkling. Bubbling over of life and joy.
Tango is rarely bubbling over. It is more self contained. Directing the energy inwards. More like boiling under pressure. More intensity and energy, but perhaps less visible.
I remember so well one of my first times to a festival. As usual, people were going crazy on the dance floor, using brownian motion as the guiding principle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yes honey, but is it tango?</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/04/yes-honey-but-is-it-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2008 15:58:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/04/yes-honey-but-is-it-tango/</guid>
      <description>Roy Lichtenstein: Girl with Ribbon (1965)
There is always a lot of fuzz in the tango communities of the world about what is the right tango. And rightly so. There is good and there is bad tango.
But in the middle of these heated arguments, we need to remind ourselves of one thing. Tango culture is rich. There is a lot of diversity in tango. Tango is not only dance. It is also music for listening.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All you need to know about style</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/03/all-you-need-to-know-about-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2008 17:56:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/03/all-you-need-to-know-about-style/</guid>
      <description>by DCCXLIX
A lot can be said about styles in tango. More on that in later posts. All you need to know about styles is the following:
Traditionally, we make a distinction between social tango (tango salón) and performances (tango fantasía).
Tango salón In a milonga, good navigation and connection with your partner is very important, as is dancing with the rest of the dance floor, which in general means no high boleos, ganchos etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Popularity contest: dancers@google</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/30/popularity-contest-dancersgoogle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2008 22:48:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/30/popularity-contest-dancersgoogle/</guid>
      <description>by geckoam
Out of curiosity I started googling some more and less famous dancers, to compare popularity on the web. Some interesting results&amp;hellip;
Methodology: I simply searched for the complete name (exact phrase) as listed below and the word &amp;ldquo;tango&amp;rdquo; and made a note of the number of hits. Suggestions for improvements and important omissions are welcome. The ones best known by their first name or nickname are a bit tricky, but this is the result so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why we never tire of tango music</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/29/why-we-never-tire-of-tango-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2008 22:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/29/why-we-never-tire-of-tango-music/</guid>
      <description>by nadworks
Tango music for the non-argentine 21st century tango lover is often something of an acquired taste. At least for tango dancers. The recordings are old, the music sounds strange, we don&amp;rsquo;t understand the lyrics &amp;ndash; but we love the dance&amp;hellip;
After some time, we get more into the music, it all changes, and we become total fanáticos de tango, we can never get enough of the classics of tango music.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It can be fun, too!</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/28/it-can-be-fun-too/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2008 11:20:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/28/it-can-be-fun-too/</guid>
      <description>Just because tango can be deep and serious, doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean it can&amp;rsquo;t be a lot of fun, too.
I remember learning very early about the three musical genres: milonga was fun, tango serious and vals about love&amp;hellip;
&amp;hellip;so no coincidence that two out of three are milongas:
httpv://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=98CmUhcJWbwhttpv://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=98CmUhcJWbw
httpvh://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=97B2vGyZ6j0
httpvh://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=S-mkR-KoPts</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technique vs. Feeling</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/27/technique-vs-feeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2008 21:42:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/27/technique-vs-feeling/</guid>
      <description>by my hovercraft is full of eels
Which one is most important? Technique or dancing with feeling? I sometimes get the impression that tango dancers are divided in two camps, the technique camp and the feelings camp. The first emphasizes the technical matters of the dance, the latter paying solely attention to the feeling. As long as we can hug each other, all is well ;-) Both seemingly ignoring the other point of view completely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roxana y Sebastián</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/25/roxana-y-sebastian/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2008 22:01:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/25/roxana-y-sebastian/</guid>
      <description>I just found these videos with Roxana and Sebastián, aren&amp;rsquo;t they wonderful!
httpvh://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=Xi-ZUJ5c8Z4
httpvh://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=lpZo9jWGnLA</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The tyranny of novelty</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/23/the-tyranny-of-novelty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2008 22:02:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/23/the-tyranny-of-novelty/</guid>
      <description>by Jacob Bøtter
The man who has journeyed all over the world can&#39;t find any novelty in five thousand miles, for he finds only new things -- yet another novelty, the old routine of the forever new -- while his abstract concept of novelty got lost at sea after the second new thing he saw.   _The Book of Disquiet (171) by Fernando Pessoa_    As in fashion, people in dance seem always to be chasing the new black.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheek to cheek</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/22/cheek-to-cheek/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2008 17:47:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/22/cheek-to-cheek/</guid>
      <description>Heaven, I&#39;m in Heaven, And my heart beats so that I can hardly speak; And I seem to find the happiness I seek When we&#39;re out together dancing, cheek to cheek. Heaven, I&#39;m in Heaven, And the cares that hang around me thro&#39; the week Seem to vanish like a gambler&#39;s lucky streak When we&#39;re out together dancing, cheek to cheek. Oh! I love to climb a mountain, And to reach the highest peak, But it doesn&#39;t thrill me half as much As dancing cheek to cheek.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost there</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/21/almost-there/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2008 12:03:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/21/almost-there/</guid>
      <description>by patsun They say it takes 10 years learning to walk&amp;hellip; Almost there ;-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango magazines -- preparing for Buenos Aires</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/19/tango-magazines-preparing-for-buenos-aires/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2008 22:19:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/19/tango-magazines-preparing-for-buenos-aires/</guid>
      <description>Some of our students are going to Buenos Aires tomorrow. Oh the memories&amp;hellip;
I made sure they were equipped with the latest editions of El tangauta and B.A. Tango, giving a good overview over the happenings in November and December. They were always hard to get, even if they are given away for free, it could easily take a couple of weeks before we got hold of an issue. Now, they are available online, and one can prepare for the first week at home or on the plane down there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 Tangos -- Adios Buenos Aires</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/19/12-tangos-adios-buenos-aires/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2008 17:06:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/19/12-tangos-adios-buenos-aires/</guid>
      <description>The documentary 12 tangos was just released in international version on DVD. It is a documentary, and the Adios Buenos Aires part of the title is somehow more accurate with regards to the content of the film. If you are looking for the Buena Vista Social Club of tango, you will be disappointed. There are no interviews with musicians, and only a few of the oldtimers participate in the orchestra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waiting for the right moment</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/18/waiting-for-the-right-moment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2008 17:57:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/18/waiting-for-the-right-moment/</guid>
      <description>by just.Luc
   -I see a lot of men are not dancing. They can&#39;t manage to dance when the floor is so full of people.     -It may not be because of lack of ability. It may be because they enjoy the dance more when the floor is not packed and they can more around the floor in their dance. Maybe they are waiting for their favorite music.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I started DJing</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/17/how-i-started-djing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2008 15:44:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/17/how-i-started-djing/</guid>
      <description>by AllegaertMe
When I started dancing tango, the &amp;ldquo;milonga&amp;rdquo; was in a café where we basically heard the same double cd over and over and over. In general, everybody knew exactly what song came next and started humming on the next song before it started. Knowing the music is all good, but, well&amp;hellip;
-I guess I would start djing, was the dry comment from an American dancer we met in Bs As a few years ago when I told this story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shut up and listen! (II)</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/16/shut-up-and-listen-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2008 12:25:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/16/shut-up-and-listen-ii/</guid>
      <description>by Carol Esther
My previous post got me going on the habit that some dancers have of talking while dancing.
Just stop it, ok?
How can you possibly be listening to the music when you are talking at the same time? The conversation is going on in the dance, remember? And even if you somehow manage to do both at the same time, you are disturbing the others on the floor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shut up and listen!</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/16/shut-up-and-listen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2008 12:02:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/16/shut-up-and-listen/</guid>
      <description>by !borghetti
Johanna wonders about the negative connotations of &amp;ldquo;following&amp;rdquo;. There is nothing wrong with following, following is crucial to make the dance work, and that is no simple task. The problem is being assigned the role of simply following, being the &amp;ldquo;follow(er)&amp;rdquo;.
Or should I say reduced to follower.
Just as there is nothing wrong with listening, but being assigned the role of being the listener is somehow limiting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classic Couples: Gavito &amp; Duran</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/15/classic-couples-gavito-duran/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2008 14:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/15/classic-couples-gavito-duran/</guid>
      <description>[youtube]http://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=v246c8wP6_0[/youtube]
[youtube]http://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=0H6GvpWRNi8[/youtube]
[youtube]http://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=4_GlpLqfB_s[/youtube]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dancing is for fags and sissies...</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/14/dancing-is-for-fags-and-sissies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2008 14:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/14/dancing-is-for-fags-and-sissies/</guid>
      <description>Photo: zabara_tango@flickr, CC-licensed

Photo: Un Milonguero Mejicano@flickr, CC-licensed
&amp;ndash; while football is for real men: 
Photo: NaturalBlu@flickr, CC-licensed

Photo: NaturalBlu@flickr, CC-licensed</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Secret -- Don&#39;t tell anyone</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/11/the-secret-dont-tell-anyone/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2008 16:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/11/the-secret-dont-tell-anyone/</guid>
      <description>The main character is asked to prepare an omelet in the morning for his master, a Parisian intellectual. Feeling his cooking is underappreciated, he contemplates the intellectuals&amp;rsquo; missing reflection on his artistry in the kitchen. This is clearly about tango: (From Monique Truong&amp;rsquo;s The Book of Salt:)
Like children, gullible and full of wonder, they always ask, &#34;What is your secret?&#34; Do I look like a fool? I ask myself each time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gingerbread milonga</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/10/gingerbread-milonga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2008 16:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/10/gingerbread-milonga/</guid>
      <description>Some friends (also tango maniacs, of course) made this just before Christmas a couple of years ago. A really tasty milonga it was! Welcome to Club Grizelle!



I released the photos under a Creative Commons license, so feel free to use them for whatever non-commercial purpose you like :-) I appreciate a link and a comment if you find use for it.
Maybe they can be useful for invitations to your Christmas milonga?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nuevo tools, nuevo problems</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/09/nuevo-tools-nuevo-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2008 21:07:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/09/nuevo-tools-nuevo-problems/</guid>
      <description>Models can be very useful. By making a simplified version of the world that we are able to grasp, we may learn something about the world outside the model as well. This approach has proven very successful in a lot of areas, and is also applied to tango.
There is a danger associated with model building, as everyone working with them should know, and that is to mistake the model for reality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salón Canning</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/06/salon-canning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2008 23:08:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/06/salon-canning/</guid>
      <description>I realize that the guys at Movement invites movement are not afraid of provocation, but I think they suffer a tiny bit from a syndrome often associated with Gringos, shooting from the waist.
In their rant abot Canning, they fail to recognize a few important reasons Canning has such an important position. Aside from being one of the very best floors in the city (maybe the very best), it attracts many excellent dancers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the eye of the beholder</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/06/in-the-eye-of-the-beholder/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2008 17:31:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/06/in-the-eye-of-the-beholder/</guid>
      <description>Isn&amp;rsquo;t it funny how we see so different things, even when watching the exact same event?

I remember seeing containers all over the place while we were renovating our appartment, a friend who is an architect and carpenter seemed to literally see through the walls in the house before we bought it. A trained art expert will instantly recognize the work of an artist, an analyst will see through the endless rows of numbers in a spreadsheet&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Follow the leader?</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/03/follow-the-leader/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2008 21:15:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/03/follow-the-leader/</guid>
      <description>Johanna&amp;rsquo;s comment and her subsequent post on leads and follows inspired me to write an entire post in addition to the comment in her blog. In her post (and follow-up) she argues why you would want to use the terms lead and follow for the two dancers in a tango embrace, and discuss howthey are surrounded with angst.
I find it to be the terms man and woman that are surrounded by angst, and that is probably the reason people use lead and follow as euphemisms for man and woman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 tangos</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/01/12-tangos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 11:24:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/01/12-tangos/</guid>
      <description>Just ordered the new documentary 12 tangos. Will be very interesting to see, it also claims to be a Buena Vista Tango Club, so a shootout between 12 tangos and Cafe de los maestros. 12 tangos has a great advantage in being actually available.
I will get back to it later, in the meantime, the trailer:
[youtube]http://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=mrFklWP6dQY&amp;amp;feature=related[/youtube]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Masquerade</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/31/masquerade/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2008 21:07:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/31/masquerade/</guid>
      <description>Who are you when you are dancing? Are you the leader? The follower? The man? The woman? I was once confronted with my using the terminology man/woman in class. The person complaining said that she was dancing a role (she was dancing the man&amp;rsquo;s part) and that was the role of the leader.
I know this easily gets messy, but I never liked the euphemism leader/follower when what we are talking about is a man and a woman in most cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lágrima Ríos &amp; Candombe</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/28/lagrima-rios-candombe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2008 22:13:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/28/lagrima-rios-candombe/</guid>
      <description>I just love the name! Lágrima Ríos is a wonderful artistic name, Rivers of tears.. Re tango, no?
My attention was brought to some of her recordings by Michael&amp;rsquo;s music blog, discussing some available recordings of hers. Luckily, I was able to find them both at emusic for instant satisfaction :-) She is featured in the film Café de los maestros, which I have not yet been able to get hold of (but will eventually!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go before it&#39;s too late</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/28/go-before-its-too-late/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2008 22:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/28/go-before-its-too-late/</guid>
      <description>When should you go to Buenos Aires?I would say: as soon as possible. Go before it&amp;rsquo;s too late! You will gain nothing by waiting. You will not be good enough, anyway ;-) But do by all means go!
If you wait until you are ready, you risk missing out on the entire thing. Going to milongas in your neighborhood, you will believe you improve to become a good dancer, and that you know what tango is about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>¡Ahora, pollo!</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/26/ahora-pollo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2008 21:55:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/26/ahora-pollo/</guid>
      <description>Returning again to Buenos Aires, a lot more experienced and familiar with music and culture than the first time I had read that another Alberto was still live and kicking, Alberto Podestá that would be. We had some tango musicians from our city coming down, and thought it would be an excellent thing to do with them. Podestá is singing at the place La Cumparsita in San Telmo, but for some reason or another we never made it while our musicians were in town.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Death in the Afternoon</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/24/death-in-the-afternoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2008 20:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/24/death-in-the-afternoon/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, reading on very different topics can give deep insights in tango. Death in the Afternoon by Ernest Hemingway is such a book. I thought of tango often when reading his treaty on bullfighting.
While not being as deadly or controvertial as the bullfighting, tango is also a culture full of rituals and things you have to know to really appreciate. And it was the parts that was guiding the novice to understand the rich culture of bullfighting and its meaning that really made me think of tango.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fabian Peralta &amp; Virginia Pandolfi in HD</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/21/fabian-peralta-virginia-pandolfi-in-hd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2008 15:52:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/21/fabian-peralta-virginia-pandolfi-in-hd/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why so serious?</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/17/why-so-serious/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2008 21:50:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/17/why-so-serious/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes people are complaining that tango dancers are oh so serious. Never smiling or laughing. Relax, and have som fun, why so serious?
For me, I have always had a hard time agreeing on tango being fun. Of course it can be great fun, especially milonga, but not primarily fun. Fun actually has very little to do with it. That is not to say that I do not enjoy tango, on the contrary, I enjoy it very much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Putting the baby to sleep</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/14/putting-the-baby-to-sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 20:49:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/14/putting-the-baby-to-sleep/</guid>
      <description>I quite recently became a father, and the poor child is exposed to a lot of tango music, naturally. (And I get out to dance less, hence the blog writing.) Before he was born, I used to talk about how we would practice walking together, he and I. Now this is how it turned out:
The scene: Unpatiant 12 days old boy, waiting for his mother to get ready for breast-feeding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Café de los maestros</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/13/cafe-de-los-maestros/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2008 13:33:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/13/cafe-de-los-maestros/</guid>
      <description>Always looking out for new films about tango, both dance and music, I must say I am really looking forward to this one: Café de los maestros. It has been described as the tango equivalent to the _Buena Vista Social Club. I already got the soundtrack, so I know the music is excellent. Can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see it. _
When oh when will it become available on DVD? It will never be shown on the silver screen where I live I&amp;rsquo;m afraid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old tango hero</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/09/old-tango-hero/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2008 20:53:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/09/old-tango-hero/</guid>
      <description>On our first visit to Buenos Aires, we rented a room in San Telmo. Right in the neighborhood is the Centro Cultural Torquato Tasso. For some reason we never came around to go there, even if it was by far the closest milonga.
Until one evening, we finally found space in our schedule to visit El Tasso. There was to be live music, and we were quite excited. The place was packed with people, and all of a sudden an old man was announced, and with support from a couple of guys he entered the stage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ideal</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/23/the-ideal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2008 21:08:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/23/the-ideal/</guid>
      <description>The previous post about Confiteria Ideal reminded me of the first visit to Buenos Aires back in 2001. This was before YouTube, remember, and there was lots of rumors about everything, and not so much tango information available on the web.
Being interested in architecture as well as in tango, trying to find the location for a scene in the film Tango by Carlos Saura, we were told by someone that we should go to one of the oldest milongas in Buenos Aires, yes our source believed it would be the same milonga that was pictured in the movie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confiteria La Ideal en BBC</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/23/confiteria-la-ideal-en-bbc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2008 20:49:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/23/confiteria-la-ideal-en-bbc/</guid>
      <description>Another good documentary about tango. I enjoyed it a lot. Some of the interesting scenes are available on youtube, but the documentary itself was quite hard to get hold of. As far as I could determine, it is not available for sale, not even on ebay, so you better know one of them pirates or use your imagination ;-)
I am quite impressed by how ordinary dancers are able to express what tango means to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classes and entertainment</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/22/classes-and-entertainment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2008 11:01:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/22/classes-and-entertainment/</guid>
      <description>Why do people take classes? When I first started out in tango, I assumed people attended to classes to learn how to dance or to improve their dance, learning steps or improving technique or other skills. How naïve.
After several years more, I have discovered that people take classes for a variety of reasons, some of which I find perfectly reasonable, others I still cannot really understand. The good reasons are:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listening to the music</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/21/listening-to-the-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2008 20:48:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/21/listening-to-the-music/</guid>
      <description>What is good musicality?
Countless workshops are offered, people discuss who is dancing more musical or who doesn&amp;rsquo;t get it. But not easy to define. So without trying to get to the bottom of it, some reflexions are in place.
I heard quite often after dancing for a few years that I was dancing musically, which of course made me happy. Who wouldn&amp;rsquo;t like to dance musically? Of course it could be just to be polite and not mentioning my other more obvious shortcomings, but I think that even if my musicality was not very good or mature, at least I was:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More on less</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/21/more-on-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2008 20:30:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/21/more-on-less/</guid>
      <description>I just read an interview with this year&amp;rsquo;s campeones, Daniel Nacucchio &amp;amp; Cristina Sosa (congratulations, and nice to see Neri &amp;amp; Yanina did well also :-) - Well, he quoted old milonguero wisdom:
El que menos hace, a veces es el que hace más Which means something like, the one who does less, sometimes is the one that does more. (Forgive my translation, neither Spanish nor English is my native language).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passing judgement</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/05/passing-judgement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 20:17:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/05/passing-judgement/</guid>
      <description>It seems to be a popular activity among tango enthusasts, dissing all the dancers you don&amp;rsquo;t really like, especially teachers of course, and explain what everybody else does wrong. (Of course, we all do everything right ourselves ;-)
Sometimes it gets a bit out of hand, and can spread some negative energy, in particular when there is disagreement of who is in and who is out on a table at the milonga or in a small community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>O Ultimo Bandoneón</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/08/21/o-ultimo-bandoneon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2008 18:39:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/08/21/o-ultimo-bandoneon/</guid>
      <description>It is actually possible to get hold of this, but I had to order it from Brazil, so it was with portuguese subtitles, which was - challenging, but a very nice film it was. Recommended.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More or less?</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/08/07/more-or-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2008 18:26:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/08/07/more-or-less/</guid>
      <description>To quote Mies van der Rohe, less is more. As in architecture, this is very true in tango, I think. I was always accused of being subtle in my dancing (I always suspected it to be a euphemism for unclear, vague or not present). To my great surprise, after many years learning to dance the milonga - yes learning the milonga, more on this later - one of the things I really had to work on being more subtle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>El último bandoneón</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/22/la-ultima-bandoneon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2008 10:15:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/22/la-ultima-bandoneon/</guid>
      <description>httpvh://youtube.com/watch?v=eGerxiMniBQ
Maravillosa!
Now where can I get the entire film?
Trailer here:
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neri &amp; Yanina</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/16/neri-yanina/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2008 09:47:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/16/neri-yanina/</guid>
      <description>Standing out at the práctica of Carlitos and Rosa, it&amp;rsquo;s good to see they did well at the campeonato. Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clichés</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/06/cliches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2008 10:31:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/06/cliches/</guid>
      <description>Ever since I started dancing, the topic of tango clichés has fascinated me. The rose in mouth, castanets, head flicks, dramatic poses are all parts of what usually pops into people&amp;rsquo;s heads when they hear the word tango. Where did they come from, and why did they stick? Going through a lot of Hollywood production at least gives a partial answer, and Rudolph Valentino is one of the people to blame, the rose in mouth appears in the film Blood and sand, where he plays a bullfighter, while the film he dances the tango is _Four horsemen of the apocalypse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gavito Dixit</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/06/01/gavito-dixit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 15:26:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/06/01/gavito-dixit/</guid>
      <description>Gavito Dixit I ¿Bailaste el tango de tu vida esta noche? No bailes más… El tangauta #129
Gavito Dixit II El tango está entre paso y paso, allí donde se escuchan los silencios y cantan las musas. El tangauta #130
Gavito Dixit III El hombre debe saber que baila para ella,y al hacerlo, hace que ella se vea como una reina. Sólo así será el rey. El tangauta #131</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/about-simba/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2008 17:15:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/about-simba/</guid>
      <description>A tango dancer since 1998&amp;frasl;1999, I have been consumed by learning, dancing, teaching and djing as well as community building in my small tango community.
Always thinking a lot about the tango and why it means so much to me, but not always time to write or discuss with the equally tango crazy, I have had the intention to blog for some time, but after I became a father quite recently, there is much less time for dancing, but some time for blogging in between.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>