<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Milongueros on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/categories/milongueros/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Milongueros on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 14:43:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/categories/milongueros/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rare Clips of Petróleo, Virulazo and others</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2013/03/31/rare-clips-of-petroleo-virulazo-and-others/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 14:43:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2013/03/31/rare-clips-of-petroleo-virulazo-and-others/</guid>
      <description>Amazing how these old clips slowly surface on youtube and facebook. Here are some clips that seem to be from an old documentary, posted by Victor Barrios and Cristina Benavidez:
      HT: @FerGaleraTango</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Losing a Friend</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2012/01/04/losing-a-friend/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 22:34:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2012/01/04/losing-a-friend/</guid>
      <description>by HocusFocusClick
Standing in front of the window, glancing out. The day had long since started, yet it was dark outside. It was pouring down, despite being mid-winter. He saw through the rain. He saw through the house across the street.
What he saw was her smile. Her dancing cumbia in the kitchen. Her explaining the concepts of &amp;ldquo;cheta&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;negro&amp;rdquo;. Her expertly preparing a mate. &amp;ldquo;Her standing on one leg in the Comme il Faut showroom, trying one shoe while putting on a second while asking for third pair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning From Early Music</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/07/10/learning-from-early-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 11:54:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/07/10/learning-from-early-music/</guid>
      <description>by madabandon
In a sense, dancing Argentine Tango in 2011 in a country far away from Argentina is an inescapable anachronism. How could it ever be authentic? Should it be? Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t any art form evolve and develop in a quest for ever improvement? In the (un)concious choice between opposing traditions, which would be the right to follow?
Now, these questions are not unique for tango of course:
The idea of revival has become a touchstone for the Early Music Movement, and consequently the fact that some styles of performance have been going on long enough to develop and build their own continuity presents some philosophical complications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rodolfo &amp; Maria Cieri and others @ Dailymotion</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/07/22/rodolfo-maria-cieri-and-others-dailymotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2010 20:50:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/07/22/rodolfo-maria-cieri-and-others-dailymotion/</guid>
      <description>** **_I just discovered several early nineties videos at dailymotion, uploaded by tanguito94. If I&amp;rsquo;m not mistaken, this is filmed at the now defunct milonga El Akarense. _In addition to this one with Rodolfo &amp;amp; Maria Cieri from 1994, there is one with Pupi &amp;amp; Graciela, Pepito &amp;amp; Gilda and Stella Barba &amp;amp; Victor Romero.
Enjoy!
HT: Jorge</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution?</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/04/27/evolution-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2010 20:35:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/04/27/evolution-2/</guid>
      <description>I hear it every so often: that tango technique, especially for women, has gone through a tremendous evolution since the resurgence in the early 1980s. Let&amp;rsquo;s just say I&amp;rsquo;m not quite convinced. Watch this clip from the 1988 movie Tango Bar, and draw your own conclusions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adiós Maestro</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/04/18/adios-maestro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2010 19:03:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/04/18/adios-maestro/</guid>
      <description>by Simba tango
Friday morning brought more sad news from Buenos Aires. It is time to complete the biography of El &amp;ldquo;Turco&amp;rdquo; José Brahemcha. Another great milonguero is gone.
He had been sick for a while, so in a sense it was no surprise, and we did wonder if we were ever to see him again as we parted for the last time from his apartment in Buenos Aires.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;El Turco&#34; José Brahemcha -- a short biography</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/03/09/el-turco-jose-brahemcha-a-short-biography/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2010 19:23:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/03/09/el-turco-jose-brahemcha-a-short-biography/</guid>
      <description>El &#34;Turco&#34; José -- as he is commonly known -- was born in Buenos Aires, in the neighborhood of Saavedra, July 17 1931. He was a dedicated bicycle rider when he was a kid, until his mother (who was a tango singer) suggested that he learn to dance &#34;to get to know some girls&#34;. At the age of 16, he started to practice with his friends from his neighborhood in the house of one of them, where they had a gramophone player.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Essence of Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/16/tango-essence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2010 19:30:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/16/tango-essence/</guid>
      <description>When we watched the milongueros dancing years ago, we could perceive the mystery behind what they did, no matter if it was easy or difficult. Therefore, technique has to be understood first, then it can be copied, but the goal is to get to its essence. If you use the word &#34;technique&#34; less in class, and instead use words like &#34;essence&#34; and &#34;sensation&#34;, students can perform the movement with a more natural attitude and will learn faster than if you speak about numbers, diagonals or muscles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;El Turco&#39; José Brahemcha</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/14/el-turco-jose-brahemcha/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2010 11:38:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/14/el-turco-jose-brahemcha/</guid>
      <description>I have only one great regret in tango, and that it not taking classes with Gavito. Of course there are others as well, but with Gavito we had the opportunity, we passed, and shame on us for it. Of course, at the time we simply didn&amp;rsquo;t know better.
Determined not to make same mistake again, we decided to take our teachers&amp;rsquo; advice and try to get in touch with the legendary &amp;lsquo;El Turco&amp;rsquo; José.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homenaje a los milongueros -- the show</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/10/homenaje-a-los-milongueros-the-show/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2009 02:30:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/10/homenaje-a-los-milongueros-the-show/</guid>
      <description>Marisa Galindo was directing a show in honor of the milongueros, and she is now posting footage from this show on youtube for all of us to see! The show was filmed on the 16th of October 1991, Homenaje a los Milongueros de Buenos Aires.
I have seen fragments of this show before, but didn&amp;rsquo;t know the source, and this seems to be much better quality and I think complete. Truth to be told, I haven&amp;rsquo;t had time to watch it all yet, but I will, and I will watch it again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Death of the Prodigy dancer</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/03/16/death-of-the-prodigy-dancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2009 21:40:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/03/16/death-of-the-prodigy-dancer/</guid>
      <description>by Mickal
Tango is full of nostalgia, even sentimentality. We long for the times that were. Even sentimentality was better in the 40s. How can it be for the real milongueros, who were young in that time?
Not to say it is the same, but the thought struck me the other day. I just bought the new Prodigy album, playing it loud and dancing around the kitchen. (I do this a lot, usually to tango music these days) This was the music of my youth, when we went out to party, that was the best.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waiting for the right moment</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/18/waiting-for-the-right-moment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2008 17:57:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/18/waiting-for-the-right-moment/</guid>
      <description>by just.Luc
   -I see a lot of men are not dancing. They can&#39;t manage to dance when the floor is so full of people.     -It may not be because of lack of ability. It may be because they enjoy the dance more when the floor is not packed and they can more around the floor in their dance. Maybe they are waiting for their favorite music.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the eye of the beholder</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/06/in-the-eye-of-the-beholder/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2008 17:31:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/06/in-the-eye-of-the-beholder/</guid>
      <description>Isn&amp;rsquo;t it funny how we see so different things, even when watching the exact same event?

I remember seeing containers all over the place while we were renovating our appartment, a friend who is an architect and carpenter seemed to literally see through the walls in the house before we bought it. A trained art expert will instantly recognize the work of an artist, an analyst will see through the endless rows of numbers in a spreadsheet&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confiteria La Ideal en BBC</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/23/confiteria-la-ideal-en-bbc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2008 20:49:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/23/confiteria-la-ideal-en-bbc/</guid>
      <description>Another good documentary about tango. I enjoyed it a lot. Some of the interesting scenes are available on youtube, but the documentary itself was quite hard to get hold of. As far as I could determine, it is not available for sale, not even on ebay, so you better know one of them pirates or use your imagination ;-)
I am quite impressed by how ordinary dancers are able to express what tango means to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More on less</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/21/more-on-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2008 20:30:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/21/more-on-less/</guid>
      <description>I just read an interview with this year&amp;rsquo;s campeones, Daniel Nacucchio &amp;amp; Cristina Sosa (congratulations, and nice to see Neri &amp;amp; Yanina did well also :-) - Well, he quoted old milonguero wisdom:
El que menos hace, a veces es el que hace más Which means something like, the one who does less, sometimes is the one that does more. (Forgive my translation, neither Spanish nor English is my native language).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>El último bandoneón</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/22/la-ultima-bandoneon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2008 10:15:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/22/la-ultima-bandoneon/</guid>
      <description>httpvh://youtube.com/watch?v=eGerxiMniBQ
Maravillosa!
Now where can I get the entire film?
Trailer here:
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>