<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tangovia on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/tags/tangovia/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tangovia on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/tags/tangovia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributing to the Digital Tango Archive</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/12/11/contributing-to-the-digital-tango-archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2010 13:46:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/12/11/contributing-to-the-digital-tango-archive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/erielookingproductions/4080575123/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2464/4080575123_c522fec054.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Library Donations Box by erielookingproductions, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/erielookingproductions/&#34;&gt; erielookingproductions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have written about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/07/31/a-labour-of-love-that-needs-more-lovers/&#34;&gt;effort of Tango Via to digitally archive the entire tango catalogue&lt;/a&gt;, and how &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/12/21/inside-the-digital-archive/&#34;&gt;I was impressed with their ambitions, the work so far&lt;/a&gt; and the significance of preserving the tango culture for the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an update to point your attention to their &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tangovia.org/membresias.htm&#34;&gt;donation page&lt;/a&gt;, you can &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.helpargentina.org/en/digitalarchive&#34;&gt;donate via Help Argentina&lt;/a&gt; if you are outside Argentina. If in Argentina, they suggest you get in touch with them to get instructions for donations. If you have important original material, that is also a way to contribute to the project, but I suspect hard cash is what my readers are most likely to have for offer. US residents get a tax exempt under the terms of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/501(c)#501.28c.29.283.29&#34;&gt;501(c.3)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read more about the digital archive and &lt;a href=&#34;http://tangovia.org&#34;&gt;Tango Vía&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/08/10/tango-via-in-el-tangauta/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/10/29/ignacio-varchausky-interview/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.guardian.co.uk/culture/2010/oct/05/argentina-dance-tango-buenos-aires&#34;&gt;in The Guardian&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inside the digital archive</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/22/inside-the-digital-archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2009 01:45:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/22/inside-the-digital-archive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/erica_marshall/2656065581/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3148/2656065581_1d1732991b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Hard Drive Guts by Erica_Marshall, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/erica_marshall/&#34;&gt; Erica_Marshall&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Ignacio Varchausky gave his &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/12/19/what-to-listen-for-in-tango/&#34;&gt;musicality seminar&lt;/a&gt; at the&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.visittangobuenosaires.com/La_Casa_del_Tango-sp.htm&#34;&gt; Casa de tango&lt;/a&gt; here in Buenos Aires, where the &lt;a href=&#34;http://tangovia.org/&#34;&gt;TangoVía&lt;/a&gt; project resides, he was kind to show us around the premises and demonstrate the current state of the digital archive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They have a very &lt;a href=&#34;http://tangovia.org/archivo_audio.htm&#34;&gt;nice set of equipment&lt;/a&gt;, he showed us the machine they use to clean the discs properly before doing the transfers, the different turntables for different kinds of discs, amplifiers and ADC as well as tape equipment. In addition to the recordings themselves, they are scanning or photographing the covers and where available, the original scores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the really interesting part was when Ignacio sat down in front of a computer and demonstrated the already working database with everything that was already digitized and properly catalogued. From a nice web interface, one could perform all kinds of searches in the music, matrix number, original format, artist, year etc. From the results page, you could play an mp3 version of the material directly, and where available you could open the scores and watch them while listening to the music. Very impressive, and no doubt this will become an important tool for musicians, dancers and researchers in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, I was very interested in their plans with respect to releasing the material they are collecting. That is the next phase, said Ignacio, first they have to collect the material, and archive it properly. Then the legal issues have  to be resolved. They hope to be able to put the database online eventually, for everybody to enjoy the richness of tango through the ages. Then they will think about releasing records. They don&amp;rsquo;t get much if any help from the record companies, in fact in a way they are competitors, as the record companies don&amp;rsquo;t have access to all the material themselves anymore. The record companies have themselves to blame, of course, as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.totango.net/rca.html&#34;&gt;they burned the masters&lt;/a&gt; themselves&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TangoVía are collaborating with a lot of important and knowledgeable collectors, including the local partner of the Japanese Akihito Baba of Club Tango Argentino &amp;lsquo;fame&amp;rsquo;. In addition to published recordings, they will digitize rare gems; tracks recorded from radio broadcasts, outtakes. Ignacio demonstrated a few such hidden jewels of the collections, Horacio Salgán playing and Alfredo Gobbi (violinist) playing solo piano.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can you and I help? If you didn&amp;rsquo;t already listen to the interview by Keith Elshaw, I can tell you that they are launching a program for donating money around March 2010. For U.S. citizens, it will even be tax deductable. I will keep you posted when they launch the new program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to spreading the word, you can start thinking about organizing some charity milongas or adding a voluntary donation to festival/marathon/milonga payment options. I think this is a project clearly worthy of the support from the entire tango community all over the world!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ignacio Varchausky interview</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/10/30/ignacio-varchausky-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2009 00:03:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/10/30/ignacio-varchausky-interview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/smiling_da_vinci/14785644/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/11/14785644_d4b5aea489.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Interview by smiling_da_vinci, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/smiling_da_vinci/&#34;&gt; smiling_da_vinci&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keith over at &lt;a href=&#34;http://totango.net/&#34;&gt;totango.ne&lt;/a&gt;t just published an interview with Ignacio of El Arranque, Orquesta Escuela de tango &amp;amp; TangoVia, and you can download it from his page. He doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide a permalink for his post, so for future reference, the files can be found here &lt;a href=&#34;http://totango.net/Ignacio%20Interview%20Part%201.mp3&#34;&gt;part one&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://totango.net/Ignacio%20Interview%20Part%202.mp3&#34;&gt;part two&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://totango.net/Ignacio%20Interview%20Part%203.mp3&#34;&gt;part three&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t had time to check it out myself yet, maybe on the plane&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>