<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tangovia on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/tags/tangovia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tangovia on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2010 13:46:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/tags/tangovia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributing to the Digital Tango Archive</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/12/11/contributing-to-the-digital-tango-archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2010 13:46:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/12/11/contributing-to-the-digital-tango-archive/</guid>
      <description>by erielookingproductions
I have written about the effort of Tango Via to digitally archive the entire tango catalogue, and how I was impressed with their ambitions, the work so far and the significance of preserving the tango culture for the future.
This is an update to point your attention to their donation page, you can donate via Help Argentina if you are outside Argentina. If in Argentina, they suggest you get in touch with them to get instructions for donations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inside the digital archive</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/22/inside-the-digital-archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2009 01:45:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/22/inside-the-digital-archive/</guid>
      <description>by Erica_Marshall
After Ignacio Varchausky gave his musicality seminar at theCasa de tango here in Buenos Aires, where the TangoVía project resides, he was kind to show us around the premises and demonstrate the current state of the digital archive.
They have a very nice set of equipment, he showed us the machine they use to clean the discs properly before doing the transfers, the different turntables for different kinds of discs, amplifiers and ADC as well as tape equipment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ignacio Varchausky interview</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/10/30/ignacio-varchausky-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2009 00:03:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/10/30/ignacio-varchausky-interview/</guid>
      <description>by smiling_da_vinci
Keith over at totango.net just published an interview with Ignacio of El Arranque, Orquesta Escuela de tango &amp;amp; TangoVia, and you can download it from his page. He doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide a permalink for his post, so for future reference, the files can be found here part one, part two and part three.
I haven&amp;rsquo;t had time to check it out myself yet, maybe on the plane&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>