<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Review on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>https://simbatango.github.io/tags/review/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Review on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="https://simbatango.github.io/tags/review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>DyM Online | Tango Classics</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2011/05/07/dym-online--tango-classics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 20:27:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2011/05/07/dym-online--tango-classics/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/toddbinger/3235728614/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3265/3235728614_f7835317b7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Color Spectrum CD Reflection by Todd Binger, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/toddbinger/&#34;&gt; Todd Binger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to check out the offerings of DyM a bit more closely after I noticed that some of them were available in lossless format from the French site Qobuz. I got a couple of De Caro compilations because they are hard to get by other places. These tracks are mostly from the late 20s and early 30s, so what I found out may or may not apply to other, later recordings issued in this series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;material&#34;&gt;Material&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of these tracks are not available on cd or as downloads anywhere else as far as I know, and early De Caro is very intersting for several reasons, not least because he had a great influence on the development of tango music. To state it briefly, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.todotango.com/english/creadores/jdecaro.html&#34;&gt;De Caro was a genius&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;quality&#34;&gt;Quality&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These several of these volumes are available as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.qobuz.com/label/zebralution-dym-online/telechargement-ecoute-albums&#34;&gt;lossless downloads from Qobuz&lt;/a&gt;, and now &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.danzaymovimiento.com/dymlog/id/133-Download-salsa-and-tango-music-as-FLAC&#34;&gt;also directly from DyM&lt;/a&gt;. This is a great development, and very useful for tango music, as it can often be useful to do some eq or other processing of the sound, which is the case where lossy codecs are not really a good choice. And it turned out that some editing is indeed needed for the DyM releases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quality of the transfers I got was very variable. Some tracks were fine, with little noise and pretty much ready to be listened to, others were very noisy and quite a few were noticeably sped up during transfer from shellac. I tried slowing them down 6-12% (depending on track), and by comparing to other versions of the tracks that I already had, I got it more or less right, but it is very hard if not impossible to know for sure what the exact speed should be. One has to use one&amp;rsquo;s ears, and I used the timbre of the piano as a guideline, which seems to have worked out fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is in stark contrast with the Japanese collectors editions of CTA and AMP which are consistently well transferred in my experience. The transfers of El Bandoneon were infamous for being transferred at too high speed, like many of these are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cover-and-information&#34;&gt;Cover and information&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These collections are download only, which means that there is basically no cover information such as recording date, matrix number etc. Very bare bone. I used &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tango.info/albums/?col=DYM+Online%2F+Tango+Classics&#34;&gt;tango.info&lt;/a&gt; to improve tagging of my files. The Japanese series of CTA and AMP are way ahead in providing meta information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover art is a joke. Not only is the image a disaster, the cover image also suffers from &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Compression_artifact&#34;&gt;ugly jpg artifacts&lt;/a&gt;. Not that it is really important, but I mean &amp;ndash;  come on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;price-and-availability&#34;&gt;Price and availability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I actually think download only works well for this fringe material. Not to say for all music. For me personally cds are not very interesting, I only read a cd exactly once anyway which is when I rip it to lossless files on my computer. Lossless downloads is a very nice development, and kudos for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both at Qobuz and at DyM you have to buy the entire volume to get the lossless version, though, which is irritating and somewhat offsets the advantage of downloads where you usually only pay for the tracks you need. I know I am not alone in buying cds to get just one track missing from my collection. Therefore this is unfortunate from a customer perspective, but probably makes sense from a profit maximizing vendor perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9-10 tracks for EUR 10.39 at Qobuz and ca EUR 9 + membership (EUR 29.88/year) from DyM is a bit pricey, considering the price of commercial releases from Argentina and BATC where you get roughly twice the number of tracks for the same price. It is a bit cheaper and much more readily available than the Japanese releases, but the quality of the transfers and the information provided is not at the same level either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearly material for collectors and djs only.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tangueros del Norte: Inspiración</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2008/12/24/tangueros-del-norte-inspiraci%C3%B3n/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2008 00:21:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2008/12/24/tangueros-del-norte-inspiraci%C3%B3n/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/12/inspiracion.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/12/inspiracion.png&#34; alt=&#34;Tangueros del Norte: Inspiración&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine a tango orchestra of really young and talented musicians, forming a small orquesta típica with members ranging from the age of 10-14. Three bandoneóns, three violins, double bass and piano. Playing tango, and not only Piazzolla. Playing together for several years to get the music under their skin. Where would this happen if not in Buenos Aires?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Norway! In a cold small town in the middle of nowhere, or in the heart of Norway as some would say. Up in the northern desert, they call themselves _Tangueros del Norte. _The orchestra was formed back in 2003, and they just released their debut album, which is called &lt;em&gt;Inspiración&lt;/em&gt;, released December 8 2008.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The orchestra is the ultimate result of the work of the bandoneón player &lt;em&gt;Kåre Jostein Simonsen&lt;/em&gt;, who started teaching bandoneón in the municipality music school. He had a vision about how great it would be to create a real tango orchestra and play the great arrangements of Pugliese&amp;hellip;  He gathered his talented bandoneón-players and searched for other talented youngsters to complete the orchestra, and the rest as they say, is history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twice they have been to Buenos Aires to learn, and even if they impressed very early, they have grown considerably over the years. Their musical travel has been documented in a film by &lt;em&gt;Mari Lunden Nilsen&lt;/em&gt;, called &lt;em&gt;Lidenskapens skole&lt;/em&gt; (The school of passion). The film was shown at the 2008 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kosmorama.no/&#34;&gt;Kosmorama film festival&lt;/a&gt;, and will be broadcasted on Norwegian national TV (&lt;a href=&#34;http://tv2.no/&#34;&gt;TV2&lt;/a&gt;) December 26. The film shows how these youngsters have grown up together and not just as musicians.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The young musicians have taken over more and more control of the artistic development, and the only regret, seen from a dancer&amp;rsquo;s perspective, is that they are (like most other tango players) completely uninterested in playing for dancing. Because they believe it is too simple. And that is a pity, as they have great potential, but lack a feeling for the &amp;ldquo;swing&amp;rdquo; (what would be a good word for this?) of tango. As many other classically trained musicians, they think that tango allows them to be sloppy, which to some degree is correct, but when they are not sloppy in the right manner and the right places, the result is  &amp;ndash; well sloppy. This is particularly evident in the Piazzolla composition _Libertango, _where they are sometimes way off tempo, without it adding anything to the interpretation. They are simply off, and it is disturbing. Playing fast is simply not enough, it is supposed to be &lt;em&gt;fast and precise&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong &amp;ndash; the record in total has come off quite well, particularly taking into consideration how young they all are. The oldest have just started their education in music academies. One of the most interesting tracks is &lt;em&gt;Vino y se fue&lt;/em&gt;, a tango written to the lead violinist Viktor Stenhjem by the composer &lt;em&gt;Sverre Indris Joner&lt;/em&gt; of &lt;em&gt;Electrocutango&lt;/em&gt; fame. And in this piece the violinist really shines. The title track Inspiración and Sumblime fantasía are also very nice. &lt;em&gt;Libertango&lt;/em&gt; as already mentioned, does not convince me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well recorded and with some very fine tracks, Inspiración is overall well worth a listen. Actually it is really better than most non-Argentine tango records. And being a orquesta típica makes the sound much fuller than most tango orchestras around, which are often trios, quartets or quintets. If you have the opportunity to experience them live: go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will be very interesting to see what comes next from this tango orchestra, and I am sure we will hear more from them, both in Tangueros del Norte and in other settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can get the record at &lt;a href=&#34;http://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewAlbum?id=300505601&amp;amp;s=143457&#34;&gt;iTunes&lt;/a&gt; now, at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.musiconline.no/shop/displayAlbum.asp?id=35975&#34;&gt;MusicOnline&lt;/a&gt; and at &lt;a href=&#34;http://cdon.no/musikk/tangueros_del_norte/inspiracione-4063906&#34;&gt;CdOn&lt;/a&gt;. You can also &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tangueros.no/musikk/&#34;&gt;listen to some sample tracks&lt;/a&gt; at their &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tangueros.no/&#34;&gt;homepage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 Tangos -- Adios Buenos Aires</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2008/11/19/12-tangos----adios-buenos-aires/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2008 17:06:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2008/11/19/12-tangos----adios-buenos-aires/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/11/12-tangos.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/11/12-tangos.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The documentary &lt;a href=&#34;http://12tangos.com&#34;&gt;12 tangos&lt;/a&gt; was just released in international version on DVD. It is a documentary, and the Adios Buenos Aires part of the title is somehow more accurate with regards to the content of the film. If you are looking for the Buena Vista Social Club of tango, you will be disappointed. There are no interviews with musicians, and only a few of the oldtimers participate in the orchestra. So Café de los maestros should be a better bet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;12 tangos is mainly a film about the hard times in Argentina after the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Argentine_economic_crisis_(1999-2002)&#34;&gt;crisis in &lt;sup&gt;2001&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2002&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/a&gt; when many lost everything they had, and quite a lot of people were forced to move to Europe to get work. That is, in the opposite direction of their anscestors, who went from Europe to Argentine for the same purpose. The film tells the stories of a young dancer (Marcela Maiola) going to Paris, her partner, the retired professional dancer (&lt;a href=&#34;http://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=ji6R1K_oAUo&#34;&gt;Roberto Tonet&lt;/a&gt;) who is afraid of losing his apartment in order to survive and  a mother (Yolanda Zubieta) leaving her children to go to Spain (she has no apparent connection with tango).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mixed in between these are musical numbers from a concert at La Catedral, a milonga in Buenos Aires. This is where the 12 tangos come in, and they are supposed to work like a framwork for the storytelling, and are marked as chapters on the dvd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though it did not take me with storm, I quite enjoyed the film. The photography was excellent at times. I particularly enjoyed the scene that is shown on the cover, where some partly hidden dancers are part of the live show at La Catedral. It works much better in motion than on the cover. The dancing was ok, not stunning, but nice. I did not like the slow motion sequence, though, as the connection with the music is completely lost, but maybe it works better for non-dancers. I admit my preferences in this respect have changed considerably after taking up dancing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Las muñecas dressed as vampires were hilarious, even if they were even better in _&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0380741/&#34;&gt;Tango, un giro extraño&lt;/a&gt;__. _And Roberto was quite a character :-) But I also found something amiss, like it did not all fit together that well. Maybe the relation between the 12 tangos and the rest of the film was not clear enough.  There were also some peculiarities, like having school-children explain the economic crisis that I found a bit strange. Some glitches in the text, where the English text was suddenly in German.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some more about the musicians would have been nice, and the presence of José Libertella was perhaps a bit oversold, as he is only featured in one of the last musical numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall a nice film. And on a completely subjective note, it is so good to see footage from mi Buenos Aires querido, el colectivo, hearing people chit chat, people walking in the streets, the skyline&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both the film and the soundtrack are available from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://12tangos.com/&#34;&gt;film&amp;rsquo;s website&lt;/a&gt;. It took about a week from I order until I had the discs in my hand. For immediate listening, I just discovered that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.emusic.com/album/Luis-Borda-12-Tangos-Adios-Buenos-Aires-MP3-Download/11320075.html&#34;&gt;the sountrack is available on emusic&lt;/a&gt; as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>