<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Review on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/tags/review/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Review on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 20:27:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/tags/review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>DyM Online | Tango Classics</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/05/07/dym-online-tango-classics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 20:27:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/05/07/dym-online-tango-classics/</guid>
      <description>by Todd Binger
I decided to check out the offerings of DyM a bit more closely after I noticed that some of them were available in lossless format from the French site Qobuz. I got a couple of De Caro compilations because they are hard to get by other places. These tracks are mostly from the late 20s and early 30s, so what I found out may or may not apply to other, later recordings issued in this series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tangueros del Norte: Inspiración</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/24/tangueros-del-norte-inspiracion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2008 00:21:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/24/tangueros-del-norte-inspiracion/</guid>
      <description>Imagine a tango orchestra of really young and talented musicians, forming a small orquesta típica with members ranging from the age of 10-14. Three bandoneóns, three violins, double bass and piano. Playing tango, and not only Piazzolla. Playing together for several years to get the music under their skin. Where would this happen if not in Buenos Aires?
In Norway! In a cold small town in the middle of nowhere, or in the heart of Norway as some would say.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 Tangos -- Adios Buenos Aires</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/19/12-tangos-adios-buenos-aires/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2008 17:06:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/19/12-tangos-adios-buenos-aires/</guid>
      <description>The documentary 12 tangos was just released in international version on DVD. It is a documentary, and the Adios Buenos Aires part of the title is somehow more accurate with regards to the content of the film. If you are looking for the Buena Vista Social Club of tango, you will be disappointed. There are no interviews with musicians, and only a few of the oldtimers participate in the orchestra.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>