<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Advice on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/categories/advice/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Advice on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2012 21:51:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/categories/advice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Find One Error</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2012/12/04/find-one-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2012 21:51:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2012/12/04/find-one-error/</guid>
      <description>This is a great idea! Trouvez l&amp;rsquo;erreur! from Les Pas Parfaits de Montréal. Simple, funny and well executed. Drawings by Véronique Paquette. My French is a bit rusty, but I believe the drawings are free to use for non-commercial purposes, and that it is allowed to translate them and incorporate translations in the images.
Makes me want to go to Montréal!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience the breadth of tango in Buenos Aires</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/03/24/experience-the-breadth-of-tango-in-buenos-aires/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 12:54:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/03/24/experience-the-breadth-of-tango-in-buenos-aires/</guid>
      <description>by Simba tango
A friend is going to Buenos Aires for the first time this week, and I sent her some information about where to go, encouraging her to experience the breadth of tango in Buenos Aires. So many people get stuck in one small part of the tango world and never experience anything else. When they come back, they believe they know how the tango in Buenos Aires is&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango and Toddler in Buenos Aires</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/15/tango-and-toddler-in-buenos-aires/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2009 00:03:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/15/tango-and-toddler-in-buenos-aires/</guid>
      <description>by salvoguille
Dear readers: I need your advice: We consider ourselves to find our way around in Buenos Aires fairly well after several previous stays there. This time, however, there is something different. We are no longer a couple going to the milongas every night. We are a small family.
Strolling with or without purpose in the streets of our beloved city we can still do, enjoying café con leche while watching people walk past, too.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>