<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Metaphor on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/tags/metaphor/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Metaphor on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 23:41:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/tags/metaphor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Eating the marshmellow</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/27/eating-the-marshmellow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 23:41:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/27/eating-the-marshmellow/</guid>
      <description>by Sarah Marafi (мυƒƒιησσн™)
I just read a very interesting article in the New Yorker about research on people&amp;rsquo;s ability to deter satisfaction, and how it could be a character treat determined very early. The researchers performed an experiment where children were given the choice of eating a marshmellow now, or wait fifteen minutes, waiting in front of the marshmellows, and get two marshmellows. Some kids were able to find ways of distracting themselves, earning the extra marshmellow in the end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empty movement</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/04/empty-movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2009 20:43:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/04/empty-movement/</guid>
      <description>by bass_nroll
As you probably know, tango is not merely a dance. Among other things, the dance is also a language. It is not like a language, because the different movements have different meanings, which can be used for actual communication. It is not a metaphor. However, when people copy movements without realizing the underlying meaning, the result is movements with no meaning. Empty movement.
Or even worse, you may be saying something without knowing it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sabor a tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/12/sabor-a-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2009 20:22:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/12/sabor-a-tango/</guid>
      <description>by Simba tango
It is common to say that we taste four diffent tastes: sweet, salt, bitter and sour. Combinations of these make up all other tastes. Sounds familiar? You may be guessing what I&amp;rsquo;m getting at&amp;hellip;
The experience of taste, or should I say the experience of a meal, which we humans make for the pure pleasure of enjoying the different tastes and combinations, consists of a lot more than these four basic tastes (some also include umami, but that&amp;rsquo;s not the point).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>