<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Styles on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>https://simbatango.github.io/tags/styles/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Styles on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="https://simbatango.github.io/tags/styles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango (the Dance) Genealogy</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2010/10/08/tango-the-dance-genealogy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2010 12:19:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2010/10/08/tango-the-dance-genealogy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/styles-evolution.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/styles-evolution.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The evolution of tango has not followed a single, easy to track, path. It is rather quite a mess, so in an attempt to figure out how it all goes together, I tried putting my current understaning together in a &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/styles-evolution.pdf&#34;&gt;chart (pdf)&lt;/a&gt; showing the main developments of the tango dance in all its incarnations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just to reiterate: in my opinion there are two distinctions that really matter in tango: &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2008/12/03/all-you-need-to-know-about-style/&#34;&gt;Social vs. performance&lt;/a&gt;, which I covered before, and good vs. bad. Which is nothing new, of course:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;No hay tango viejo ni tango nuevo. El tango es uno solo. Tal vez la única diferencia está entre los que lo hacen bien y los que lo hacen mal

There is no old tango nor is there new tango. Tango is one. Perhaps the only difference is between those who do it well and those that do it badly.

&gt; 
&gt; _Aníbal Troilo_
&gt; 
&gt; 
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, the intricacies of &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2010/06/21/on-style/&#34;&gt;style&lt;/a&gt;s and evolution in tango is a fascinating topic, and this is my humble and far from perfect attempt to visualize  tango&amp;rsquo;s development. Constructive criticism, additions and corrections of errors are most welcome. Suggestions for improvements in formatting likewise. Bear in mind that many of the terms are not well defined, and different people may refer to the same things under different names or to different things under the same name&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some notes about this chart: I started out from Stephen Brown&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tejastango.com/evolution.html&#34;&gt;Evolution of Argentine Tango Styles&lt;/a&gt;, but I have made some additions and modifications. The term &amp;ldquo;tango salón&amp;rdquo; is ambiguous at best when describing tango styles. In my opinion, what is often referred to as milonguero style is also tango salón, but there seems to be no widely acknowledged term for social tango not including  milonguero style or nuevo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In lack of a better term, I used &amp;ldquo;Modern Salón&amp;rdquo; to denote the current mix of several styles of social tango. I grouped several geographical styles under the somewhat arbitrary Northern (roughly from Palermo, Crespo  to Pueyrredón, Urquiza and Saavedra etc.), Centre and Southern (roughly La Boca, San Telmo etc). This is in accordance with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.history-of-tango.com/tango-dance.html&#34;&gt;Christine Denniston&amp;rsquo;s observations&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created the chart with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.graphviz.org/&#34;&gt;graphviz&lt;/a&gt; (dot), the &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/tango-genealogy.zip&#34;&gt;chart source is available here&lt;/a&gt;. Tango (the Dance) Genealogy by &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2010/10/08/tango-the-dance-genealogy/&#34;&gt;Simba tango&lt;/a&gt; is licensed under a &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 Unported License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All you need to know about style</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2008/12/03/all-you-need-to-know-about-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2008 17:56:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2008/12/03/all-you-need-to-know-about-style/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/dccxlix/402981172/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/162/402981172_e9e0825a39.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Jack’s Bugatti by DCCXLIX, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/dccxlix/&#34;&gt; DCCXLIX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot can be said about styles in tango. More on that in later posts. All you &lt;em&gt;need to know&lt;/em&gt; about styles is the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traditionally, we make a distinction between social tango (tango salón) and performances (tango fantasía).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;tango-salón&#34;&gt;Tango salón&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a milonga, good navigation and connection with your partner is very important, as is dancing with the rest of the dance floor, which in general means no high boleos, ganchos etc. Just because you know how to do them, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to use them on a crowded floor. Rather, stay with movements close to the floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As long as people respect these basic guidelines, dancers are usually compatible, regardless of individual differences in dancing style, body size etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Buenos Aires, you will observe that people in the centre, where it is more crowded, dance closer and travel less (around the dance floor), and make smaller steps. In the milongas in the barrios ouside the centre, you will often see more walking, more flexible embrace and more elaborate figures. This has to do with the space available and the people going there. In the centre, tranditionally, the boy-meet-girl part was more important, while outside people went out with their family. Different objectives, different dancing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dancing in the barrios outside the centre is somtimes (somewhat confusingly) also called tango salón and sometimes estilo Villa Urquiza (the name of one particular barrio).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subcategories flourish, and you will invariable hear people make generalizations based on some more or less randomly chosen attribute of someone&amp;rsquo;s dance and call it a &amp;lsquo;style&amp;rsquo; (e.g. &amp;lsquo;close embrace&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;V-style&amp;rsquo; etc.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;tango-fantasía&#34;&gt;Tango fantasía&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Show tango, tango for performances or tango fantasía is tango where everything is allowed, high kicks, high boleos, ganchos, soltadas, even jumps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main purpose is to entertain the audience and to explore the possiblilities of the dance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;both-tango&#34;&gt;Both tango&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both are tango, but for different purposes. And to be appreciated accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it. The topic of style is fascinating, and people discuss it all the time. I will come back to it in later posts. But this is really all you &lt;em&gt;need to know&lt;/em&gt;.  You probably &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to know more, though. In the meantime, for readers of spanish/castellano, &lt;a href=&#34;http://enlamilonga.blogspot.com/2008/08/el-tango-explicado-mis-padres.html&#34;&gt;El tango explicado a mis padres&lt;/a&gt; is excellent.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>