<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/categories/books/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/categories/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Vero Tango Quotes</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2012/11/05/vero-tango-quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 21:28:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2012/11/05/vero-tango-quotes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/VERO.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/VERO.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;During a class.

&#34;Good. Now that you know the move, try to enjoy it.&#34;

&#34;What?&#34;

&#34;Enjoy it!&#34;

&#34;Oh shit.&#34;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blurb.fr/books/3692987/&#34;&gt;Enjoy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning the Language of Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/06/27/learning-the-language-of-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2010 17:30:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/06/27/learning-the-language-of-tango/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/simba_tango/4735758259/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4081/4735758259_6f8ae59c6a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;El tango by Simba tango, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-sa/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/simba_tango/&#34;&gt; Simba tango&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t know the language of tango, you&amp;rsquo;ll miss out on a lot, and for once, I don&amp;rsquo;t mean in a metaphorical sense. One anecdote I remember from my early days of tango was being told of a workshop that started with the following announcement:  &amp;rdquo;This is an advanced class, hence it will be taught in Spanish&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;m not sure who it supposedly was that said it, but I have a similar experience with Gustavo Naveira teaching in Buenos Aires with lots of foreigners present: &amp;ndash;Is there anyone here that speaks absolutely no Spanish? (lots of hands in the air) No Spanish at all? (fewer, but still quite a few hands in the air) Then he would go on teaching in Spanish with a few very short, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0335266/&#34;&gt;Lost in translation&lt;/a&gt;-style summaries in English every now and then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is that learning a little Spanish has been of tremendous value in the process of learning the tango. And with one noteable exception, all our main teachers the last few years have been Spanish only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember our first trip to Buenos Aires, taking classes where the instruction sounded more or less like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Blah blah blah blah blah **atras**, blah blah blah blah, **adelante **blah blah blah blah **ocho** blah blah blah....&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As time went by, the number of words we picked up grew, but atras (backwards) and adelante (forwards) and ocho were ones that stood out from the beginning. Fast forward to today, and my Spanish (well Catalan, really) colleague introduces me to a fellow Spanish guy as &amp;ldquo;the guy that speaks &lt;em&gt;Argentine&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;. A bit of an exaggeration, but still, we&amp;rsquo;ve come a long way, and it really helps connecting with people when you go there, even if they actually speak English themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some Argentines insist they speak Castellano, not Español (Spanish), this is also a lesson from our very first trip, and we generally stuck to using the word castellano, as that seemed to insult or irritate noone, and made sure we knew they were no longer a Spanish colony :-) . Anquises &lt;a href=&#34;http://zigurat-anquises.blogspot.com/2009/08/espanol-o-castellano.html&#34;&gt;argues that Español is the more correct term&lt;/a&gt;, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the process of improving one&amp;rsquo;s understanding of a language, a good dictionary is priceless. I already got the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Diccionario-Lunfardo-Spanish-Athos-Espindola/dp/9504909833&#34;&gt;dictionary of Lunfardo&lt;/a&gt;, a regular Spanish dictionary, what I was searching for was an &lt;em&gt;Argentine&lt;/em&gt; dictionary, but that turned out to be uavailable even in one of the great bookstores in Buenos Aires, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/El_Ateneo&#34;&gt;El Ateneo&lt;/a&gt;. The guy in the bookstore told us they used the Spanish ones in school and everywhere else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the Spanish dictionary will take you a long way, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t cover all the local usage. This was clearly demonstrated once as we went to the local pharmacy after looking up what we wanted in the dictionary, only to have them rolling over the counter laughing when we tried to put our newfound knowledge to work. What saved us was a little improvised acting combined with key Spanish words which finally revealed the term used in Argentina. A little body language trumps everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also there are a lot of slang expressions, and we found the slang dictionary &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Puto-El-Que-Lee-Spanish/dp/9872281203/&#34;&gt;Puto el que lee&lt;/a&gt; (diccionario argentino de insultos, injurias e improperios) in a bookstore, and found it would fill in nicely. The Argentines have an astounding number of names for prostitutes and both female and male genetalia, which all come in handy when you want to insult someone or just talk to your friends in a playful manner (¡Che, boludo!). It also has a hilarious appendix with a few tables letting you construct your own insults very easily as well as illustrations, for example covering &amp;lsquo;Grandes hijos de puta del Mundo&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;Grandísimos hijos de puta del Mundo&amp;rsquo; and correspondingly for Argentina. Unfortunately, I&amp;rsquo;m not enough into Argentine politics to get all the Argentines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, one of the last days of our last stay, we started chatting about this with our great host, and he suggested we got the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Diccionario-del-Habla-Argentinos-Spanish/dp/9500430282/&#34;&gt;Diccionario del habla de los Argentinos&lt;/a&gt;. At last. This relatively recent publication actually passed our little test of words we learnt from some of our porteño friends, and we could look them all up in the dictionary. It was too late to buy it in Buenos Aires, but we ordered it  from Argentina via Amazon. Amazing that you can actually get all of these books on Amazon! A bit more expensive, but it comes with this fuzzy feeling inside when there is mail from Argentina in the mailbox :-) The illustration photo is from this dictionary.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Music Instinct</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/04/18/the-music-instinct/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2010 19:43:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/04/18/the-music-instinct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2010/03/music-instinct.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2010/03/music-instinct.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know more about music than you think. You start picking up the rules from the day you are born, yes even before. And part of what makes music enjoyable is this knowledge of what to expect and the delight when your expectations are fulfilled, or some times bent a little before they find resolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is part of the message of a fascinating book about music, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/Music-Instinct-Works-Cant-without/dp/1847920888/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1271619437&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;The Music Instinct&lt;/a&gt; by Philip Ball, (read reviews for instance in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.economist.com/books/displaystory.cfm?story_id=15450498&#34;&gt;The Economist&lt;/a&gt;, or in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.guardian.co.uk/books/2010/feb/21/the-music-instinct-philip-ball&#34;&gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt;) a book that I finally had time to finish reading this week-end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Philip Ball has reviewed a lot of research on how our brains process music, and combines that knowledge with music theory and research in a very interesting blend. I enjoyed it a lot, and there is clearly material for quite a few posts here, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t had the time to process it all yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Already as small children we have figured out a lot of  the rules of music, but mainly about the music with which we are familiar. Ball investigates what is universal and what is based on cultural habit, how we interpret pitch, scales, melody, harmony,  rhythm, syntactic rules, semantics, the list goes on and on. In the final chapter he among other things discusses whether music can be interpreted incorrectly  &amp;ndash; fascinating topics and very relevant to tango as to all other music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A recommended read, and I&amp;rsquo;ll certainly get back to this later. Did you know that even an amoeba can respond to rhythm? Seems unlikely tango beginners could lack that ability&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Día del padre/Father&#39;s Day</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/21/d%C3%ADa-del-padre/fathers-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2009 18:14:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/21/d%C3%ADa-del-padre/fathers-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/06/daddy-kisses.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;daddy-kisses&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look what Simba got for Father&amp;rsquo;s Day! Guess which is now the favourite book for the night-time reading? Even beats &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/Thats-Dinosaur-Touchy-Feely-Board-Books/dp/0746048149&#34;&gt;That&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/Thats-Dinosaur-Touchy-Feely-Board-Books/dp/0746048149&#34;&gt;&amp;rsquo;s not my Dinosaur&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. The daddy frog and the froglet seems to be my son&amp;rsquo;s favourite part of this book, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book is by Anne Gutman and Georg Hallensleben, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chroniclebooks.com/index/main,book-info/store,BOOKS/products_id,3306/&#34;&gt;published by chronicle books&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My name is Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/03/10/my-name-is-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2009 19:54:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/03/10/my-name-is-tango/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alexbasnett/2658836298/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3194/2658836298_4957b2b6bf.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Crimson Red by Alex Basnett, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/alexbasnett/&#34;&gt; Alex Basnett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The neverending discussions of styles in tango often leave me baffled, as the idea that one is to choose one of a small number of predefined styles seems perpendicular to my idea of tango. Which is it going to be? Traditional or modern? We have to remember that tango is a quite modern dance &amp;ndash; it always was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And no book deals better with the issue of style and the clash of modern and traditional than &lt;em&gt;My name is red&lt;/em&gt; by Orhan Pamuk, the author was awarded the Nobel price of literature. While the plot is circling around the investigation of a murder, the subject matter of it is more about how the main characters, Turkish miniature painters, are torn between the modern and the traditional. Between East (traditional) and West (modern). Between following tradition, trying to achieve perfection, and developing their own style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as you probably know, the ideal in tango (modern) has always been to achieve one&amp;rsquo;s own style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to find a good quote, something about the old masters perfecting their drawing until they no longer needed eyesight to paint, so fully immersed in their body and mind was the old arts. Or one of the wonderful parables to illustrate the subtle points about style. The ones I found (it&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I first read the book) were so long, so you better read the book yourself. Maybe later, we&amp;rsquo;ll see.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why we never tire of tango music</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/29/why-we-never-tire-of-tango-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2008 22:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/29/why-we-never-tire-of-tango-music/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/nadworks/219864640/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/63/219864640_5bb97d5c4a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;MY FAVOURITE MUSIC... by nadworks, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/nadworks/&#34;&gt; nadworks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tango music for the non-argentine 21st century tango lover is often something of an acquired taste. At least for tango dancers. The recordings are old, the music sounds strange, we don&amp;rsquo;t understand the lyrics &amp;ndash; but we love the dance&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some time, we get more into the music, it all changes, and we become total fanáticos de tango, we can never get enough of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://tejastango.com/classic_tangos.html&#34;&gt;classics of tango music&lt;/a&gt;. Why do we never get tired of listening to these old recordings, often transferred from old, scratchy 78s, since &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.totango.net/rca.html&#34;&gt;the masters were burnt&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will often hear tango lovers rave about the &lt;em&gt;complexity&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;richness&lt;/em&gt; of tango music. So let us investigate a bit further what is the source of this richness. The title of the first record by the orchestra Escuela de tango, &lt;em&gt;De contrapunto&lt;/em&gt; gives us the first clue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One way to categorize music is by the musical textures, and the three main categories are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Monopohonic&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Homophonic&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Polyphonic&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monophony&#34;&gt;Monophonic&lt;/a&gt; music consists of a single melody line, and is the simplest form of musical texture. Perhaps the best known example in western music is the Gregorian chant. The monophonic music is also the easiest to understand or interpret.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Homophony&#34;&gt;Homophonic&lt;/a&gt; music is slightly more complex, as it consists of a principal melody line accompanied by a chordal accompaniment. Perhaps a bit surprisingly, it is the most recent &amp;ldquo;invention&amp;rdquo;, as it basically did not occur in music created earlier than the end of the 16th century. It was used in a lot of romantic music for increased clarity and thus emotional impact, in contrast with the most complex form, polyphony.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polyphony&#34;&gt;Polyphonic&lt;/a&gt; music is the kind that is the most demanding of the listener. Several melodic lines, or &amp;ldquo;voices&amp;rdquo;, are present at the same time, forming harmonies as they go. To appreciate this, you may have to disregard some parts of the music, and the melodic line (horizontal) will become apparent. This gives a different listening experience than &amp;ldquo;just listening&amp;rdquo; to all the sounds present at the same time (vertical). Depending on which lines you choose, the same piece may be experienced somewhat differently each time. And this is what is actually meant when dancers talk about dancing to different instruments. All voices need not be present at the same time, of course, and some melodic lines will move from instrument to instrument, so dancing different voices would be a more precise definition of what you are actually doing. (The clue from de contrapunto is that &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Counterpoint&#34;&gt;counterpoint&lt;/a&gt; is one special case of polyphonic music)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To quote Aaron Copland in the book &lt;em&gt;What to listen for in music&lt;/em&gt; (on which this post leans heavily),  &amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;repeated hearings keep up your interest better than music of homophonic texture. Even supposing that you do not hear all the separate voices equally well, there is every likelihood that when you return to it again, there will be something different for you to listen to. You can always hear it from a different angle.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pop music springs out from the homophonic tradition from the romantic music. While being popular music, tango from the golden age has a certain quality that you will not generally find in today&amp;rsquo;s popular music, the polyphony. And that also explains why it is much less interesting to dance to pop music than the real stuff. It is simply not enough to throw in some bandoneón samples or having more or less the right rhythm. More on that in a later post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The polyphonic nature of most tango music means there are a lot of ways to listen to the same tune, you can discover something new time after time. And it makes the music sound fresh every time. And thus the dance stays fresh as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Secret -- Don&#39;t tell anyone</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/11/the-secret----dont-tell-anyone/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2008 16:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/11/the-secret----dont-tell-anyone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/11/salt.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/11/salt.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main character is asked to prepare an omelet in the morning for his master, a Parisian intellectual. Feeling his cooking is underappreciated, he contemplates the intellectuals&amp;rsquo; missing reflection on his artistry in the kitchen. This is clearly about tango: (From Monique Truong&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Book of Salt:)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Like children, gullible and full of wonder, they always ask, &#34;What is your secret?&#34;

Do I look like a fool? I ask myself each time. Please, Madame, do not equate my lack of speech with a lack of thought. If there is a secret, Madame, I would take it with me to my unmarked grave, hide it in my bony jaw, the place my tongue would be if it had not rotted away. (...)

They all believe in a &#34;secret&#34; ingredient, a balm for their Gallic pride, a magic elixir that anyone can employ to duplicate my success. Its very existance threatens my own. (...) If there is a &#34;secret&#34;, Madame, it is this: Repetition and routine. Servitude and subservience. Beck and call.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should read the passage in context, it is too long to fit in a blog post, it is in the beginning of chapter 15.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS: Many thanks to my lovely wife for serving me the delicious omelet and sharing the secret. (The recipy is in the same chapter :-) )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://flickr.com/photos/wlodi/252462355/&#34;&gt;Photo&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;http://flickr.com/photos/wlodi/&#34;&gt;wlodi&lt;/a&gt;@flickr, &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/deed.en&#34;&gt;CC-licensed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Death in the Afternoon</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/24/death-in-the-afternoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2008 20:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/24/death-in-the-afternoon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/images/vicente-barrera.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Vicente Barrera&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, reading on very different topics can give deep insights in tango. &lt;em&gt;Death in the Afternoon&lt;/em&gt; by Ernest Hemingway is such a book. I thought of tango often when reading his treaty on bullfighting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While not being as deadly or controvertial as the bullfighting, tango is also a culture full of rituals and things you have to know to really appreciate. And it was the parts that was guiding the novice to understand the rich culture of bullfighting and its meaning that really made me think of tango.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hemingway is an excellent writer, of course, so it is impossible to summarize this extraordinary book in a blog post, and adding value even harder, but I will try to give an idea of what made me think of tango in this book:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed the descriptions of how people are initiated into a new world, and how this entering a different world takes place. Also how some find out that it is not for them. I have never seen a bullfight, but Hemingway suggests that I would learn very early whether it is something for me. As was the case for the tango, I knew very soon that tango was for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hemingway describes how the people new to bullfighting appreciate very different things of the drama than the connoisseur, as it takes a lot of knowledge and experience to appreciate the finer points of the art of bullfighting. While the beginner is more likely to appreciate the more flashy appearance with costumes, horses etc, appearing fairly early in the process. While the expert sees right through the crowd pleasing acts and appreciates a matador (literally &amp;lsquo;killer&amp;rsquo;) that is daring, brave and performs the act of killing with precision and without cowardry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ritual of the bullfight is also something intrigueing. There is never a happy ending. The bull always dies. If the matador cannot kill the bull, is injured or killed, the bull is still killed in the end. So while a bullfight can clearly be very exciting, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound like much fun. The bullfight goes straight into the core. Life and death. And it is very very real.  The matador is always in danger of great wounds or losing his life. The bull &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; dies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this reminded me how much I appreciate the rituals of the milongas. Coming, hearing the music from afar. The &lt;em&gt;cabeceo&lt;/em&gt;, the tandas, everybody on the floor moving as one&amp;hellip;  The chit-chat in between songs. Accompanying the lady back to her table. The tango ends, and the spell is broken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was very interesting to read about how the matadors use tricks to make the bull move closer and closer, until it is so close that the bullfighter gets blood on his clothes. The bullfighter controlling every move of the bull, only twisting his wrist or turning his torso ever so slightly. How different moves were invented by this and that bullfighter, and changed the world of bullfighting. How cowards pretend to be brave, only to be disclosed by the expert eye. The real masters. The great art. The bullfight is a staged tragedy of life and death. Maybe tango is a staged romance. Both very real indeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then you have the crowd pleasing tricks versus real skill. And the responsibility of the conoisseur. This strung a chord with the never ending tango debates on styles, favourite dancers, nuevo versus traditional.  Some advice from the old man. (And this indeed applies to tango as well):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt; ...there is one thing you can do and that is know what is good and what is bad, to appreciate the new but let nothing confuse your standards. You can continue to attend bullfights even when they are bad; but never applaud what is not good. You should, as a spectator, show your appreciation of the good and valuable work that is essential but not brilliant. You should appreciate the proper working and correct killing of a bull that is impossible to be brilliant with. A bullfighter will not be better than his audience very long. If they prefer tricks to sincerity they soon get the tricks. If a really good bullfighter is to come and to remain honest, sincere, without tricks and mystifications there must be a nucleus of spectators that he can play for when he comes.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highly recommended!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>