<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lyrics on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/categories/lyrics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lyrics on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 18:23:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/categories/lyrics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Letras de Non-Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/06/30/letras-de-non-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 18:23:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/06/30/letras-de-non-tango/</guid>
      <description>Maybe you remember my Letras de Tango post a while back, showing the most used words in tango lyrics. The possibility of doing something similar for other genres/pop music was raised in the comments. And the guys over at last.fm just did exactly that. So head over and have a look at their graphics for Blues, Country, Electronic, Folk, Goth, Hip-Hop, Indie, Metal, Rap, Rock and Soul. They also did some interesting distance charts, showing graphically how similar the lyrics of different genres are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letras de tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/03/29/letras-de-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2010 09:14:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/03/29/letras-de-tango/</guid>
      <description>We all know that tango is about lost love, broken hearts, right? Well &amp;ndash; now we can check it out. Hans at Amsterdam tango club put all the 13,000 lyrics they got in their online database in a single html file, which made it rather easy to do some statistics. I wrote a small script, counting the occurrences of each word, and the figure above is a representation of the results, but leaving the very shortest words like y, o, el, lo etc out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheek to cheek</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/22/cheek-to-cheek/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2008 17:47:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/22/cheek-to-cheek/</guid>
      <description>Heaven, I&#39;m in Heaven, And my heart beats so that I can hardly speak; And I seem to find the happiness I seek When we&#39;re out together dancing, cheek to cheek. Heaven, I&#39;m in Heaven, And the cares that hang around me thro&#39; the week Seem to vanish like a gambler&#39;s lucky streak When we&#39;re out together dancing, cheek to cheek. Oh! I love to climb a mountain, And to reach the highest peak, But it doesn&#39;t thrill me half as much As dancing cheek to cheek.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>