<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tango on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/tags/tango/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tango on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2010 20:24:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/tags/tango/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The &#39;Inventor of Jazz&#39; Plays the Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/07/14/the-inventor-of-jazz-plays-the-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2010 20:24:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/07/14/the-inventor-of-jazz-plays-the-tango/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ndash;There is this guy&amp;hellip;. and he plays the tango, too. I was at a Christmas party, sharing table with a guy that was writing his thesis on stride piano or pianists. Somehow the topic of tango had come up (strange, isn&amp;rsquo;t it?), and he was delighted to enlighten me about this early tango reference in American music. He promised to make me a copy, but that never materialized.
Nevertheless, I managed to track down the recordings myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quality and snobs</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/05/quality-and-snobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2009 02:30:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/05/quality-and-snobs/</guid>
      <description>by 96dpi
Food (and drinks) metaphors for tango seem to be popular lately, so here in another one: My brother and I have two very distinct wine quality stories that I find very amusing when seen together. Each involves a young woman, at the age where going to parties and flirting with alcohol is at its most exciting, somewhere just before or just after going to university.
#1: A rather simple red wine was served with the main dish at a dinner party with the entire class of that year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mickey Mouse -- The Gallopin&#39; Gaucho (1928)</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/10/mickey-mouse-the-gallopin-gaucho-1928/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2009 03:02:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/10/mickey-mouse-the-gallopin-gaucho-1928/</guid>
      <description>HT: ShelleyDelaine</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cadencia</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/23/cadencia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2009 01:01:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/23/cadencia/</guid>
      <description>by Kanaka&amp;rsquo;s Paradise Life in Hawaii
If you have to ask, you will never know.   _Luis Armstrong when asked &#39;what is jazz?&#39;_    &amp;ndash;You see, that is not the way to make it &amp;lsquo;swing&amp;rsquo; in tango. I was looking out onto the group of people standing around us with question marks painted all over their faces. &amp;ndash;Well, I don&amp;rsquo;t know the right word, but the corresponding to swing in tango.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The dual nature of tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/04/the-dual-nature-of-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2009 02:49:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/04/the-dual-nature-of-tango/</guid>
      <description>by airpark
I often wonder why tango is so attractive, why I (and others with me) got so obsessed with it. Why we never tire of it.
In part, I think it has to do with the infinite depth that can be found within it, and part of the source of this I believe is the dual nature of tango, or its apparent paradoxes. Making it difficult to explain or describe what tango is and isn&amp;rsquo;t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>White powder vs. Tango Argentino</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/21/white-powder-vs-tango-argentino/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2009 14:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/21/white-powder-vs-tango-argentino/</guid>
      <description>Powder Mountain Perspective from Ian Provo on Vimeo.
Common (could be pro or con, depending&amp;hellip;):
 Balance
 Rhythm
 Dissociation
 Improvisation
 Flow
 Max 12 min. rush
 Addictive
  Skiing pros  Fresh air
 Beautiful mountains
 Keeps you in shape
  Skiing cons  Avalanches
 Weather dependent
 Cold, dress accordingly
 Tough ascents
 Heavy on the knees
 Practical clothing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost there</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/21/almost-there/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2008 12:03:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/21/almost-there/</guid>
      <description>by patsun They say it takes 10 years learning to walk&amp;hellip; Almost there ;-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Masquerade</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/31/masquerade/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2008 21:07:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/31/masquerade/</guid>
      <description>Who are you when you are dancing? Are you the leader? The follower? The man? The woman? I was once confronted with my using the terminology man/woman in class. The person complaining said that she was dancing a role (she was dancing the man&amp;rsquo;s part) and that was the role of the leader.
I know this easily gets messy, but I never liked the euphemism leader/follower when what we are talking about is a man and a woman in most cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why so serious?</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/17/why-so-serious/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2008 21:50:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/17/why-so-serious/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes people are complaining that tango dancers are oh so serious. Never smiling or laughing. Relax, and have som fun, why so serious?
For me, I have always had a hard time agreeing on tango being fun. Of course it can be great fun, especially milonga, but not primarily fun. Fun actually has very little to do with it. That is not to say that I do not enjoy tango, on the contrary, I enjoy it very much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More on less</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/21/more-on-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2008 20:30:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/21/more-on-less/</guid>
      <description>I just read an interview with this year&amp;rsquo;s campeones, Daniel Nacucchio &amp;amp; Cristina Sosa (congratulations, and nice to see Neri &amp;amp; Yanina did well also :-) - Well, he quoted old milonguero wisdom:
El que menos hace, a veces es el que hace más Which means something like, the one who does less, sometimes is the one that does more. (Forgive my translation, neither Spanish nor English is my native language).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passing judgement</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/05/passing-judgement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 20:17:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/05/passing-judgement/</guid>
      <description>It seems to be a popular activity among tango enthusasts, dissing all the dancers you don&amp;rsquo;t really like, especially teachers of course, and explain what everybody else does wrong. (Of course, we all do everything right ourselves ;-)
Sometimes it gets a bit out of hand, and can spread some negative energy, in particular when there is disagreement of who is in and who is out on a table at the milonga or in a small community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>El último bandoneón</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/22/la-ultima-bandoneon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2008 10:15:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/22/la-ultima-bandoneon/</guid>
      <description>httpvh://youtube.com/watch?v=eGerxiMniBQ
Maravillosa!
Now where can I get the entire film?
Trailer here:
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clichés</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/06/cliches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2008 10:31:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/06/cliches/</guid>
      <description>Ever since I started dancing, the topic of tango clichés has fascinated me. The rose in mouth, castanets, head flicks, dramatic poses are all parts of what usually pops into people&amp;rsquo;s heads when they hear the word tango. Where did they come from, and why did they stick? Going through a lot of Hollywood production at least gives a partial answer, and Rudolph Valentino is one of the people to blame, the rose in mouth appears in the film Blood and sand, where he plays a bullfighter, while the film he dances the tango is _Four horsemen of the apocalypse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gavito Dixit</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/06/01/gavito-dixit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 15:26:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/06/01/gavito-dixit/</guid>
      <description>Gavito Dixit I ¿Bailaste el tango de tu vida esta noche? No bailes más… El tangauta #129
Gavito Dixit II El tango está entre paso y paso, allí donde se escuchan los silencios y cantan las musas. El tangauta #130
Gavito Dixit III El hombre debe saber que baila para ella,y al hacerlo, hace que ella se vea como una reina. Sólo así será el rey. El tangauta #131</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>