<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ambience on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>https://simbatango.github.io/tags/ambience/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ambience on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="https://simbatango.github.io/tags/ambience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Entering the milonga</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2008/12/17/entering-the-milonga/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2008 15:45:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2008/12/17/entering-the-milonga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/untitlism/2547423465/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3078/2547423465_f1db2aefc9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Resurrection by Untitled blue, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/untitlism/&#34;&gt; Untitled blue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The moment or should I say process of entering a milonga is very special for me. I think savoring the moment is something very important in tango, and for me it starts at the moment I am standing outside the milonga entrance. There is a certain amount of expectation for the night even before, of course, but this is when I really start enjoying the sensation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I move into the building, the sound of music becomes more clear, maybe the dj plays a nice song, and I get this uplifted feeling, raising the expectations for the night. This is even more exciting for unknown milongas, but it goes for my regular milongas as well. I just love when I have to climb some stairs to get to the milonga (think Niño Bien), feeling the music getting stronger with each step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After entering the venue, I prefer taking a moment in the back, watching the floor. How is the mood today, who&amp;rsquo;s dancing, is it crowded, or will I there be space for the occacional caminata? Are any of my favorite dancers present, and if so, am I able to locate where they sit? I am now taking the first small steps towards taking action: finding a table, determining whom to ask (with the cabeceo, of course) to dance. If my friends are not dancing, I greet them and might sit at their table. If possible I change my shoes before entering, else I do it as discreetly as possible while taking in the mood of the night. Getting ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all milongas where they serve drinks, I get something to drink, a beer, maybe some champagne, and have a taste while I watch the floor and listen to the music. &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2008/11/18/waiting-for-the-right-moment/&#34;&gt;Waiting for the right moment&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to write about this special moment for some time, and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://enlamilonga.blogspot.com/2008/12/los-rituales-de-la-llegada.html&#34;&gt;challenge of una tanguera&lt;/a&gt; made it irresistable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>