<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>El Turco Jose on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/tags/el-turco-jose/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in El Turco Jose on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/tags/el-turco-jose/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Adiós Maestro</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/04/18/adios-maestro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2010 19:03:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/04/18/adios-maestro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/simba_tango/3331310852/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3559/3331310852_2861dde337.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sunderland (empty) by Simba tango, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/simba_tango/&#34;&gt; Simba tango&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friday morning brought more sad news from Buenos Aires. It is time to complete the biography of &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2010/02/14/el-turco-jose-brahemcha/&#34;&gt;El &amp;ldquo;Turco&amp;rdquo; José Brahemcha&lt;/a&gt;. Another great milonguero is gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He had been sick for a while, so in a sense it was no surprise, and we did wonder if we were ever to see him again as we parted for the last time from his apartment in Buenos Aires. That he is gone only a few months later is hard to believe, nevertheless. The memories are still so fresh. José smiling peacefully from his chair. Truly and deeply missed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Que en paz descanse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;José Brahemcha (July 7 1931 - April 15 2010)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;El Turco&#34; José Brahemcha -- a short biography</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/03/09/el-turco-jose-brahemcha-a-short-biography/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2010 19:23:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/03/09/el-turco-jose-brahemcha-a-short-biography/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2010/03/jose-bw.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2010/03/jose-bw.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;El &#34;Turco&#34; José -- as he is commonly known -- was born in  Buenos Aires, in the neighborhood of  Saavedra, July 17 1931.  He was a dedicated bicycle rider when he was a kid, until his mother (who was a tango singer) suggested that he learn to dance &#34;to get to know some girls&#34;.  At the age of 16, he started to practice with his friends from his neighborhood in the house of one of them, where they had a gramophone player.

They had only one shellac disc with two Pugliese recordings: &#34;La Yumba&#34; on one side, and the milonga &#34;Andá que te cure Lola&#34; on the other.  They were practicing what they remembered from the dance from the movies or what they had seen at the neighborhood dances. When he knew a little, he started to go to the dances and carnivals in the club  &#34;Ausonia Montañeses&#34; in Colegiales.

El Turco worked with wicker, making fine objects like purses. As he wished to learn more dancing, a friend from his work, who already danced, recommended him to go to the practices where people usually learned to dance.  Thus, for some time he went with his uncle in the neighborhood of Martelli to the practices in the clubs, among them the &#34;Huracán&#34; (The hurricane).

The practices were held in the basket courts and they were full of men learning to follow, how to lead, the salida (basic step) and lots of others figures of tango. Later, he returned to the neighborhood of Urquiza, and since he liked that elegant style especially, he studied how &#34;Milonguita&#34; danced in particular, and adapted to his way of dancing.

José&#39;s style can be described as a tango of the floor, with a great variety of original figures and a smooth and elegant way of moving with energy and precision,  the figures always in harmony with the music. Presently he is dedicated to teaching private lessons and group lessons all over the country as well as abroad.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humbly translated by yours truly. This is the original text as posted on  the now defunct website of the Academia de Estilos de Tango Argentino (ACETA):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;El &#34;Turco&#34; José -- como habitualmente se lo conoce -- nació en Buenos Aires, en el barrio de Saavedra, el 17 de julio de 1931. De dedicó desde chico al ciclismo hasta que su madre (que cantaba tangos) le sugiró que aprendiese a bailar &#34;para relacionarse con las chicas&#34;. A los 16 años, junto a los amigos del barrio, empezaron a practicar en la casa de uno de ellos que tenía fonola.

Tenían un solo disco de pasta que conenía dos grabaciones de Pugliese: &#34;La Yumba&#34; de un lado y la milonga &#34;Andá que te cure Lola&#34; del otro. Practicaban según lo que recordaban del baile de alguna película o lo que veían en los bailes de barrio. Ya sabiendo un poco, empezó a frecuentar bailes en los carnavales del club &#34;Ausonia Montañeses&#34; en el barrio de Colegiales.

El Turco trabajó haciendo bomboneras de mimbre y más adelante armando carteras y otros objetos finos en mimbre. Como tenía intención de aprender a bailar más, un amigo de ese trabajo (que ya bailaba) le recomendó ir a las prácticas que en ese entonces se solían hacer. Así que durante algun tiempo frecuentó junto a su tío en Villa Martelli las prácticas que se realizaban en los clubes, entre ellos &#34;Huracán&#34;.

José cuenta que se hacían en las canchas de básket y que estaban repletas de varones aprendiendo a ser llevados, cómo llevar, la marca, la salida, y tantas otras figuras del tango. Más adelante volvió al barrio de Urquiza y gustándole sobre todo ese estilo elegante, estudió en particular el modo de bailar de &#34;Milonguita&#34;, adaptándalo a su manera.

Su estilo puede definirse como un tango al piso, con una gran variedad de figuras originales y un modo de moverse suave y elegante con energía y precisión, armonizando las figuras con la música.  Actualmente se dedica a enseñar en clases particulares y a grupos tanto en el país como en el exterior.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to&lt;a href=&#34;http://jantango.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt; Janis&lt;/a&gt; for saving and sharing it.  As always, I appreciate any contribution to improve the translation. Especially the part about the wicker bombonera (it only rings a bell as the CABJ stadium to me) and the llevados/llevar/marca part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fourth seminar with José is March 14, so if you are in Bs As at that time, you know what to do&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;El Turco&#39; José Brahemcha</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/14/el-turco-jose-brahemcha/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2010 11:38:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/14/el-turco-jose-brahemcha/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/QU3zfxcNuHs&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I have only one great regret in tango, and that it not taking classes with Gavito. Of course there are others as well, but with Gavito we had the opportunity, we passed, and shame on us for it. Of course, at the time we simply didn&amp;rsquo;t know better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Determined not to make same mistake again, we decided to take our teachers&amp;rsquo; advice and try to get in touch with the legendary &amp;lsquo;El Turco&amp;rsquo; José. Master of &amp;lsquo;Estilo Villa Urquiza&amp;rsquo;. I originally thought he did not teach anymore, but in fact Jorge Dispari was hosting a workshop with his old master just days before we arrived in Buenos Aires. Then another one days after we left. Que mala suerte!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were not really planning on taking much lessons at all, but we couldn&amp;rsquo;t just let it go with that, so I got his number, called him up, and made an appointment with his lovely wife. And off we went.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will often hear the term maestro of maestros in the tango world. But rarely does it apply as well as with José. In my case, you could say he&amp;rsquo;s the maestro del maestro del maestro..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, he can&amp;rsquo;t dance himself anymore, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop him. When you see how he demonstrates with his feet, caressing the floor like no one else I&amp;rsquo;ve seen, you realize what an amazing dancer is in front of you. Simply a privilege to have the opportunity to learn from such an extraordinary man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first things he asked was: Which music do you like to dance to? No hesitation, straight to the core: the music. Whenever I hear the song Cascabelito, I think of José. It was on all three cds we used while practicing on his living room floor. Vargas. Di Sarli. Pugliese.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;José is famous for his sublime subtlety, and would not stop until we got it exactly right. We demonstrated. &amp;ndash;No. he would say. Again. &amp;ndash;No. Until we finally got it. &amp;ndash;You have to practice this a lot, he would say. &amp;ndash;Make sure to take notes or film it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;José would sit in his chair, smiling, but with the sharp eyes cultivated to reveal the finer points of tango since he was young, learning to dance mainly by watching the more experienced dancers. We would talk about the tango before and now, and his passion for this dance would lighten his eyes, eager to bring the tango he loves on to new generations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the things he showed us were absolutely gorgeous. Yielding very nice sentiments as well as elegance and finesse. The first day we did corrections.&amp;ndash;You want to learn the Villa Urquiza style? he asked. &amp;ndash;Then you cannot do like that. It should be like this. Despacio.. (do it slowly). The last day we did nothing but walking exercises. It will take a lot of practice to internalize it all, but it will be well worth the extra effort. Dancing the tango of José is far from easy. Oh, do I hope there will be more opportunities to learn from this great master again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This rare footage of José dancing was published by his daughter Laura on facebook. It is from the Sunday milonga upstairs at Sunderland, organized by the late Lampazo. Jorge Dispari was giving the introduction as well as djing there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jorge Dispari is hosting another class with José in Buenos Aires February 21st.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>