<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Milongueros on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/tags/milongueros/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Milongueros on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/tags/milongueros/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution?</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/04/27/evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2010 20:35:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/04/27/evolution/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/bQb7JWpEVRo&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I hear it every so often: that tango technique, especially for women, has gone through a tremendous evolution since the resurgence in the early 1980s. Let&amp;rsquo;s just say I&amp;rsquo;m not quite convinced. Watch this clip from the 1988 movie &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0096221/&#34;&gt;Tango Bar&lt;/a&gt;, and draw your own conclusions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treating the symptoms</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/06/treating-the-symptoms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2009 00:41:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/06/treating-the-symptoms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/dradd/2410180992/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2175/2410180992_402a6c1c23.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Pill Mosaic Redux II by Dradd., on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/dradd/&#34;&gt; Dradd.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a laugh when I read &lt;a href=&#34;http://movementinvitesmovement.wordpress.com/2009/11/26/sweating-and-tango-something-is-wrong/&#34;&gt;this part&lt;/a&gt; by MovementInvitesMovement. In their wonderful, provocative style, they wrote an entire post about something that I hinted at &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/11/06/tailored-for-tango/#comment-473&#34;&gt;in a comment&lt;/a&gt; in my &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/11/06/tailored-for-tango/&#34;&gt;post about clothes and tango&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Some hard core dancers would say that if it gets too warm with the jacket on, you are waisting energy ![;-)](http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif)&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When my beloved wife read that, her immediate reaction was: &lt;strong&gt;hard core dancers&lt;/strong&gt;? Why didn&amp;rsquo;t you write &lt;strong&gt;milonguero&lt;/strong&gt;? I see her point, while in our household, they can be considered synonyms, it opens for misunderstandings. Isn&amp;rsquo;t the clueless guy spinning around like a ventilador (we all know how that &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/11/24/hola-papa-noel/&#34;&gt;may turn out&lt;/a&gt;) from festival to festival hard core? Milonguero resolves the ambiguity elegantly by removing the cluelessness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I sometimes wonder if this obsession with sweat is an anglo-american thing, as all the posts I can remember about this have been from that cultural sphere, but that is probably just exposing my prejudice. Of course, you should take the natural precautions, just as everywhere else, but if you have to resort to sportswear to keep dry&amp;hellip; I said it before, and I will repeat it now: Going to a milonga means &lt;strong&gt;going out&lt;/strong&gt;, not, I repeat: &lt;strong&gt;NOT work out&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While learning to dance tango certainly takes a lot of effort, dancing in a social context doesn&amp;rsquo;t really require much effort. On stage is a different matter, of course, but there is an awful lot of steps and sequences you can do without getting all wet if you do it right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One practical tip for those of you still tempted to just numb your body and go on as before: work on your pivots. Yes gentlemen, I am talking to you. It is frustrating to see so called advanced dancers throwing themselves and their partner around in order to make the next step of the giro on the beat, when all it takes is a little pivot. I don&amp;rsquo;t know about &amp;lsquo;most efficient&amp;rsquo;, but certainly a lot more efficient and clearly a lot more elegant.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homenaje a los milongueros -- the show</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/10/homenaje-a-los-milongueros----the-show/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2009 02:30:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/10/homenaje-a-los-milongueros----the-show/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Marisa Galindo was directing a show in honor of the milongueros, and she is now &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/user/galindomarisa3971&#34;&gt;posting footage from this show on youtube&lt;/a&gt; for all of us to see! The show was filmed on the 16th of October 1991, Homenaje a los Milongueros de Buenos Aires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have seen fragments of this show before, but didn&amp;rsquo;t know the source, and this seems to be much better quality and I think complete. Truth to be told, I haven&amp;rsquo;t had  time to watch it all yet, but I will, and I will watch it again. And again. And so should you, haha!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;httpv://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ph6XGNTea9c&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;httpv://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YVnLoZj9VzI&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;httpv://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ktdMg_Mzs0w&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;httpv://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PbECyyIEzIg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HT: &lt;a href=&#34;http://jantango.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;Janis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homenaje a los milongueros</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/16/homenaje-a-los-milongueros/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2009 02:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/16/homenaje-a-los-milongueros/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/simba_tango/3724775725/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2424/3724775725_887e20fde6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Bienvenidos al Club Sin Rumbo by Simba tango, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/simba_tango/&#34;&gt; Simba tango&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you enter the &lt;em&gt;cathedral of tango&lt;/em&gt;, the milonga &lt;strong&gt;Sin Rumbo&lt;/strong&gt;, among the things hanging on the wall is this piece written by Marisa Galindo as a homage to the milongueros. It may serve as guiding principles or ideals for all tango dancers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;los-milongueros&#34;&gt;Los milongueros&amp;hellip;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;son quienes saben hacer la ronda&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;son quienes un oido musical increible&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;son los que conocen cada orquesta y a sus cantores y a veces cantan despacito al oído.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;son quienes con poco despliegue coreográfico producen un fuerte intercambio de emociones y de placer, que a veces se transforma en éxtasis, cuando desde el rol femenino, podés cerrar los ojos en una entrega total.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;son suaves y precisos en la marcación, marcan con todo cuerpo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;cuidan a los mujeres para no sean golpeados&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;bailan para él y para ella, no para el público&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;respetan al grupo evitando las figuras que son peligrosas en la pista: ganchos, boleadas, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;su rítmo, las variaciones rítmicas y sus pausas están en contacto con la música, con la mujer y con los otros bailarines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A rough translation would be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-milongueros&#34;&gt;The milongueros&amp;hellip;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;know how to make the dance flow well on the floor&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;have amazing ears for music&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;know each orchestra and singer and will somtimes sing quietly in your ear&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;create great emotional variations and pleasure by using simple coreographic elements, that sometimes transforms into ecstasy, when the woman can close her eyes in total surrender&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;are soft and precise in their lead, using their entire body to lead&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;protect the women so they are not pushed or kicked&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;dance for him and for her, not for the crowd watching&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;respect the other dancers by avoiding dangerous figures like ganchos and boleos (kicks) on the dance floor&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;their rhythm, rhytmical variations and pauses are connected with the music, with the woman and with the other dancers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Venturing once more into the perilous landscape of translations.. I tried being a bit less literal in my translation this time. I took the liberty of substituting rol feminino with woman, as I had trouble avoiding awkward constructs. I think this is the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve seen this expression used in castellano, usually the teachers will stick to the terms man (hombre) and woman (mujer).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I studied foreign languages in high school, we  would invariably translate short texts, so in a way this crazy project makes some sense. (Hopefully improving my castellano.) Maybe I will dare try translating the &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2008/06/01/gavito-dixit/&#34;&gt;Gavito dixit&lt;/a&gt; sometime&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>