<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Milongueros on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/tags/milongueros/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Milongueros on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2010 20:35:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/tags/milongueros/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution?</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/04/27/evolution-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2010 20:35:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/04/27/evolution-2/</guid>
      <description>I hear it every so often: that tango technique, especially for women, has gone through a tremendous evolution since the resurgence in the early 1980s. Let&amp;rsquo;s just say I&amp;rsquo;m not quite convinced. Watch this clip from the 1988 movie Tango Bar, and draw your own conclusions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treating the symptoms</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/06/treating-the-symptoms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2009 00:41:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/06/treating-the-symptoms/</guid>
      <description>by Dradd.
I had a laugh when I read this part by MovementInvitesMovement. In their wonderful, provocative style, they wrote an entire post about something that I hinted at in a comment in my post about clothes and tango.
Some hard core dancers would say that if it gets too warm with the jacket on, you are waisting energy ![;-)](http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif) When my beloved wife read that, her immediate reaction was: hard core dancers?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homenaje a los milongueros -- the show</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/10/homenaje-a-los-milongueros-the-show/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2009 02:30:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/10/homenaje-a-los-milongueros-the-show/</guid>
      <description>Marisa Galindo was directing a show in honor of the milongueros, and she is now posting footage from this show on youtube for all of us to see! The show was filmed on the 16th of October 1991, Homenaje a los Milongueros de Buenos Aires.
I have seen fragments of this show before, but didn&amp;rsquo;t know the source, and this seems to be much better quality and I think complete. Truth to be told, I haven&amp;rsquo;t had time to watch it all yet, but I will, and I will watch it again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homenaje a los milongueros</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/16/homenaje-a-los-milongueros/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2009 02:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/16/homenaje-a-los-milongueros/</guid>
      <description>by Simba tango
As you enter the cathedral of tango, the milonga Sin Rumbo, among the things hanging on the wall is this piece written by Marisa Galindo as a homage to the milongueros. It may serve as guiding principles or ideals for all tango dancers:
Los milongueros&amp;hellip;  son quienes saben hacer la ronda
 son quienes un oido musical increible
 son los que conocen cada orquesta y a sus cantores y a veces cantan despacito al oído.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>