<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Codigos De La Milonga on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>https://simbatango.github.io/tags/codigos-de-la-milonga/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Codigos De La Milonga on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="https://simbatango.github.io/tags/codigos-de-la-milonga/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Resistance</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/07/26/the-resistance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2009 00:42:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/07/26/the-resistance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/mirsasha/92364080/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/42/92364080_db1cccacc2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Wall of flyers by mirsasha, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/mirsasha/&#34;&gt; mirsasha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tangocommuter1.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Tangocommuter&lt;/a&gt; is constructive and a man of action. Simba likes that. Following up on his own idea to distribute the &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/07/15/homenaje-a-los-milongueros/&#34;&gt;homage to the milongueros&lt;/a&gt;, he has created  a &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/sin-rumbo.pdf&#34;&gt;flyer&lt;/a&gt;, and I am happy to host it here at simbatango.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenge is, in his own words:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

&gt; 
&gt; (...) print out a lot of copies, with an attractive picture, perhaps that of the entrance to Sin Rumbo, so that it looks like a regular leaflet, to leave on the table at the entry of every milonga we go to…
&gt; 
&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quietly sneaking in a little education in the milongas. Nonobtrusive. Quite neat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we need your help. Print out a handful of &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/sin-rumbo.pdf&#34;&gt;tangocommuter&amp;rsquo;s flyer&lt;/a&gt;, and leave it at your local milonga. Or make your own design if you prefer. You may use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/simba_tango&#34;&gt;my images at flickr&lt;/a&gt; (with a &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;cc license&lt;/a&gt;) or find someone else&amp;rsquo;s or make something yourself. Suggestions for improvements and new versions are most welcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And please do keep us updated on your success&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EDIT: New version from Tangocommuter, &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/sinrumbo.pdf&#34;&gt;this prints four leaflets on one page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homenaje a los milongueros</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/07/16/homenaje-a-los-milongueros/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2009 02:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/07/16/homenaje-a-los-milongueros/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/simba_tango/3724775725/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2424/3724775725_887e20fde6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Bienvenidos al Club Sin Rumbo by Simba tango, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/simba_tango/&#34;&gt; Simba tango&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you enter the &lt;em&gt;cathedral of tango&lt;/em&gt;, the milonga &lt;strong&gt;Sin Rumbo&lt;/strong&gt;, among the things hanging on the wall is this piece written by Marisa Galindo as a homage to the milongueros. It may serve as guiding principles or ideals for all tango dancers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;los-milongueros&#34;&gt;Los milongueros&amp;hellip;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;son quienes saben hacer la ronda&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;son quienes un oido musical increible&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;son los que conocen cada orquesta y a sus cantores y a veces cantan despacito al oído.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;son quienes con poco despliegue coreográfico producen un fuerte intercambio de emociones y de placer, que a veces se transforma en éxtasis, cuando desde el rol femenino, podés cerrar los ojos en una entrega total.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;son suaves y precisos en la marcación, marcan con todo cuerpo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;cuidan a los mujeres para no sean golpeados&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;bailan para él y para ella, no para el público&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;respetan al grupo evitando las figuras que son peligrosas en la pista: ganchos, boleadas, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;su rítmo, las variaciones rítmicas y sus pausas están en contacto con la música, con la mujer y con los otros bailarines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A rough translation would be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-milongueros&#34;&gt;The milongueros&amp;hellip;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;know how to make the dance flow well on the floor&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;have amazing ears for music&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;know each orchestra and singer and will somtimes sing quietly in your ear&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;create great emotional variations and pleasure by using simple coreographic elements, that sometimes transforms into ecstasy, when the woman can close her eyes in total surrender&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;are soft and precise in their lead, using their entire body to lead&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;protect the women so they are not pushed or kicked&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;dance for him and for her, not for the crowd watching&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;respect the other dancers by avoiding dangerous figures like ganchos and boleos (kicks) on the dance floor&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;their rhythm, rhytmical variations and pauses are connected with the music, with the woman and with the other dancers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Venturing once more into the perilous landscape of translations.. I tried being a bit less literal in my translation this time. I took the liberty of substituting rol feminino with woman, as I had trouble avoiding awkward constructs. I think this is the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve seen this expression used in castellano, usually the teachers will stick to the terms man (hombre) and woman (mujer).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I studied foreign languages in high school, we  would invariably translate short texts, so in a way this crazy project makes some sense. (Hopefully improving my castellano.) Maybe I will dare try translating the &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2008/06/01/gavito-dixit/&#34;&gt;Gavito dixit&lt;/a&gt; sometime&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The code</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/01/25/the-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2009 10:56:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/01/25/the-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/anthonygrimley/116867237/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/51/116867237_9a18590294.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Red no entry sign by anthonygrimley, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/anthonygrimley/&#34;&gt; anthonygrimley&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be difficult to learn tango. In addition to learning to know the music, leading and following and the basic vocabulary, there are the rules. So many rules to remember. Or codigos, as some prefer to call them. Codigos de la milonga.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there are some that think way too much attention devoted to these &amp;ldquo;rules&amp;rdquo;. Ancient rules from Buenos Aires, we can manage very well without them, thankyouverymuch. In our country, we do it our way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What these people fail to understand is that what they see as rigid rules from a distant time is only &lt;em&gt;common sense&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;simple courtesy&lt;/em&gt;. I know courtesy is out of fashion these days, but here is your wake-up call: so is couple dancing! And they go together, the two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is astonishing that one has to teach grown up individuals, tell them explicitly that one should not kick the others on the dance floor, respect a no for a no and in general behave like  grown ups. And even more startling: after being taught these things, people still do it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yes honey, but is it tango?</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2008/12/04/yes-honey-but-is-it-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2008 15:58:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2008/12/04/yes-honey-but-is-it-tango/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/11/roy-lichtenstein.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/11/roy-lichtenstein.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Roy Lichtenstein: Girl with Ribbon (1965)&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Roy Lichtenstein: Girl with Ribbon (1965)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is always a lot of fuzz in the tango communities of the world about what is the right tango. And rightly so. There is good and there is bad tango.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in the middle of these heated arguments, we need to remind ourselves of one thing. Tango culture is rich. There is a lot of diversity in tango. Tango is not only dance. It is also music for listening. Tango song is a world of its own. Tango dance is not only for the milonga, but also for the stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One possible source of much of the confusion is that people are unaware of both the richness and the suitness for different purposes. Explore the possibilities and adjust according to circumstances. Nobody minds you practicing lifts or jumps or ganchos or volcadas or whatever you are into. Just behave on the dancefloor. Simple, really.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://enlamilonga.blogspot.com/2008/08/entonces-es-o-no-es-tango.html&#34;&gt;This article by Una milonguera&lt;/a&gt; is also recommended for readers of spanish/castellano.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>