<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Walk on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/tags/walk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Walk on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2010 17:51:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/tags/walk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Experiment shows: walking heel first more efficient</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/16/experiment-shows-walking-heel-first-more-efficient/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2010 17:51:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/16/experiment-shows-walking-heel-first-more-efficient/</guid>
      <description>This will not, of course, settle the agelong debate of whether to walk toe first or heel first in tango. Still, I found it interesting that there has recently been published research on the efficiency of the human walk, specifically investigating walking heel first versus walking toe first. If you are striving for the most efficient walk, their conclusion might be worth noting:
   When human subjects walked with their heels slightly elevated in a ‘low-digitigrade’[toe first] posture, COT [cost of transport] increased by 53% above that of normal plantigrade [heel first] walking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking on high heels</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/04/walking-on-high-heels/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2009 02:10:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/04/walking-on-high-heels/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;599&amp;rdquo; caption=&amp;ldquo;Cinderella discovers the risk involved in dancing too wildly while wearing glass shoes&amp;rdquo;][/caption]
Sure he was great, but don&#39;t forget that Ginger Rogers did everything he did, backwards... and in high heels. I had the pleasure of dancing with a woman in Buenos Aires who really knew how to operate her feet. She worked in television in her country, and was known as &amp;rsquo;the woman that knows how to walk on high heels&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to walk</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/11/learning-to-walk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2009 13:15:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/11/learning-to-walk/</guid>
      <description>by Café du Monde
After spending a lot of time relearning how to walk, and teaching others to do the same, it is refreshing to watch a (very) young man learning to walk, in fact learning basically everything.
Following him from being unable to hold his own head, through rolling around and sitting up, getting up by means of whatever furniture or grown up legs are in his proximity is fascinating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ROOOAAAAAAAAARRR!!!</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/24/roooaaaaaaaaarrr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2009 01:26:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/24/roooaaaaaaaaarrr/</guid>
      <description>by Tambako the Jaguar
Simba.. is trapped in a cage. Yes, he has youtube, he has his music collection. But something is missing. Grrrrrrr.
Will someone please take Simba for a walk. A Di Sarli walk. Or if that&amp;rsquo;s not possible, maybe some comforting words&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A morir</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/19/a-morir/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2009 01:24:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/19/a-morir/</guid>
      <description>by Xanboozled
   _--When a man walks nicely, the woman dies in his embrace._   --_When a man walks badly, the woman wants to die._ HT: yy</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost there</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/21/almost-there/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2008 12:03:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/21/almost-there/</guid>
      <description>by patsun They say it takes 10 years learning to walk&amp;hellip; Almost there ;-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waiting for the right moment</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/18/waiting-for-the-right-moment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2008 17:57:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/18/waiting-for-the-right-moment/</guid>
      <description>by just.Luc
   -I see a lot of men are not dancing. They can&#39;t manage to dance when the floor is so full of people.     -It may not be because of lack of ability. It may be because they enjoy the dance more when the floor is not packed and they can more around the floor in their dance. Maybe they are waiting for their favorite music.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the eye of the beholder</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/06/in-the-eye-of-the-beholder/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2008 17:31:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/06/in-the-eye-of-the-beholder/</guid>
      <description>Isn&amp;rsquo;t it funny how we see so different things, even when watching the exact same event?

I remember seeing containers all over the place while we were renovating our appartment, a friend who is an architect and carpenter seemed to literally see through the walls in the house before we bought it. A trained art expert will instantly recognize the work of an artist, an analyst will see through the endless rows of numbers in a spreadsheet&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Putting the baby to sleep</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/14/putting-the-baby-to-sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 20:49:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/14/putting-the-baby-to-sleep/</guid>
      <description>I quite recently became a father, and the poor child is exposed to a lot of tango music, naturally. (And I get out to dance less, hence the blog writing.) Before he was born, I used to talk about how we would practice walking together, he and I. Now this is how it turned out:
The scene: Unpatiant 12 days old boy, waiting for his mother to get ready for breast-feeding.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>