<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dj on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/categories/dj/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dj on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 19:43:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/categories/dj/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Los estilos fundamentales del tango por Ignacio Varchausky | Alfredo Gobbi</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2015/10/26/los-estilos-fundamentales-del-tango-por-ignacio-varchausky-alfredo-gobbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 19:43:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2015/10/26/los-estilos-fundamentales-del-tango-por-ignacio-varchausky-alfredo-gobbi/</guid>
      <description>The Gobbi seminar video is up!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Los estilos fundamentales del tango por Ignacio Varchausky | Horacio Salgán</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2015/09/19/los-estilos-fundamentales-del-tango-por-ignacio-varchausky-horacio-salgan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2015 15:40:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2015/09/19/los-estilos-fundamentales-del-tango-por-ignacio-varchausky-horacio-salgan/</guid>
      <description>This time with video. Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Los estilos fundamentales del tango por Ignacio Varchausky</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2015/08/23/los-estilos-fundamentales-del-tango-por-ignacio-varchausky/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2015 19:01:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2015/08/23/los-estilos-fundamentales-del-tango-por-ignacio-varchausky/</guid>
      <description>Ignacio Varchausky is doing a series of very interesting seminars on the style of different tango orchestras. Audio recordings of the seminars have been released with links in the facebook comments, and that means an opportunity to listen to them even when very lejos de Buenos Aires. They are in Spanish though, so you need to follow spoken Spanish reasonably well to make any use of it.
Apparently, they build on a seminar similar to the one that inspired this post on how to listen to tango, so you might want to check out that first, if you haven&amp;rsquo;t already.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rise of the Tango DJ</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2014/09/05/the-rise-of-the-tango-dj/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2014 10:46:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2014/09/05/the-rise-of-the-tango-dj/</guid>
      <description>by sebastien.barre
I am thrilled to see the increased interest in djing and playing quality tango music for dancers the last few years. In trying to understand how it all came about, it is tempting to focus on the efforts of individuals to bring good dance music to their local community, but thereby we might miss the big picture.
Technological and economic changes can be transformative. Some of the most famous examples from the world of tango are the invention of the electrical recorder/the microphone, the fierce competition between orchestras during the golden age of tango and the selective pressure following from men largely outnumbering women in the milongas as the dance developed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Felix Picherna | Tengo una pregunta para vos</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2014/09/02/felix-picherna-tengo-una-pregunta-para-vos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 19:37:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2014/09/02/felix-picherna-tengo-una-pregunta-para-vos/</guid>
      <description>Felix Picherna is a legend, and he was clearly the first tango dj to make a lasting impression in me. Sitting with his cassette deck, rewinding the prepared tandas, live commenting the upcoming music with the microphone. Unforgettable.
Enjoy this video from the excellent &amp;ldquo;Tengo una pregunta para vos&amp;rdquo; series by Pepa Palazón, that I just recently found time to start watching. There are several gems there, and the most recent ones are subtitled in English (that includes this one).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guide To Tango Music Stores</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2013/05/23/guide-to-tango-music-stores/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2013 16:24:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2013/05/23/guide-to-tango-music-stores/</guid>
      <description>by Telstar Logistics
Tangohub beat me to it. Head over there for a comprehensive guide to stores for buying tango music online. It&amp;rsquo;s written from a UK perspective, but most of the stores mentioned are international.
I would mention Tangostore also (aka Zival&amp;rsquo;s), but they have been offline for a while.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango Tunes Website Up</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2013/05/08/tango-tunes-website-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 04:34:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2013/05/08/tango-tunes-website-up/</guid>
      <description>The long awaited TangoTunes project website is now online and accepting purchases. I&amp;rsquo;ll start by checking out the few Troilo recordings they have available at the moment. The purchase went through very smoothly.
This is how they present themselves:
TangoTunes is an Austrian-Argentine project with the aim to preserve the music of Tango Argentino. This way, we also preserve and support a piece of Argentine culture, which was declared World Heritage several years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Fast Transfers</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2013/05/07/more-fast-transfers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 08:36:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2013/05/07/more-fast-transfers/</guid>
      <description>by Aleera*
I have previously discussed too fast transfers from 78s. Age Akkerman has a well researched take on Di Sarli&amp;rsquo;s El ciruja which he found to be about 5% too fast on the Euro Records transfer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BPM</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2013/03/29/bpm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 19:41:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2013/03/29/bpm/</guid>
      <description>by Paul Graham Raven
The advances in DSP and processing power since I started ripping my cds to store all my music on a computer drive are enormous.
Sometimes having an estimate of the BPM of a tango song can be useful, e.g. when searching for &amp;ldquo;slow&amp;rdquo; milongas, sorting by BPM would be useful. But tapping each song individually to store in tags &amp;ndash; no way it&amp;rsquo;s worth the effort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Audio Restoration from Multiple Copies</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2013/03/27/audio-restoration-from-multiple-copies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 18:53:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2013/03/27/audio-restoration-from-multiple-copies/</guid>
      <description>I was pondering the usefulness of noise removal based on several copies of a recording, possibly from different physical copies. A Google search reveals that such a technique is already patented:
The present invention provides a method for reducing noise using a plurality of recording copies. The present invention produces a master file with lower noise than the available recording copies, and avoids the problems of losing musical content caused by prior art pop and click removers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango Tunes</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2013/02/20/tango-tunes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 15:49:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2013/02/20/tango-tunes/</guid>
      <description>The first results are trickling down from the TangoVia project. Tango Tunes is a Vienna based organisation, digitizing music with the help from TangoVia. They recently provided a preview of what they will offer, and I have to say I think it sounds very good. The Troilo sample in particular was very promising. The first songs available for purchase are 100 Biagi songs. The price is EUR 100, which is expensive compared with commercial releases, but cheaper than the Japanese labels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hope for CTA, AMP, Audio Park reissues?</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2012/11/15/hope-for-cta-amp-audio-park-reissues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2012 10:09:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2012/11/15/hope-for-cta-amp-audio-park-reissues/</guid>
      <description>by eerkmans
Many CTA discs and others are available in Europe through the Austrian DJ Bernhard Gehberger. He recently went to Japan and met with the guys behind CTA, AMP and Audio Park. From his report from that trip, it seems like he is working on facilitating reissues of these out-of-print discs. Which would be of great benefit to the tango community if he pulls it through. Today they are both hard to get and expensive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TINT based filing and human readable with FUSE and pytagsfs</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/09/20/tint-based-filing-and-human-readable-with-fuse-and-pytagsfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2011 19:28:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/09/20/tint-based-filing-and-human-readable-with-fuse-and-pytagsfs/</guid>
      <description>├── Canaro, Rafael │ ├── HQCD 99 Buenos Aires to Paris - Argentine tango performers in France 1924-1938 │ │ └── La mélodie de notre adieu.flac │ ├── ORQ 232 Rafael Canaro en Francia (1936-1939) │ │ ├── 01 Alma de bandoneón (Mario Beltrán).flac │ │ ├── 02 Campanas del recuerdo.flac
│ │ ├── 21 Olvidame (Luis Mariano).flac │ │ └── 22 Callecita de mi novia (Luis Mariano).flac │ └── ORQ 233 1929-1945 │ ├── 01 Las vueltas de la vida.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Too Fast Transfers</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/06/15/too-fast-transfers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 21:23:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/06/15/too-fast-transfers/</guid>
      <description>I sort of promised to post a few samples of my results from slowing down some tracks that I believe are transferred at too high speed in the DyM Tango Classics collection.
Although I have suspected that several other transfers, most notably on the El Bandoneon label were transferred at too high speed, I never tried slowing them down myself because I knew it to be hard to find the correct speed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improved Loudness Correction With EBU R128</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/01/18/improved-loudness-correction-with-ebu-r128/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 21:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/01/18/improved-loudness-correction-with-ebu-r128/</guid>
      <description>by Niels Linneberg
Music mastered at different levels can be a pain when you&amp;rsquo;re a dj, as well as when listening to music at home. The great differences in loudness levels is in part due to what is sometimes called the &amp;ldquo;Loudness War&amp;rdquo;, but sometimes it is just inconsistent between different issuers. As long as you listen to a CD/compilation as it was designed from the issuer, there is no problem, it is when you start mixing tracks from different sources that the volume starts jumping up and down&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now playing...</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/08/03/now-playing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2010 08:34:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/08/03/now-playing/</guid>
      <description>Most djs follow a reasonably predictable scheme when they play, grouping the music in tandas of the same orchestra and from the same period. Also some variation of a repeating pattern is common when it comes to the sequence of the tandas.
However, new dancers often don&amp;rsquo;t know this (doesn&amp;rsquo;t anyone teach about how a milonga works?), and they don&amp;rsquo;t know the music. And as the incentives to learn it all alone are not as they were in the old days in Buenos Aires, many djs provide an extra service to their community in displaying what they are playing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated MusicBrainz Picard Plugins for tango.info</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/07/23/updated-musicbrainz-picard-plugins-for-tango-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2010 17:09:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/07/23/updated-musicbrainz-picard-plugins-for-tango-info/</guid>
      <description>by Sebastian Niedlich (Grabthar)
I had a couple of requests for the plugins for MusicBrainz Picard in the last months. I haven&amp;rsquo;t used them much myself, as there sadly are few contributers on tango music to the MusicBrainz metadata database.
However, I just checked whether they worked with the current format of tracks.csv from tango.info and the newest release of Picard (0.12.1). With one minor adjustment, they now do, and I uploaded the new versions to be found on thetagging with MusicBrainz Picard page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Better Slogan</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/05/28/a-better-slogan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2010 20:50:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/05/28/a-better-slogan/</guid>
      <description>by law_keven
Time to upgrade my deejaying slogan. While I still sort of like the tongue in cheek fluffy deejay advertisment in-joke of **Keine komische Musik, **it has several problems. It is in German, and doesn&amp;rsquo;t really translate well. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure people get the joke, they may not even understand German. Also it may come off a bit negative. I would prefer a more positive note, so to speak.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whiskey Tango Foxtrot</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/03/11/whiskey-tango-foxtrot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2010 20:09:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/03/11/whiskey-tango-foxtrot/</guid>
      <description>by hdeb89
I was dancing a nice tanda with a friend of a friend, and while it was not exactly my favorite music, we were doing fine. We were having a good time. There were lots of people dancing, nobody got hurt, and we were dancing peacefully among the other couples. So far so good&amp;hellip;
I appreciated the festival organizers&amp;rsquo; effort to give some extra credit to the djs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DJing again</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/03/04/djing-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2010 22:01:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/03/04/djing-again/</guid>
      <description>by The unnamed
After a break of almost two years, I&amp;rsquo;m djing again this Weekend. I must say I look forward to it, knowing I will like the music at the milonga is always nice ;-) I got so much new music that I&amp;rsquo;m eager to use. While setting up my computer again (which was reinstalled after a breakdown a year ago) and doing some preparations, I listened to some of my favorite music, which was really nice, too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango Audio Restoration</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/03/01/tango-audio-restoration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 21:29:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/03/01/tango-audio-restoration/</guid>
      <description>Tango music was recorded with equipment much inferior to what is available today. Adding to that, the record companies threw away the master&amp;rsquo;s leaving us with reproductions based on the shellac records that further deteriate the sound.
For many of the commercial releases of tango music, the Reliquias series, the 78RPM series etc, the transfers have been cleaned and the noises removed for the music to become more clear and easy to listen to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Audio Myths</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/09/audio-myths/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2010 21:22:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/09/audio-myths/</guid>
      <description>Now, this may be only remotely relevant to tango, but tango music and hence its reproduction is important for dancers and djs in particular, so here it goes. I think the lessons from this video are most relevant when it comes to making decisions about equipment such as sound cards for djing, lossless versus lossy encoding of music and quality of transfers and restorations.
If you hang out at hydrogenaudio, this will all be familiar, but I have to say actually performing an abx was a humbling experience with regards to what I can and can&amp;rsquo;t hear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stuff without the stuff</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/04/27/stuff-without-the-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 01:11:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/04/27/stuff-without-the-stuff/</guid>
      <description>by?Simba tango
There was a discussion on the tango dj mailing list a while ago about people wanting &amp;ldquo;stuff without the stuff&amp;rdquo;. In other words, tango (dance) without tango (music). An oxymoron, one would think.
Stephen Brown put it so well with his little story:
   A number of years ago, I was in a coffee shop that offered coffee prepared many different ways. One of the ways was decaffeinated coffee with artificial sweetener and artificial cream.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last.fm cleaning up</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/29/lastfm-cleaning-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2009 21:45:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/29/lastfm-cleaning-up/</guid>
      <description>by aldask
Last.fm are finally cleaning up their metadata, or at least they have started. If you are on last.fm, why don&amp;rsquo;t you help out by voting for Rodolpho Biagi to redirect to Rodolfo Biagi? (follow the link to faulty spelling, vote at the bottom right). And while you are at it, if you are also a tango dj, why don&amp;rsquo;t join the group tangodj?
Information on tango music has gotten better lately, and a sample from top Pugliese tracks seems reasonable:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 40</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/11/top-40/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2009 11:36:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/11/top-40/</guid>
      <description>by Ger Audrey
I loved the think top 40 part of Alex&amp;rsquo; rant after attending a festival. The dj should think hits, hits and more hits to please the dancers. And maybe throw in a little surprise. Not all the time, but we need a little variation. But in general, play the good stuff. People are not interested in you digging up some weird music that you think maybe will work for tango.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Humbleness</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/09/humbleness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2009 20:16:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/09/humbleness/</guid>
      <description>by herval
I just heard this story, and found it hilarious, about a dancer complaining to the dj. The conversation went something like this:
-Ur music sux, man! -Allriiiight... which song would you like me to play? -! -Just name one song you would like me to play... -!! -Sooo... you don&#39;t actually know any songs, do you... Needless to say; before complaing, you ought to know what you are talking about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volume adjustments for tango music</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/07/volume-adjustments-for-tango-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2009 13:55:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/07/volume-adjustments-for-tango-music/</guid>
      <description>There was some discussion on the tangodj mailing list about the use of Replay Gain for tango music. I have used it for several years, and found it to be immensely useful. As you can see from the histogram above, the loudness of cd releases varies a lot, and Replay Gain makes automatic adjustments to make the loundess more or less the same. It does a lot better than I do, that&amp;rsquo;s for sure, and frees up time for the more interesting parts of the djing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keine komische Musik</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/05/keine-komische-musik/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2009 22:22:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/05/keine-komische-musik/</guid>
      <description>by emurray
I was warned once in a milonga in Central Europe: We have to dance **now, **this is milonga, he won&amp;rsquo;t play much of it. Later there will only be _komische Musik _(comical music).
This is the best excuse I have ever heard for asking someone (me) to dance! And she was right. The dj had no clue whatsoever and played a lot of &amp;ndash; well, komische Musik.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fb2k for the tangoDJ</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/26/fb2k-for-the-tangodj/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2008 20:57:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/26/fb2k-for-the-tangodj/</guid>
      <description>by duncan Foobar2000 just came out in version 0.9.6, making it a lot easier to configure for tangodjing purposes. I have written a short guide on how to configure fb2k for the tangoDJ. I will update the main article with new information, and suggestions for improvements are most welcome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Showing off</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/10/showing-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2008 22:12:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/10/showing-off/</guid>
      <description>by - mika -
Who hasn&amp;rsquo;t been tempted&amp;hellip;
&amp;hellip; to do some flashy moves when someone sitting next to the dance floor watches.
&amp;hellip; to show all the tricks of the trade when getting to dance with a really good dancer
&amp;hellip; to play some obscure gem from the record collection when djing
&amp;hellip; to play some music to be innovative
The problem is, it does not impress anyone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I started DJing</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/17/how-i-started-djing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2008 15:44:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/17/how-i-started-djing/</guid>
      <description>by AllegaertMe
When I started dancing tango, the &amp;ldquo;milonga&amp;rdquo; was in a café where we basically heard the same double cd over and over and over. In general, everybody knew exactly what song came next and started humming on the next song before it started. Knowing the music is all good, but, well&amp;hellip;
-I guess I would start djing, was the dry comment from an American dancer we met in Bs As a few years ago when I told this story.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>