<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tango on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/categories/tango/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tango on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 18:31:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/categories/tango/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Slow</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2014/09/25/slow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 18:31:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2014/09/25/slow/</guid>
      <description>by andy khouri
Insights about tango may be found where you least suspect it. Slow down and dance with me&amp;hellip; yeah..
Knew you&#39;d be here tonight So I put my best dress on Boy I was so right Our eyes connected Now nothing&#39;s how it used to be No second guesses Track in on this feeling Pull focus close up you and me Nobody&#39;s leaving Got me affected Spun me 180 degrees It&#39;s so electric Slow down and dance with me Yeah.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>El Papa Francisco</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2013/03/31/el-papa-francisco/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 07:20:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2013/03/31/el-papa-francisco/</guid>
      <description>Apparently the new pope is a tango lover, and now he got his own tango. Composition and lyrics by Daniel Ursini. Courtesy of Canciones para grabar.
Happy Easter, Papa Fracisco!
HT @milongaroom</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>White powder vs. Tango Argentino</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/21/white-powder-vs-tango-argentino/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2009 14:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/21/white-powder-vs-tango-argentino/</guid>
      <description>Powder Mountain Perspective from Ian Provo on Vimeo.
Common (could be pro or con, depending&amp;hellip;):
 Balance
 Rhythm
 Dissociation
 Improvisation
 Flow
 Max 12 min. rush
 Addictive
  Skiing pros  Fresh air
 Beautiful mountains
 Keeps you in shape
  Skiing cons  Avalanches
 Weather dependent
 Cold, dress accordingly
 Tough ascents
 Heavy on the knees
 Practical clothing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The tyranny of novelty</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/23/the-tyranny-of-novelty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2008 22:02:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/23/the-tyranny-of-novelty/</guid>
      <description>by Jacob Bøtter
The man who has journeyed all over the world can&#39;t find any novelty in five thousand miles, for he finds only new things -- yet another novelty, the old routine of the forever new -- while his abstract concept of novelty got lost at sea after the second new thing he saw.   _The Book of Disquiet (171) by Fernando Pessoa_    As in fashion, people in dance seem always to be chasing the new black.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost there</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/21/almost-there/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2008 12:03:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/21/almost-there/</guid>
      <description>by patsun They say it takes 10 years learning to walk&amp;hellip; Almost there ;-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 Tangos -- Adios Buenos Aires</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/19/12-tangos-adios-buenos-aires/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2008 17:06:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/19/12-tangos-adios-buenos-aires/</guid>
      <description>The documentary 12 tangos was just released in international version on DVD. It is a documentary, and the Adios Buenos Aires part of the title is somehow more accurate with regards to the content of the film. If you are looking for the Buena Vista Social Club of tango, you will be disappointed. There are no interviews with musicians, and only a few of the oldtimers participate in the orchestra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I started DJing</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/17/how-i-started-djing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2008 15:44:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/17/how-i-started-djing/</guid>
      <description>by AllegaertMe
When I started dancing tango, the &amp;ldquo;milonga&amp;rdquo; was in a café where we basically heard the same double cd over and over and over. In general, everybody knew exactly what song came next and started humming on the next song before it started. Knowing the music is all good, but, well&amp;hellip;
-I guess I would start djing, was the dry comment from an American dancer we met in Bs As a few years ago when I told this story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classic Couples: Gavito &amp; Duran</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/15/classic-couples-gavito-duran/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2008 14:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/15/classic-couples-gavito-duran/</guid>
      <description>[youtube]http://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=v246c8wP6_0[/youtube]
[youtube]http://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=0H6GvpWRNi8[/youtube]
[youtube]http://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=4_GlpLqfB_s[/youtube]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dancing is for fags and sissies...</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/14/dancing-is-for-fags-and-sissies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2008 14:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/14/dancing-is-for-fags-and-sissies/</guid>
      <description>Photo: zabara_tango@flickr, CC-licensed

Photo: Un Milonguero Mejicano@flickr, CC-licensed
&amp;ndash; while football is for real men: 
Photo: NaturalBlu@flickr, CC-licensed

Photo: NaturalBlu@flickr, CC-licensed</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nuevo tools, nuevo problems</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/09/nuevo-tools-nuevo-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2008 21:07:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/09/nuevo-tools-nuevo-problems/</guid>
      <description>Models can be very useful. By making a simplified version of the world that we are able to grasp, we may learn something about the world outside the model as well. This approach has proven very successful in a lot of areas, and is also applied to tango.
There is a danger associated with model building, as everyone working with them should know, and that is to mistake the model for reality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 tangos</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/01/12-tangos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 11:24:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/01/12-tangos/</guid>
      <description>Just ordered the new documentary 12 tangos. Will be very interesting to see, it also claims to be a Buena Vista Tango Club, so a shootout between 12 tangos and Cafe de los maestros. 12 tangos has a great advantage in being actually available.
I will get back to it later, in the meantime, the trailer:
[youtube]http://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=mrFklWP6dQY&amp;amp;feature=related[/youtube]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fabian Peralta &amp; Virginia Pandolfi in HD</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/21/fabian-peralta-virginia-pandolfi-in-hd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2008 15:52:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/21/fabian-peralta-virginia-pandolfi-in-hd/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old tango hero</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/09/old-tango-hero/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2008 20:53:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/09/old-tango-hero/</guid>
      <description>On our first visit to Buenos Aires, we rented a room in San Telmo. Right in the neighborhood is the Centro Cultural Torquato Tasso. For some reason we never came around to go there, even if it was by far the closest milonga.
Until one evening, we finally found space in our schedule to visit El Tasso. There was to be live music, and we were quite excited. The place was packed with people, and all of a sudden an old man was announced, and with support from a couple of guys he entered the stage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confiteria La Ideal en BBC</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/23/confiteria-la-ideal-en-bbc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2008 20:49:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/23/confiteria-la-ideal-en-bbc/</guid>
      <description>Another good documentary about tango. I enjoyed it a lot. Some of the interesting scenes are available on youtube, but the documentary itself was quite hard to get hold of. As far as I could determine, it is not available for sale, not even on ebay, so you better know one of them pirates or use your imagination ;-)
I am quite impressed by how ordinary dancers are able to express what tango means to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classes and entertainment</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/22/classes-and-entertainment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2008 11:01:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/22/classes-and-entertainment/</guid>
      <description>Why do people take classes? When I first started out in tango, I assumed people attended to classes to learn how to dance or to improve their dance, learning steps or improving technique or other skills. How naïve.
After several years more, I have discovered that people take classes for a variety of reasons, some of which I find perfectly reasonable, others I still cannot really understand. The good reasons are:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listening to the music</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/21/listening-to-the-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2008 20:48:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/21/listening-to-the-music/</guid>
      <description>What is good musicality?
Countless workshops are offered, people discuss who is dancing more musical or who doesn&amp;rsquo;t get it. But not easy to define. So without trying to get to the bottom of it, some reflexions are in place.
I heard quite often after dancing for a few years that I was dancing musically, which of course made me happy. Who wouldn&amp;rsquo;t like to dance musically? Of course it could be just to be polite and not mentioning my other more obvious shortcomings, but I think that even if my musicality was not very good or mature, at least I was:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More on less</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/21/more-on-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2008 20:30:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/21/more-on-less/</guid>
      <description>I just read an interview with this year&amp;rsquo;s campeones, Daniel Nacucchio &amp;amp; Cristina Sosa (congratulations, and nice to see Neri &amp;amp; Yanina did well also :-) - Well, he quoted old milonguero wisdom:
El que menos hace, a veces es el que hace más Which means something like, the one who does less, sometimes is the one that does more. (Forgive my translation, neither Spanish nor English is my native language).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passing judgement</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/05/passing-judgement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 20:17:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/05/passing-judgement/</guid>
      <description>It seems to be a popular activity among tango enthusasts, dissing all the dancers you don&amp;rsquo;t really like, especially teachers of course, and explain what everybody else does wrong. (Of course, we all do everything right ourselves ;-)
Sometimes it gets a bit out of hand, and can spread some negative energy, in particular when there is disagreement of who is in and who is out on a table at the milonga or in a small community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>O Ultimo Bandoneón</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/08/21/o-ultimo-bandoneon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2008 18:39:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/08/21/o-ultimo-bandoneon/</guid>
      <description>It is actually possible to get hold of this, but I had to order it from Brazil, so it was with portuguese subtitles, which was - challenging, but a very nice film it was. Recommended.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More or less?</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/08/07/more-or-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2008 18:26:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/08/07/more-or-less/</guid>
      <description>To quote Mies van der Rohe, less is more. As in architecture, this is very true in tango, I think. I was always accused of being subtle in my dancing (I always suspected it to be a euphemism for unclear, vague or not present). To my great surprise, after many years learning to dance the milonga - yes learning the milonga, more on this later - one of the things I really had to work on being more subtle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>El último bandoneón</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/22/la-ultima-bandoneon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2008 10:15:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/22/la-ultima-bandoneon/</guid>
      <description>httpvh://youtube.com/watch?v=eGerxiMniBQ
Maravillosa!
Now where can I get the entire film?
Trailer here:
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neri &amp; Yanina</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/16/neri-yanina/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2008 09:47:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/16/neri-yanina/</guid>
      <description>Standing out at the práctica of Carlitos and Rosa, it&amp;rsquo;s good to see they did well at the campeonato. Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clichés</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/06/cliches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2008 10:31:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/06/cliches/</guid>
      <description>Ever since I started dancing, the topic of tango clichés has fascinated me. The rose in mouth, castanets, head flicks, dramatic poses are all parts of what usually pops into people&amp;rsquo;s heads when they hear the word tango. Where did they come from, and why did they stick? Going through a lot of Hollywood production at least gives a partial answer, and Rudolph Valentino is one of the people to blame, the rose in mouth appears in the film Blood and sand, where he plays a bullfighter, while the film he dances the tango is _Four horsemen of the apocalypse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gavito Dixit</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/06/01/gavito-dixit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 15:26:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/06/01/gavito-dixit/</guid>
      <description>Gavito Dixit I ¿Bailaste el tango de tu vida esta noche? No bailes más… El tangauta #129
Gavito Dixit II El tango está entre paso y paso, allí donde se escuchan los silencios y cantan las musas. El tangauta #130
Gavito Dixit III El hombre debe saber que baila para ella,y al hacerlo, hace que ella se vea como una reina. Sólo así será el rey. El tangauta #131</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>