<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Codigos De La Milonga on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/categories/codigos-de-la-milonga/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Codigos De La Milonga on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/categories/codigos-de-la-milonga/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Find One Error</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2012/12/04/find-one-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2012 21:51:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2012/12/04/find-one-error/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-jYfvJchBQ60/UHQuT_Snw3I/AAAAAAAAAl4/gAlD_mrpf3w/s1600/IP06_finalpetit.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-jYfvJchBQ60/UHQuT_Snw3I/AAAAAAAAAl4/gAlD_mrpf3w/s1600/IP06_finalpetit.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a great idea! Trouvez l&amp;rsquo;erreur! from &lt;a href=&#34;http://lespasparfaits.blogspot.no/&#34;&gt;Les Pas Parfaits&lt;/a&gt; de Montréal. Simple, funny and well executed. Drawings by Véronique Paquette. My French is a bit rusty, but I believe the drawings are free to use for non-commercial purposes, and that it is allowed to translate them and incorporate translations in the images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Makes me want to go to Montréal!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of the Cabeceo Part III: When in Rome...</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/10/20/the-art-of-the-cabeceo-part-iii-when-in-rome.../</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2011 18:54:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/10/20/the-art-of-the-cabeceo-part-iii-when-in-rome.../</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/brettdavis/3506498664/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3656/3506498664_7dc0959756.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Romulus and Remus by Bsivad, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/brettdavis/&#34;&gt; Bsivad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the music of the cortina fades out, she glances over the tables on the opposite side of the dance floor. Refreshes her memory of where the different dancers she watched on the floor are seated. Preparing to try and catch the eye of one of her favorite partners as the music starts for the next tanda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her eyes move along the tables,  she is nodding to her self, yes, yes, maybe&amp;hellip; her eyes reach the corner of the dance floor, and she quickly moves on. Not him. She saw him on the dance floor, and with that embrace, if that is even the right word, no. Not a chance. She looks down to make it clear. She has to be careful about that part of the room, it seems. Better not cause any misunderstanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subtlety is not his force, apparently. She can see his gesturing in her peripheral view, doing her best to ignore him. But it&amp;rsquo;s too late. He is coming closer. She picks up her purse. She knows exactly where she got every single item, nevertheless she starts moving methodically between them, checking that each is in its designated place. Travel-sickness pills, mints, magnifier, spare stockings, paper towels, hand disinfectant&amp;hellip;.  He stops in front of her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;He:&lt;/strong&gt; Listen, here in Buenos Aires, he says with a  broad grin, we ask a woman to dance using our eyes&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**She: **I know&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;He:&lt;/strong&gt; So we don&amp;rsquo;t have to come up to the table to ask&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**She: **I know&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;He:&lt;/strong&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s called the cabeceo&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He tilts his head to one side and smiles again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;She:&lt;/strong&gt; I know&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She speaks without moving an inch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;He:&lt;/strong&gt; If you want to dance with me, you have to look at me and smile, you know&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He grins again and stretches out his hand for hers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;She:&lt;/strong&gt; I know. &lt;em&gt;No. Gracias.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She forces herself to make a brief smile and returns to her inventory listing. Now, where did I put that bottle of insect repellent?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of the Cabeceo Part II: Failing Gracefully</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/07/18/the-art-of-the-cabeceo-part-ii-failing-gracefully/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2011 20:17:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/07/18/the-art-of-the-cabeceo-part-ii-failing-gracefully/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/8o5IWOKl2gA&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;There she was, the girl with the blue dress. I noticed here before, but I never managed to catch her eye. Her seat was all the way over at the other corner, so I started walking between the tables. As I approached slowly, I tried to establish eye contact. She changed her position. A slight turn of the head. I got closer. She looked down. Opened her purse. I walked on until I passed her and continued to the Men&amp;rsquo;s room. Refused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some days later, I was back in the same milonga. There she was. This time closer to my table, sitting with her girlfriend, whom I had also noticed before. Fortunately, her friend accepted my invitation. I met her at the corner of  the wonderful parquet dance floor as the place started to get really packed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked her back to the table with the frozen blue dress and returned to my own. From the corner of my eye, I watched the two of them discussing vividly, glancing over in my direction. The moment of truth. Too bad I would not hear the verdict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Di Sarli intrumental. I scanned the crowd for a suitable partner. Two eyes met mine. With a subtle nod, the contract was written and I walked towards the table. The blue dress got up and we headed for the dance floor. Hora Pica &amp;ndash; peak hour &amp;ndash; and no other option than keeping it simple. Walking in an embrace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Random meetings with strangers in the night. Most are quickly forgotten. Others stay with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several years later, on a different continent. There is something familiar with that girl. I walk over to her table to say hello. She remembers. She goes dancing with some other guy while I chat with a mutual friend.  Then she returns. Di Sarli Instrumental.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our eyes meet again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HT illustration video: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.limericktango.com/2011/07/ode-au-tango/&#34;&gt;Limerick tango&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of the Cabeceo Part I: Are You Flirting With Me?</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/10/23/the-art-of-the-cabeceo-part-i-are-you-flirting-with-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2010 13:45:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/10/23/the-art-of-the-cabeceo-part-i-are-you-flirting-with-me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/pedrosimoes7/60010574/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/32/60010574_149e48d8af.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rita N by pedrosimoes7, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/pedrosimoes7/&#34;&gt; pedrosimoes7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;Nobody asks me to dance, complained our Canadian classmate. We were sitting at our table in the Buenos Aires Golf Club, overlooking the dark course and the city skyline. We started chatting about the cabeceo, surely she knew the habit of the Porteño dancer to ask by catching a potential partner&amp;rsquo;s eye and confirming with a slight nod towards the pista?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course she didn&amp;rsquo;t. On the contrary, she brought her habit of avoiding to meet the eye of men she did not know, avoiding unwanted attention and flirts from strangers, as she did back home. That is effectively the same as wearing a sign saying you&amp;rsquo;re not interested in dancing, and that habit had be brought to an end in the milongas. Instead, watching attentively and gently transmit the intent of watching out for dancers, is the way to go. If dancing is what you&amp;rsquo;re after, of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the golf club, the women wore furs, black dresses and pearls, and mostly went with their suit-clad husbands, who were in turn occupied with taking care of their women or occasionally a close friend in their company. Yet there also were also people interested in dancing with people outside their own table&amp;hellip; Our classmate headed over towards the bar, where she kept her eyes open for dancing opportunities. It didn&amp;rsquo;t take long before she was out on the floor. And on the floor she remained for the rest of the night, dancing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the Code</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/07/16/breaking-the-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2010 17:48:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/07/16/breaking-the-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/chisholm/670116/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/1/670116_985adcdb51.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Dubai Al Bharj 7 * Hotel by Onechis1, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/chisholm/&#34;&gt; Onechis1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;-- Using your eyes is the simplest if you feel a bit uncertain. -- See how the other guests behave. Everybody participates in a kind of theatre, where the guests, too, play their parts. That means that you are a part of the other people&#39;s experience, just like the others&#39; behaviour is a part of your experience. That is why behaving properly is a way of showing respect for the others&#39; experience.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not that hard, really. Visiting a new and unfamiliar milieu. Like a luxury hotel, as the above quote (in my translation) refers to. Or a milonga in Buenos Aires. Or somewhere else.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>El Tangauta interviews Chicho</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/16/el-tangauta-interviews-chicho/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2009 03:28:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/16/el-tangauta-interviews-chicho/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/12/ElTangauta182-Chicho.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/12/ElTangauta182-Chicho.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ElTangauta182-Chicho&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Another &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eltangauta.com/nota.asp?id=1412&amp;amp;idedicion=0#nota-i&#34;&gt;interesting interview with Chicho&lt;/a&gt;, and he elaborates on some of the same things as in the&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/11/23/interview-with-mariano-chicho-frumboli/&#34;&gt; previous interview&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;[The] milongueros had respect, delicacy and sensibility, it was totally different. I know my role is contradictory, because I also collaborated in generating this young movement. In its moment I got tired of the strict milonguero codes that didn’t correspond with my time and to rebel I tried to make my way. Today I’m a milonguero again (laughter); I’m against the people who do not cabecear (nod), who don’t have codes or respect. The value of tango has been diluted. That is why I say that many dancers are lost, they barely hold on to each other to dance and for two hours like zombies, it is very sad.

&gt; 
&gt; _Mariano &#39;Chicho&#39; Frumboli_
&gt; 
&gt; 
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read the entire interview at &lt;a href=&#34;http://eltangauta.com&#34;&gt;El Tangauta&lt;/a&gt;, you need to register to download the pdf (issue 182). [Edit: It is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eltangauta.com/nota.asp?id=1412&amp;amp;idedicion=0#nota-i&#34;&gt;now online here&lt;/a&gt; (direct link to the english translation)]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tailored for Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/11/06/tailored-for-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2009 23:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/11/06/tailored-for-tango/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wmacphail/3231382603/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3377/3231382603_9083a84d93.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Emil Fusaro - Shears by wmacphail, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/wmacphail/&#34;&gt; wmacphail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;Come back here! You are not entering the floor without buttoning your jacket! Her voice left no doubt, and the young aspiring dancer stepped back, buttoned his jacket and went back on the dance floor. He was smiling, but he would not commit the same error again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In one of my very first tango lessons, I was told that the Argentine dancers would &lt;strong&gt;never&lt;/strong&gt; take off their jacket for dancing. After going to Buenos Aires, one realizes that it must have been quite some time since a man would refuse to take off his jacket for such a mundane reason as it being a little warm, making him uncomfortable. People mostly dress nice, but suits are not all that common. But there is something there. You should keep your jacket on, and there are many reasons why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Suits do have [..] a way of looking superior (p 114)&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This quote, and all the following, are from the book &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/Sex-Suits-Evolution-Modern-Dress/dp/1870626672&#34;&gt;Sex &amp;amp; Suits&lt;/a&gt;, written by Anne Hollander, and it helped me fill out some blanks and connect some stuff about the relations between tango and how clothes make the dancer. Or maybe the dance, we&amp;rsquo;ll get back to that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find that tango generally looks better when the man wears a suit, (I will explain why later). It could be just out of habit, of course, as tango was developed when men basically wore suits, but I thought it was something more there. And if we are to believe Hollander, there is indeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hollander sees a clear connection between the development of the suit and the rise of the modern movement as seen in other art forms such as music, painting and architecture. At the same time, in Argentina, starts the evolution of tango. Tango is a very modern dance in the same sense of the word, and was breaking loose from earlier dances which were heavily choreographed and didn&amp;rsquo;t allow physical proximity in that way. Think film adaptations of Jane Austen novels. Man and woman met only briefly during the dance. This changed with the invention of modern couple dancing, led by the walz and followed by the tango, introduced in Paris in the 1910s. Hollander notices this as well, but only mentions it very briefly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;The changes in women&#39;s fashion coincided with the spread of close couple-dancing as an ordinary pastime (..) p 136&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeing the evolution of tango in relationship with the modern movement in general can be revealing in other respects, too, but we will concentrate on the topic of clothing here. Early signs of modernism appeared when the West rediscovered (again) the classical ideals and the art of Ancient Greece. One thing that changed as a consequence of this, writes Hollander, is that the youth ideal was revived with other classical ideals, and the ideas about what a body should look like changed from the reigning pear shaped ideal to a more athletic (young) body ideal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following from that came the development of something that resembles a modern suit. The lines were made cleaner, one saw a removal of clutter, in exchange for an easy elegance. The tailors set out to transform their clients&amp;rsquo; bodies towards this new ideal, and in the process invented modern tailoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;(...) by the turn of the century, elegance had shifted entirely away from wrought surfaces to fundamental form, and away from courtly refinement to natural simplicity. (p 90)&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;In their pure form, they express a confident adult masculinity, unflavored with either violence or passivity. The suit reflects purposeful development (...) it has the modern look of carefully simplified dynamic abstraction that has its own strong sexual appeal. (p 113)&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The suit enhances how the man wearing it looks, moving in direction of the ideal, athletic body. At the same time, it is simple, and reveals that there is indeed a moving body inside, from which it takes much of its strength, if we are to believe Hollander. It is also interesting to note that the (three piece) suit was originally used for leisure, and seen as  &amp;rsquo;informal&amp;rsquo; attire, which is obviously something that has since changed, now being associated with work and formal occasions like weddings and tango nights&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find that not only does the suit enhance the dancer (how he looks) by enhancing the body shape, it also enhances the dance (in terms of how it looks).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By allowing some movement, while gently hiding other details, for instance by deemphasizing the chest lead and dissossiation both lead to more surprises for the onlookers, while simultaneously making the dancer look calm, athletic, powerful and elegant (as usually associated with suits). This is especially true with figures like enrosques, giros and lapises where the male dancer&amp;rsquo;s upper and lower body almost seem to be disconnected. The torso calm, clean and in control, the feet shooting around in intricate steps at high speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And one thing that is characteristic of tango, is the dissosiation between the upper and lower body. The upper body calm, introvert, embracing your partner, following the melody. The feet moving with the rhythm, making fast movements, intermingling with your partners&amp;rsquo; feet. Two different modes at once.  I believe many dancers choose how to dress to emphasize this image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sometimes wonder if the dancers often associated with Gustavo Naveira and his very structural approach to tango are more interested in exposing the inner workings of the movements, rather than hiding them, celebrating the raw movement rather than the &amp;lsquo;magic&amp;rsquo; and surprise? Like the more contemporary &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.greatbuildings.com/buildings/Centre_Pompidou.html&#34;&gt;Centre Pompidou&lt;/a&gt; in Paris is exposing the inner workings of the building, maybe they want to expose the mechanics of the dance? Make all structural elements visible, to tell the true story, one could imagine the nuevo movement going in this direction, in their search to uncover every secret of the tango movements. Show everything. Make it all clear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess you would need to dress in tight fitting t-shirt and trousers to make every movement transparent.  And it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really seem like they move in that direction, exactly. However, the further development of clothing in the 20th century fits in well with the &amp;lsquo;rebels&amp;rsquo; of tango, in moving on towards outfits even more derived from leisure clothing, throwing away the jacket and going for the shirt, sweater or t-shirt instead. Some dancers (e.g. Naveira, Chicho) notoriously dance in large tunikas or shirts which to some degree hides disossiation, though much less than a proper suit. Large, baggy pants, emphasizing leg movements, but hiding to some degree the exact placement of the legs. Trousers with light, fluffy fabrics that follow and emphasize the movements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a sense, argues Hollander, this further development of clothing is also based on the suit and has a subversive element as has all fashion. It exposes what was once essentially underwear, shirts and t-shirts, once worn under the suit, now daringly exposed. As is the mechanics of the movement itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now how about women? I always adored how the womens&amp;rsquo; skirts enhance the round movements like ochos, giros, boleos etc. Caressing the lady, creating nice lines and following, then extending the curved movement. Very nice indeed, when the skirt continues a movement in one direction, while the body already has started on the counter movement like in a boleo for instance. Hollander sees this fashion as the wave of modernity arriving much later for womens clothing  than for men, essentially at the same time that tango really took off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;(...)evening dresses were more gauzy and feminine than ever, now calf-length to show feet and ankles in exciting shoes and stockings, and very loose and revealing above the waist. Withouth tight waists and big petticoats, the bodies wearing them looked very real indeed, the breasts and hips connected in an organic human relation, and the feet and legs in plain sight. Posture, formerly very straight and queenly to go with the expanse and stiffness of the clothes, now allowed for an easy and relaxed slouch---another defining and irreversible sigh of female modernity(...) p 131&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;In the second decade of [the 20th] century, however, the furs and soft wollens and silks clinging to the yielding figure seemed at last to confess that a woman could feel her own body; and they straightforwardly invited others to grasp and stroke her as a physically responsive living creature. p134&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;By 1925, modern skirts were knee-length and not cumbersome, and they gave off no mysterious suggestions. After that, the hem moved up and down, but never all the way down for good. Skirts tended to delineate the pelvis and thighs, to move with them instead of independently, and to cover with what seemed like a single layer of fabric, just as men&#39;s trousers did. p146f&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I won&amp;rsquo;t go as far as suggesting that tango was determined by changes in fashion at the  time, but it seems clear to me that like many other things falling into place at the time created an environment where the tango could develop into the form we know it today during the golden age. And the changes in dressing is one of these pieces that shaped preferences or what was considered good form at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading the book only reinforced my view that &amp;lsquo;traditional&amp;rsquo; is a bit of a misnomer for a dance that really has &lt;strong&gt;modern&lt;/strong&gt; written all over it in capital letters. And it is a paradox that the clothing that many today see as stiff and formal once was the clothing of leisure, like t-shirts, sportswear and jeans are today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well &amp;ndash; myself I have always been a nostalgic for the modern, so for me it makes perfect sense to dress up for tango. And as I explained above, I think it makes the dance (look) better. Depending on the fabrics, it may also feel better. Not long ago one of the comments to a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7gSQgrXfwKE&#34;&gt;youtube video&lt;/a&gt; complimenting the male dancer ended &amp;lsquo;(&amp;hellip;) and the man knows how to dress!!&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coincidence? I think not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Credit to &lt;a href=&#34;http://mshedgehog.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Ms Hedgehog&lt;/a&gt; for&lt;a href=&#34;http://mshedgehog.blogspot.com/2009/06/priscilla-queen-of-desert-sex-and-suits.html&#34;&gt; directing my attention to the book&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Resistance</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/26/the-resistance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2009 00:42:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/26/the-resistance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/mirsasha/92364080/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/42/92364080_db1cccacc2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Wall of flyers by mirsasha, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/mirsasha/&#34;&gt; mirsasha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tangocommuter1.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Tangocommuter&lt;/a&gt; is constructive and a man of action. Simba likes that. Following up on his own idea to distribute the &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/07/15/homenaje-a-los-milongueros/&#34;&gt;homage to the milongueros&lt;/a&gt;, he has created  a &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/sin-rumbo.pdf&#34;&gt;flyer&lt;/a&gt;, and I am happy to host it here at simbatango.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenge is, in his own words:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

&gt; 
&gt; (...) print out a lot of copies, with an attractive picture, perhaps that of the entrance to Sin Rumbo, so that it looks like a regular leaflet, to leave on the table at the entry of every milonga we go to…
&gt; 
&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quietly sneaking in a little education in the milongas. Nonobtrusive. Quite neat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we need your help. Print out a handful of &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/sin-rumbo.pdf&#34;&gt;tangocommuter&amp;rsquo;s flyer&lt;/a&gt;, and leave it at your local milonga. Or make your own design if you prefer. You may use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/simba_tango&#34;&gt;my images at flickr&lt;/a&gt; (with a &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;cc license&lt;/a&gt;) or find someone else&amp;rsquo;s or make something yourself. Suggestions for improvements and new versions are most welcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And please do keep us updated on your success&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EDIT: New version from Tangocommuter, &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/sinrumbo.pdf&#34;&gt;this prints four leaflets on one page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homenaje a los milongueros</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/16/homenaje-a-los-milongueros/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2009 02:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/16/homenaje-a-los-milongueros/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/simba_tango/3724775725/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2424/3724775725_887e20fde6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Bienvenidos al Club Sin Rumbo by Simba tango, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/simba_tango/&#34;&gt; Simba tango&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you enter the &lt;em&gt;cathedral of tango&lt;/em&gt;, the milonga &lt;strong&gt;Sin Rumbo&lt;/strong&gt;, among the things hanging on the wall is this piece written by Marisa Galindo as a homage to the milongueros. It may serve as guiding principles or ideals for all tango dancers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;los-milongueros&#34;&gt;Los milongueros&amp;hellip;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;son quienes saben hacer la ronda&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;son quienes un oido musical increible&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;son los que conocen cada orquesta y a sus cantores y a veces cantan despacito al oído.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;son quienes con poco despliegue coreográfico producen un fuerte intercambio de emociones y de placer, que a veces se transforma en éxtasis, cuando desde el rol femenino, podés cerrar los ojos en una entrega total.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;son suaves y precisos en la marcación, marcan con todo cuerpo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;cuidan a los mujeres para no sean golpeados&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;bailan para él y para ella, no para el público&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;respetan al grupo evitando las figuras que son peligrosas en la pista: ganchos, boleadas, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;su rítmo, las variaciones rítmicas y sus pausas están en contacto con la música, con la mujer y con los otros bailarines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A rough translation would be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-milongueros&#34;&gt;The milongueros&amp;hellip;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;know how to make the dance flow well on the floor&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;have amazing ears for music&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;know each orchestra and singer and will somtimes sing quietly in your ear&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;create great emotional variations and pleasure by using simple coreographic elements, that sometimes transforms into ecstasy, when the woman can close her eyes in total surrender&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;are soft and precise in their lead, using their entire body to lead&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;protect the women so they are not pushed or kicked&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;dance for him and for her, not for the crowd watching&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;respect the other dancers by avoiding dangerous figures like ganchos and boleos (kicks) on the dance floor&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;their rhythm, rhytmical variations and pauses are connected with the music, with the woman and with the other dancers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Venturing once more into the perilous landscape of translations.. I tried being a bit less literal in my translation this time. I took the liberty of substituting rol feminino with woman, as I had trouble avoiding awkward constructs. I think this is the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve seen this expression used in castellano, usually the teachers will stick to the terms man (hombre) and woman (mujer).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I studied foreign languages in high school, we  would invariably translate short texts, so in a way this crazy project makes some sense. (Hopefully improving my castellano.) Maybe I will dare try translating the &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2008/06/01/gavito-dixit/&#34;&gt;Gavito dixit&lt;/a&gt; sometime&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Competition</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/03/01/competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 09:04:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/03/01/competition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/azarov/755359154/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1302/755359154_19898fe183.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;4944 by Alaz-, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/azarov/&#34;&gt; Alaz-&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some reason, people often assume I dance competitions when they hear I&amp;rsquo;m a tango dancer. Not so, I tell them. The only competition is to get to dance with the best dancers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while I still believe that to be true to some extent, a friend (who is an excellent dancer himself), put me on a better track. Why is it so important to dance with the &amp;ldquo;best&amp;rdquo;, he asked. Is not the point to dance with someone you may give a nice experience? And he was absolutely right, of course. So it is better to think of compatibility rather than ability. We have different strengths and weaknesses, and value different qualities in our partners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that is one reason I find the cabeceo so wonderful. It enables you to make sure you only dance with people that would actually like to dance with &lt;strong&gt;you&lt;/strong&gt;. Having a tango star accept a dance out of mercy and feeling her bored disconnectedness through an entire tanda would be unbearable for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for convenience, I still use the catch phrase for my non-tango friends. And in a sense it is still valid. It is a competition between me and the other guys: who will be the most likely to give the lady a good dance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The code</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/25/the-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2009 10:56:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/25/the-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/anthonygrimley/116867237/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/51/116867237_9a18590294.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Red no entry sign by anthonygrimley, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/anthonygrimley/&#34;&gt; anthonygrimley&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be difficult to learn tango. In addition to learning to know the music, leading and following and the basic vocabulary, there are the rules. So many rules to remember. Or codigos, as some prefer to call them. Codigos de la milonga.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there are some that think way too much attention devoted to these &amp;ldquo;rules&amp;rdquo;. Ancient rules from Buenos Aires, we can manage very well without them, thankyouverymuch. In our country, we do it our way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What these people fail to understand is that what they see as rigid rules from a distant time is only &lt;em&gt;common sense&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;simple courtesy&lt;/em&gt;. I know courtesy is out of fashion these days, but here is your wake-up call: so is couple dancing! And they go together, the two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is astonishing that one has to teach grown up individuals, tell them explicitly that one should not kick the others on the dance floor, respect a no for a no and in general behave like  grown ups. And even more startling: after being taught these things, people still do it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shut up and listen! (II)</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/16/shut-up-and-listen-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2008 12:25:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/16/shut-up-and-listen-ii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/carolesther/429895047/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/185/429895047_7cc038782b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;what’d you say by Carol Esther, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/carolesther/&#34;&gt; Carol Esther&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/index.php/2008/11/16/shut-up-and-listen/&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt; got me going on the habit that some dancers have of &lt;em&gt;talking while dancing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just stop it, ok?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can you possibly be listening to the music when you are talking at the same time? The conversation is going on in the dance, remember? And even if you somehow manage to do both at the same time, you are disturbing the others on the floor.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>