<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Codigos De La Milonga on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/categories/codigos-de-la-milonga/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Codigos De La Milonga on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2012 21:51:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/categories/codigos-de-la-milonga/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Find One Error</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2012/12/04/find-one-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2012 21:51:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2012/12/04/find-one-error/</guid>
      <description>This is a great idea! Trouvez l&amp;rsquo;erreur! from Les Pas Parfaits de Montréal. Simple, funny and well executed. Drawings by Véronique Paquette. My French is a bit rusty, but I believe the drawings are free to use for non-commercial purposes, and that it is allowed to translate them and incorporate translations in the images.
Makes me want to go to Montréal!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of the Cabeceo Part III: When in Rome...</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/10/20/the-art-of-the-cabeceo-part-iii-when-in-rome/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2011 18:54:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/10/20/the-art-of-the-cabeceo-part-iii-when-in-rome/</guid>
      <description>by Bsivad
As the music of the cortina fades out, she glances over the tables on the opposite side of the dance floor. Refreshes her memory of where the different dancers she watched on the floor are seated. Preparing to try and catch the eye of one of her favorite partners as the music starts for the next tanda.
Her eyes move along the tables, she is nodding to her self, yes, yes, maybe&amp;hellip; her eyes reach the corner of the dance floor, and she quickly moves on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of the Cabeceo Part II: Failing Gracefully</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/07/18/the-art-of-the-cabeceo-part-ii-failing-gracefully/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2011 20:17:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/07/18/the-art-of-the-cabeceo-part-ii-failing-gracefully/</guid>
      <description>There she was, the girl with the blue dress. I noticed here before, but I never managed to catch her eye. Her seat was all the way over at the other corner, so I started walking between the tables. As I approached slowly, I tried to establish eye contact. She changed her position. A slight turn of the head. I got closer. She looked down. Opened her purse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of the Cabeceo Part I: Are You Flirting With Me?</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/10/23/the-art-of-the-cabeceo-part-i-are-you-flirting-with-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2010 13:45:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/10/23/the-art-of-the-cabeceo-part-i-are-you-flirting-with-me/</guid>
      <description>by pedrosimoes7
&amp;ndash;Nobody asks me to dance, complained our Canadian classmate. We were sitting at our table in the Buenos Aires Golf Club, overlooking the dark course and the city skyline. We started chatting about the cabeceo, surely she knew the habit of the Porteño dancer to ask by catching a potential partner&amp;rsquo;s eye and confirming with a slight nod towards the pista?
Of course she didn&amp;rsquo;t. On the contrary, she brought her habit of avoiding to meet the eye of men she did not know, avoiding unwanted attention and flirts from strangers, as she did back home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the Code</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/07/16/breaking-the-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2010 17:48:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/07/16/breaking-the-code/</guid>
      <description>by Onechis1
-- Using your eyes is the simplest if you feel a bit uncertain. -- See how the other guests behave. Everybody participates in a kind of theatre, where the guests, too, play their parts. That means that you are a part of the other people&#39;s experience, just like the others&#39; behaviour is a part of your experience. That is why behaving properly is a way of showing respect for the others&#39; experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>El Tangauta interviews Chicho</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/16/el-tangauta-interviews-chicho/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2009 03:28:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/16/el-tangauta-interviews-chicho/</guid>
      <description>Another interesting interview with Chicho, and he elaborates on some of the same things as in theprevious interview.
[The] milongueros had respect, delicacy and sensibility, it was totally different. I know my role is contradictory, because I also collaborated in generating this young movement. In its moment I got tired of the strict milonguero codes that didn’t correspond with my time and to rebel I tried to make my way. Today I’m a milonguero again (laughter); I’m against the people who do not cabecear (nod), who don’t have codes or respect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tailored for Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/11/06/tailored-for-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2009 23:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/11/06/tailored-for-tango/</guid>
      <description>by wmacphail
&amp;ndash;Come back here! You are not entering the floor without buttoning your jacket! Her voice left no doubt, and the young aspiring dancer stepped back, buttoned his jacket and went back on the dance floor. He was smiling, but he would not commit the same error again.
In one of my very first tango lessons, I was told that the Argentine dancers would never take off their jacket for dancing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Resistance</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/26/the-resistance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2009 00:42:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/26/the-resistance/</guid>
      <description>by mirsasha
Tangocommuter is constructive and a man of action. Simba likes that. Following up on his own idea to distribute the homage to the milongueros, he has created a flyer, and I am happy to host it here at simbatango.com.
The challenge is, in his own words:
   (...) print out a lot of copies, with an attractive picture, perhaps that of the entrance to Sin Rumbo, so that it looks like a regular leaflet, to leave on the table at the entry of every milonga we go to…    Quietly sneaking in a little education in the milongas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homenaje a los milongueros</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/16/homenaje-a-los-milongueros/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2009 02:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/16/homenaje-a-los-milongueros/</guid>
      <description>by Simba tango
As you enter the cathedral of tango, the milonga Sin Rumbo, among the things hanging on the wall is this piece written by Marisa Galindo as a homage to the milongueros. It may serve as guiding principles or ideals for all tango dancers:
Los milongueros&amp;hellip;  son quienes saben hacer la ronda
 son quienes un oido musical increible
 son los que conocen cada orquesta y a sus cantores y a veces cantan despacito al oído.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Competition</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/03/01/competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 09:04:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/03/01/competition/</guid>
      <description>by Alaz-
For some reason, people often assume I dance competitions when they hear I&amp;rsquo;m a tango dancer. Not so, I tell them. The only competition is to get to dance with the best dancers.
And while I still believe that to be true to some extent, a friend (who is an excellent dancer himself), put me on a better track. Why is it so important to dance with the &amp;ldquo;best&amp;rdquo;, he asked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The code</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/25/the-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2009 10:56:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/25/the-code/</guid>
      <description>by anthonygrimley
It can be difficult to learn tango. In addition to learning to know the music, leading and following and the basic vocabulary, there are the rules. So many rules to remember. Or codigos, as some prefer to call them. Codigos de la milonga.
And there are some that think way too much attention devoted to these &amp;ldquo;rules&amp;rdquo;. Ancient rules from Buenos Aires, we can manage very well without them, thankyouverymuch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shut up and listen! (II)</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/16/shut-up-and-listen-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2008 12:25:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/16/shut-up-and-listen-ii/</guid>
      <description>by Carol Esther
My previous post got me going on the habit that some dancers have of talking while dancing.
Just stop it, ok?
How can you possibly be listening to the music when you are talking at the same time? The conversation is going on in the dance, remember? And even if you somehow manage to do both at the same time, you are disturbing the others on the floor.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>