<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Baby In Buenos Aires on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>https://simbatango.github.io/tags/baby-in-buenos-aires/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Baby In Buenos Aires on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="https://simbatango.github.io/tags/baby-in-buenos-aires/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango and Toddler in Buenos Aires</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/09/15/tango-and-toddler-in-buenos-aires/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2009 00:03:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/09/15/tango-and-toddler-in-buenos-aires/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/salvoguille/1441532281/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1021/1441532281_bd0c381998.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;La mar en coche by salvoguille, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/salvoguille/&#34;&gt; salvoguille&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear readers: I need your advice: We consider ourselves to find our way around in Buenos Aires fairly well after several previous stays there. This time, however, there is something different. We are no longer a couple going to the milongas  every night. We are a small family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strolling with or without purpose in the streets of our beloved city we can still do, enjoying café con leche while watching people walk past, too. Tango is harder. Tango is a nighttime activity, and not so family friendly. So in preparation of our next travel to Buenos Aires, we have started to try and figure out what we can do tango wise. Obviously, it will be different, and certainly less than before. That&amp;rsquo;s fine. What we&amp;rsquo;re after is quality, so a little quality goes a long way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One major concern is the safety of our child in traffic. The standards in Argentina are &lt;em&gt;different&lt;/em&gt; to say the least in terms of traffic safety. Taxis with no seat belts are very common, and we are used to having him in a child safety seat, which we intend to continue doing. Public transportation (colectivo and subte) is a partial solution to this, but won&amp;rsquo;t take us everywhere. We have also thought about using remises more, if we find someone we know have good cars, it will be worth the extra wait/planning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For tango, there seem to be three possibilities: Bringing the baby, one going out while the other is babysitting, having a babysitter for a night. Listed in the order of the expected frequency we plan on trying each to get some dancing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are staying in the neighborhood of Palermo Viejo, which is close to the green line (Línea D) and lots of buses. Salón Canning, La Viruta, Villa Malcom and others are within walking distance (but of those, Canning is the only we&amp;rsquo;d consider).  So Canning will work well for option two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to bringing the baby, we have thought of bringing him to some practicas, where we can go by bus. It&amp;rsquo;s not too late in the evening, so it might work out. We&amp;rsquo;ll see. Also the open air milonga &lt;em&gt;La Glorieta&lt;/em&gt; is quite nice, and one can easily watch the  stroller and chat with friends while the other is dancing, easily accessible by subway. We haven&amp;rsquo;t used the afternoon milongas in the centre so much, as our experience with them from earlier wasn&amp;rsquo;t too good, but we are very open for recommendations there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, an occasional babysitter allows us to go wherever, and would be nice for going out at night, maybe to milongas in the barrios or in the centre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don&amp;rsquo;t plan on taking much lessons, but we&amp;rsquo;ll take some privates with out favorite teachers, and probably a few group lessons as well. Even if some of them are quite late, we hope we can bring him for some.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone knows of families that brought small children to Buenos Aires and still managed to get out to dance a little? We would be very happy for other suggestions and recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I&amp;rsquo;ll you updated on how it goes. No matter how carefully we plan, there will be surprises.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>