<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Campeonato on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/tags/campeonato/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Campeonato on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2009 01:27:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/tags/campeonato/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Campeones mundiales de tango salon 2009: Hiroshi &amp; Kyoko Yamao (JP)</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/30/campeones-mundiales-de-tango-salon-2009-hiroshi-kyoko-yamao-jp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2009 01:27:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/30/campeones-mundiales-de-tango-salon-2009-hiroshi-kyoko-yamao-jp/</guid>
      <description>I have wondered whether the Argentine would ever select a non-argentine couple to win the tango salon category. Now I know, the fabulous Japanese couple Hiroshi &amp;amp; Kyoko just won the first prize! Great dancers and great people! Felicitaciones!!!
UPDATE:
2xtango got pictures and video from the last ronda with Hiroshi and Kyoko and a nice post about the winners. Also Hiroshi and Kyoko have some pictures at their blog (machine translated from Japanese).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>¡Mucha mierda en el mundial!</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/29/mucha-mierda-en-el-mundial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2009 18:19:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/29/mucha-mierda-en-el-mundial/</guid>
      <description>by Simba tango
Tonight is the night of the final of the mundial (world championship) of tango salon. While I always found the idea of a competition in social dancing somewhat absurd, it happens that for the last couple of years several friends have been among the finalists, and that made it all more interesting.
It all starts at 1900 local time, and rumors have it there will be live broadcast, and I will try to catch it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cristhian Sosa &amp; Lida Montovani</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/04/cristhian-sosa-lida-montovani/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2009 01:48:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/04/cristhian-sosa-lida-montovani/</guid>
      <description>Wow! First place both in milonga and vals! I am impressed, but not surprised. They were in a different class entirely as far as I could judge from the videos posted over at 2xtango.
Felicitaciones!
Here they are performing at La Viruta. A milonga and a vals, of course.
    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The real stuff</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/10/the-real-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2009 15:12:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/10/the-real-stuff/</guid>
      <description>by oed
Ah -- you dance **real** milonga (echte Milonga). After struggling with my milonga for years, this was the ultimate sign I was finally getting somewhere. And one of my favorite compliments ever. I got a tip from the Argentine host to ask this woman to dance, he thought I should dance with someone good. So I did. And was not disappointed. Starting almost right out with a milonga, which would have terrified me only a year earlier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neri &amp; Yanina</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/16/neri-yanina/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2008 09:47:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/16/neri-yanina/</guid>
      <description>Standing out at the práctica of Carlitos and Rosa, it&amp;rsquo;s good to see they did well at the campeonato. Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>