<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spotify on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/tags/spotify/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Spotify on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2011 18:58:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/tags/spotify/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>More De Caro</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/12/07/more-de-caro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2011 18:58:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/12/07/more-de-caro/</guid>
      <description>Danza y Movimiento have released anotherbatch of De Caro collections. In addition to the places they were available the last time, they are also available on Spotify (links below).
I haven&amp;rsquo;t had time to listen carefully yet, but the few I have listened to seem to be transferred at the correct speed (unlike some of the older ones).
Just in time for the upcoming día del tango. Enjoy:
 Mocosita (#153)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spotify Available in the US -- Tango Classics</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/07/14/spotify-available-in-the-us-tango-classics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 15:49:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/07/14/spotify-available-in-the-us-tango-classics/</guid>
      <description>US readers might be interested that widely acclaimed music service Spotify launches in the US today. And can start listening to the classics of Argentine tango right away. The playlists are mostly complete to the degree that the music is actually available on Spotify.
That&amp;rsquo;s all.
EDIT: New URL for Classics of Argentine tango on Spotify.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baroque Zamba</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/04/11/baroque-zamba/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2011 20:59:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/04/11/baroque-zamba/</guid>
      <description>Going to Argentina for the tango, you end up falling in love with other things Argentine as well. One of these things is the Zamba, not to be confused with its Brazilian homonym homophone.
Imagine the surprised look on Simba&amp;rsquo;s face listening to a radio show reviewing some new &amp;lsquo;classical&amp;rsquo; releases. Suddenly they play an Argentine Zamba, or at least something very similar. The cd in question was the new release from the Clematis Ensemble with music by composer Mateo Romero.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classics of Tango Dance Music on Spotify</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/11/15/classics-of-tango-dance-music-on-spotify/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2010 17:14:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/11/15/classics-of-tango-dance-music-on-spotify/</guid>
      <description>I believe the only way to come to understand the tango is by listening a lot to tango music. Music appreciation classes are all great, but no substitute for putting in hours and hours of listening. For our beginning classes we have always encouraged our students to start listening to tango music right away. We used to give them a free cd, but while feeling quite ok about this morally, it was a bit on the gray side, legally.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>