<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Canning on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/tags/canning/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Canning on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/tags/canning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Nice floor</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/04/05/nice-floor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2009 01:09:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/04/05/nice-floor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/simba_tango/3412580615/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3618/3412580615_6e4dab4685.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Hardwood floor/Piso madero by Simba tango, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/simba_tango/&#34;&gt; Simba tango&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simba found a new cage. It has the most lovely hardwood floor. Parquet. Yum-ba! We&amp;rsquo;ll see how much milongas there will be in the new town, but Simba already started patrolling the new territory with enrosques and paradas thrown in here and there. And it is smooooth! So at least some private dancing inside the cave, while guarding the offspring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must admit floors mean a lot more to me after dancing tango for a while than they did before. I remember going to my first tango festival, and the more experienced dancers were discussing the quality of the floors in the different venues. ¿Que? A floor is a floor is a floor, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not so, some are soft, some are hard, smooth, slippy. Some are actually adding significantly to the dancing experience. Like the floor at Canning. Wow! A lot of nice places have terrible floors, though, so it&amp;rsquo;s not &lt;strong&gt;that&lt;/strong&gt; important, but I get all giggly inside whenever I step onto the floor at Canning. Sigh!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango magazines -- preparing for Buenos Aires</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/19/tango-magazines-preparing-for-buenos-aires/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2008 22:19:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/19/tango-magazines-preparing-for-buenos-aires/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some of our students are going to Buenos Aires &lt;em&gt;tomorrow&lt;/em&gt;. Oh the memories&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made sure they were equipped with the latest editions of &lt;a href=&#34;http://eltangauta.com/&#34;&gt;El tangauta&lt;/a&gt; and B.A. Tango, giving a good overview over the happenings in November and December. They were always hard to get, even if they are given away for free, it could easily take a couple of weeks before we got hold of an issue. Now, they are available online, and one can prepare for the first week at home or on the plane down there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really wish I could be at Canning and see Cristhian and Samantha&amp;rsquo;s performance on Friday Thursday&amp;hellip; And Thursday the 27th is a tough one: &lt;a href=&#34;http://2xtango.com/es/2008/10/16/jueves-27-de-noviembre-bailan-javier-rodriguez-andrea-misse/&#34;&gt;Andrea y Javier in one milonga&lt;/a&gt;, Orquesta Típica Sans Souci and performance by Fabian Peralta y Virginia Pandolfi in another. And Niño Bien, of course. Well, ain&amp;rsquo;t I lucky that will not have to choose&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To prepare for Buenos Aires or just to keep en eye on what&amp;rsquo;s going on down there:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://eltangauta.com/&#34;&gt;El tangauta&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;B.A. Tango: Send an email to abatango@yahoo.com with the subject line &amp;ldquo;Suscripción&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Subscription&amp;rdquo; and you will receive each number as a pdf file, both the colour magazine and the quarterly guide.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2xtango.com&#34;&gt;2xtango online magazine&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://feeds.feedburner.com/2xtango/es&#34;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salón Canning</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/06/salon-canning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2008 23:08:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/06/salon-canning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/11/canning.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/11/canning.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Salón Canning&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realize that the guys at Movement invites movement are not afraid of provocation, but I think they suffer a tiny bit from a syndrome often associated with Gringos, shooting from the waist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In their &lt;a href=&#34;http://movementinvitesmovement.wordpress.com/2008/10/28/gringo-milongas/&#34;&gt;rant abot Canning&lt;/a&gt;,  they fail to recognize a few important reasons Canning has such an important position. Aside from being one of the very best floors in the city (maybe &lt;em&gt;the very best&lt;/em&gt;), it attracts many excellent dancers. Both local and visitors. Both traditional and nuevo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also happens to be the one milonga that stayed open during the dirty war when tango dancing in effect was prohibited in Argentina. This is probably part of the reason why it is indeed the &lt;em&gt;famous&lt;/em&gt; Canning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, I believe &lt;a href=&#34;http://parakultural.com.ar/&#34;&gt;Parakultural&lt;/a&gt;, the organizer on Mondays and Fridays was one of the first in the revival of tango 10-15 years ago, and this is why these days are among the most popular at Canning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, Parakultural may be a victim of its own success, and the most busy hours, it can be practically impossible to get around the dance floor. It only takes one couple to ruin the flow of an entire floor, and when the floor is packed, well, you get stuck. It usually gets better later in the night after most of the turistas go home ;-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, for us who enjoy walking and good rotation on the dance floor, the milongas out of the centre may be a better alternative. Sigh. If only I were there too&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://flickr.com/photos/julianrod/174362538/&#34;&gt;Photo&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;http://flickr.com/photos/julianrod/&#34;&gt;julianrod&lt;/a&gt;@flickr, &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/deed.en&#34;&gt;CC-licensed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>