<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quotes on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/categories/quotes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Quotes on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2009 13:19:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/categories/quotes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Silencio</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/04/25/silencio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2009 13:19:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/04/25/silencio/</guid>
      <description>by entropiK
El que hace bien el silencio, hace bien el tango (Who plays the silence well, plays the tango well)   Osvaldo Requena      My favorite quote from the outstanding Café de los Maestros documentary. I just wanted to watch it all over again as soon as it was finished. ¡Que sentimiento! ¡Que pasión!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reinvention</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/16/reinvention/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2009 15:31:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/16/reinvention/</guid>
      <description>by pallotron
&#34;Those who don&#39;t understand [Tango] are condemned to reinvent it, poorly.&#34;   – Henry Spencer (about Unix)    I believe Miguel Angel Zotto to have said something along the same lines, that if you do not understand tango, how can you possibly improve it? I can&amp;rsquo;t seem to find the reference, though.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technique vs. Feeling</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/27/technique-vs-feeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2008 21:42:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/27/technique-vs-feeling/</guid>
      <description>by my hovercraft is full of eels
Which one is most important? Technique or dancing with feeling? I sometimes get the impression that tango dancers are divided in two camps, the technique camp and the feelings camp. The first emphasizes the technical matters of the dance, the latter paying solely attention to the feeling. As long as we can hug each other, all is well ;-) Both seemingly ignoring the other point of view completely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The tyranny of novelty</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/23/the-tyranny-of-novelty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2008 22:02:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/23/the-tyranny-of-novelty/</guid>
      <description>by Jacob Bøtter
The man who has journeyed all over the world can&#39;t find any novelty in five thousand miles, for he finds only new things -- yet another novelty, the old routine of the forever new -- while his abstract concept of novelty got lost at sea after the second new thing he saw.   _The Book of Disquiet (171) by Fernando Pessoa_    As in fashion, people in dance seem always to be chasing the new black.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Putting the baby to sleep</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/14/putting-the-baby-to-sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 20:49:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/14/putting-the-baby-to-sleep/</guid>
      <description>I quite recently became a father, and the poor child is exposed to a lot of tango music, naturally. (And I get out to dance less, hence the blog writing.) Before he was born, I used to talk about how we would practice walking together, he and I. Now this is how it turned out:
The scene: Unpatiant 12 days old boy, waiting for his mother to get ready for breast-feeding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More on less</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/21/more-on-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2008 20:30:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/21/more-on-less/</guid>
      <description>I just read an interview with this year&amp;rsquo;s campeones, Daniel Nacucchio &amp;amp; Cristina Sosa (congratulations, and nice to see Neri &amp;amp; Yanina did well also :-) - Well, he quoted old milonguero wisdom:
El que menos hace, a veces es el que hace más Which means something like, the one who does less, sometimes is the one that does more. (Forgive my translation, neither Spanish nor English is my native language).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More or less?</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/08/07/more-or-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2008 18:26:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/08/07/more-or-less/</guid>
      <description>To quote Mies van der Rohe, less is more. As in architecture, this is very true in tango, I think. I was always accused of being subtle in my dancing (I always suspected it to be a euphemism for unclear, vague or not present). To my great surprise, after many years learning to dance the milonga - yes learning the milonga, more on this later - one of the things I really had to work on being more subtle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gavito Dixit</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/06/01/gavito-dixit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 15:26:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/06/01/gavito-dixit/</guid>
      <description>Gavito Dixit I ¿Bailaste el tango de tu vida esta noche? No bailes más… El tangauta #129
Gavito Dixit II El tango está entre paso y paso, allí donde se escuchan los silencios y cantan las musas. El tangauta #130
Gavito Dixit III El hombre debe saber que baila para ella,y al hacerlo, hace que ella se vea como una reina. Sólo así será el rey. El tangauta #131</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>