<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hiroshi Amp Kyoko on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/tags/hiroshi-amp-kyoko/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hiroshi Amp Kyoko on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 01:49:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/tags/hiroshi-amp-kyoko/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Japan Update</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/10/01/japan-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 01:49:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/10/01/japan-update/</guid>
      <description>Finally somevideos of the new champions. Bear over with the person holding the camera not being able to keep still, and make sure you get the milonga at the end. The Argentine newspaper Clarin has a short interview with them.
I mentioned in a previous post that Japan was important because of the collectors of tango music there, and Royce recently posted several posts (here, here and here [UPDATE: She added part 4, part 5 and part 6] ) on this topic that are well worth a read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big in Japan</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/01/big-in-japan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:05:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/01/big-in-japan/</guid>
      <description>by skyseeker
Seeing the reactions from many after the Japanese couple Hiroshi &amp;amp; Kyoko Yamao won the mundial de tango salón as the first non-Argentines, it seems many in the tango world are unaware of the long traditions of tango in Japan. Or maybe some practice selective memory&amp;hellip;
Todotango has an interesting article on the rise of tango in Japan. While the tradition is certainly shorter in terms of years since the first impact than in Europe (Megata&amp;rsquo;s first contact with tango was in Paris in the 1920s), it does not lack much, and in a way it represents a tradition closer to the original than in Europe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Campeones mundiales de tango salon 2009: Hiroshi &amp; Kyoko Yamao (JP)</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/30/campeones-mundiales-de-tango-salon-2009-hiroshi-kyoko-yamao-jp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2009 01:27:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/30/campeones-mundiales-de-tango-salon-2009-hiroshi-kyoko-yamao-jp/</guid>
      <description>I have wondered whether the Argentine would ever select a non-argentine couple to win the tango salon category. Now I know, the fabulous Japanese couple Hiroshi &amp;amp; Kyoko just won the first prize! Great dancers and great people! Felicitaciones!!!
UPDATE:
2xtango got pictures and video from the last ronda with Hiroshi and Kyoko and a nice post about the winners. Also Hiroshi and Kyoko have some pictures at their blog (machine translated from Japanese).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>