<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tango Snob on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/tags/tango-snob/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tango Snob on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/tags/tango-snob/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Whiskey Tango Foxtrot</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/03/11/whiskey-tango-foxtrot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2010 20:09:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/03/11/whiskey-tango-foxtrot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/hbaxter/4323383702/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4048/4323383702_2e492ff2bb.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;_MG_7930 by hdeb89, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/hbaxter/&#34;&gt; hdeb89&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was dancing a nice tanda with a friend of a friend, and while it was not exactly my favorite music, we were doing fine. We were having a good time. There were lots of people dancing, nobody got hurt, and we were dancing peacefully among the other couples. So far so good&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I appreciated the festival organizers&amp;rsquo; effort to give some extra credit to the djs. I belive they wanted to send a message. But as much as I love that the art of djing is seen as more important than it used to on the northern hemisphere, there is a flip side to it.  They had hired one of the most famous djs in Europe at the time, probably the most famous. He should know what he was doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then it happened. I sensed something was wrong. This was several years back, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t instantly recognize it, but there was something strange with the music. It didn&amp;rsquo;t inspire. It didn&amp;rsquo;t fit in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn&amp;rsquo;t tango.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dj was being clever. He had played a tango which has some kind of train imitating sounds, much like you find in some blues tunes. Funny. Why not match it with another song with similar sound?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because it is a foxtrot, maybe?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello!? We are dancing tango, and you throw in a foxtrot? W.. T.. F..?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After dutifully finishing the tanda, I went for the exit. Completely threw me off the flow. On the way out, I saw the dj waving to the crowd, the crowd returned the gesture, doing the wave in return. I shivered, and went alone out in the rain, leaving my last festival behind.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>