<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tango Research on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/tags/tango-research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tango Research on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2015 19:22:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/tags/tango-research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Perfect Embrace</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2015/02/14/the-perfect-embrace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2015 19:22:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2015/02/14/the-perfect-embrace/</guid>
      <description>by virgoh
Of course, this is nothing new to tango dancers, but understanding the mechanisms is interesting:
A caress feels best when it is delivered with a small amount of force and a speed of about 1 inch per second. Stroke slower, and it feels like an unwelcome crawling bug; faster, and it feels perfunctory rather than loving.  Perform your caress not on the glabrous skin of the palm or sole, but on the hairy skin of the limbs where the caress sensing fibers are found.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BPM</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2013/03/29/bpm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 19:41:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2013/03/29/bpm/</guid>
      <description>by Paul Graham Raven
The advances in DSP and processing power since I started ripping my cds to store all my music on a computer drive are enormous.
Sometimes having an estimate of the BPM of a tango song can be useful, e.g. when searching for &amp;ldquo;slow&amp;rdquo; milongas, sorting by BPM would be useful. But tapping each song individually to store in tags &amp;ndash; no way it&amp;rsquo;s worth the effort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Audio Restoration from Multiple Copies</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2013/03/27/audio-restoration-from-multiple-copies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 18:53:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2013/03/27/audio-restoration-from-multiple-copies/</guid>
      <description>I was pondering the usefulness of noise removal based on several copies of a recording, possibly from different physical copies. A Google search reveals that such a technique is already patented:
The present invention provides a method for reducing noise using a plurality of recording copies. The present invention produces a master file with lower noise than the available recording copies, and avoids the problems of losing musical content caused by prior art pop and click removers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letras de Non-Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/06/30/letras-de-non-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 18:23:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/06/30/letras-de-non-tango/</guid>
      <description>Maybe you remember my Letras de Tango post a while back, showing the most used words in tango lyrics. The possibility of doing something similar for other genres/pop music was raised in the comments. And the guys over at last.fm just did exactly that. So head over and have a look at their graphics for Blues, Country, Electronic, Folk, Goth, Hip-Hop, Indie, Metal, Rap, Rock and Soul. They also did some interesting distance charts, showing graphically how similar the lyrics of different genres are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango Recordings Through the Year</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/04/05/tango-recordings-through-the-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 19:22:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/04/05/tango-recordings-through-the-year/</guid>
      <description>When were the different tangos recorded? From the 9233 unique recordings identified with exact recording date in the tango.info database we can see that not surprisingly there is low activity during summer, more specifically during January and February, it then picks up with peaks in June, September and December. Splitting the numbers over the decades makes a slightly more confusing picture.
If you want to check out the recordings for one specific date, there is now a nifty feature over at tango.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letras de tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/03/29/letras-de-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2010 09:14:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/03/29/letras-de-tango/</guid>
      <description>We all know that tango is about lost love, broken hearts, right? Well &amp;ndash; now we can check it out. Hans at Amsterdam tango club put all the 13,000 lyrics they got in their online database in a single html file, which made it rather easy to do some statistics. I wrote a small script, counting the occurrences of each word, and the figure above is a representation of the results, but leaving the very shortest words like y, o, el, lo etc out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance Insights</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/11/16/performance-insights/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2009 13:52:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/11/16/performance-insights/</guid>
      <description>As I was uploading a couple of new videos at youtube, I noticed the &amp;lsquo;Attention&amp;rsquo; ranking of my videos in the &amp;lsquo;Insights&amp;rsquo; section. The video with most attention (showed by a red bar like in the illustration top centre) is a video showing Jorge Dispari and María &amp;lsquo;La Turca&amp;rsquo; del Carmen at Confitería Ideal. At the time of writing, this video has been viewed 11 852 times.
Youtube describes the calculation of the video &amp;lsquo;hot spots&amp;rsquo; like this: &amp;rdquo;The ups-and-downs of viewership at each moment in your video, compared to videos of similar length.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Golden Age Visualized</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/10/17/the-golden-age-visualized/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2009 03:28:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/10/17/the-golden-age-visualized/</guid>
      <description>Golden Age of Tango When was the Golden Age of tango, exactly? It is fairly common to say 1935-1955 mas o menos, but while I was playing around with the data at tango.info, I thought it would be fun to make a plot to **see when the Golden Age was. And here it is. **
These are the number of unique recordings in the database, so if a recording is issued on several cds, it is only counted once.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From &#39;Band Union&#39; to bandoneón?</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/28/from-band-union-to-bandoneon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 14:54:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/28/from-band-union-to-bandoneon/</guid>
      <description>by Rüdis Fotos
What is the origin of the word bandoneón? Two competing theories exist. They both agree that the instrument is somehow named after the assumed inventor, Heinrich Band.
 The name &amp;lsquo;Band Union&amp;rsquo; was used by Heinrich Band and partners, and it got mispronounced and reinterpreted in Argentina as bandoneón.
 The name was invented by Band or others based on the naming of other instruments such as the accordion, Band + ion was transformed into bandonion, which in turn became bandoneón in Argentina.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On circulation</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/11/on-circulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2009 00:57:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/11/on-circulation/</guid>
      <description>by pdcawley
Ms Hedgehog is researching the dynamics of flow in the ronda, comparing with traffic and pondering about the importance of song length.
While song length can probably have some influence, I believe other factors are much more significant. And it is kind of hard to perform real experiments, even though she deserves credit for the attempt.
According to Jorge Dispari, the flow on the dance floors of Buenos Aires used to be much better than today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Song numbers</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/03/11/song-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2009 20:12:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/03/11/song-numbers/</guid>
      <description>by Stewf
Some songs are more popular than others, and some are harder to find than others. Sometimes you have to buy an entire disc full of songs you already have to get just that song. So my library of tango music has a lot of duplicates. And more, is there a word like elevenicates?
So the most popular songs are probably available on a lot of records, I figured, and out of curiosity, I checked which were the most popular in my collection, this is for all songs that I have the recording date (from tango.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rose in mouth</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/13/rose-in-mouth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2009 22:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/13/rose-in-mouth/</guid>
      <description>by alyssathiele
The tango cliché of dancing with a rose in the mouth is quite fascinating. It is everywhere, and everybody doing argentine tango wants absolutely nothing to do with it. But where does it come from?
I have often seen it associated with the silent movie star Rudolph Valentino, and suggested that it first appeared in the movie Four Horsemen of the Apocalypse (1921). So being curious, I had to check this out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volume adjustments for tango music</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/07/volume-adjustments-for-tango-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2009 13:55:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/07/volume-adjustments-for-tango-music/</guid>
      <description>There was some discussion on the tangodj mailing list about the use of Replay Gain for tango music. I have used it for several years, and found it to be immensely useful. As you can see from the histogram above, the loudness of cd releases varies a lot, and Replay Gain makes automatic adjustments to make the loundess more or less the same. It does a lot better than I do, that&amp;rsquo;s for sure, and frees up time for the more interesting parts of the djing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Popularity contest: dancers@youtube</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/07/popularity-contest-dancersyoutube/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2008 21:24:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/07/popularity-contest-dancersyoutube/</guid>
      <description>by strollerdos
Following up on the first popularity contest, I wanted to check how popular these dancers are on YouTube&amp;hellip; I used the 20 most popular from the google search numbers. Searching first for name and tango, then selecting the number of views from the most viewed video.
Here are the results: 1 

Julio Balmaceda 
520,941   2 

Juan Carlos Copes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Popularity contest: dancers@google</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/30/popularity-contest-dancersgoogle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2008 22:48:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/30/popularity-contest-dancersgoogle/</guid>
      <description>by geckoam
Out of curiosity I started googling some more and less famous dancers, to compare popularity on the web. Some interesting results&amp;hellip;
Methodology: I simply searched for the complete name (exact phrase) as listed below and the word &amp;ldquo;tango&amp;rdquo; and made a note of the number of hits. Suggestions for improvements and important omissions are welcome. The ones best known by their first name or nickname are a bit tricky, but this is the result so far.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>