<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tango In Film on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/tags/tango-in-film/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tango In Film on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/tags/tango-in-film/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Tango Movies: &#34;Tanguero&#34; and &#34;La cantante de tango&#34;</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/11/12/upcoming-tango-movies-tanguero-and-la-cantante-de-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2010 17:16:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/11/12/upcoming-tango-movies-tanguero-and-la-cantante-de-tango/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;A short update on a couple of upcoming tango movies. I find it somewhat promising that none of them seem to be about a middle aged dancer or hit man coming to Buenos Aires and there discovering tango and through it, themselves. Still, they may include other clichés such as lost love and finding oneself through tango:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tanguero&#34;&gt;Tanguero&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Omar, a Tango instructor, is forced to return to Buenos Aires because of an important phone call. He discovers an unrecognizable city, meets relatives, old friends and meets Veronica, his childhood friend. They remember the time they had spent together years before and decide to take on a difficult challenge. That’s how Omar rediscovers himself in Tango.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tangueromovie.com/&#34;&gt;Tanguero&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;la-cantante-de-tango&#34;&gt;La cantante de tango&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/_VIzIi-ii7U&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;Helena, una talentosa cantante de tango, se encuentra profundamente enamorada. Cuando consigue presentarse en un prestigioso teatro de Buenos Aires, su carrera parece despegar. Pero justo en ese momento la alcanza la tragedia: el hombre que ella ama ya no está enamorado de ella. Obsesionada y torturada por su pérdida, no puede recuperarse de su ruptura y lentamente se convierte en una sombra de la mujer que solía ser. Pero ¿Y si dejara atrás la pena y se atreviera a una nueva vida en un país distinto? Quizás así Helena podría también dejar atrás el dolor y,  lentamente, aprender a vivir y amar de nuevo.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://lacantantedetango.com.ar/&#34;&gt;La cantante de tango&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HT: &lt;a href=&#34;http://tinatangos.com/blog/&#34;&gt;Tina&lt;/a&gt; (Tanguero) and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.2xtango.com/?p=7720&#34;&gt;2XTango&lt;/a&gt; (La cantante de tango)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valentina&#39;s Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/25/valentinas-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2009 03:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/25/valentinas-tango/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/valentinas-tango.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;valentinas-tango&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got a tip about this film that I never heard about, starring rightly famous tango dancer Guillermina Quiroga, arguably one of the best female show dancers of our time. Browsing the reviews online, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really sure this was something for me, but as it was available on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.netflix.com/&#34;&gt;Netflix&lt;/a&gt;, I decided to give Guillermina a chance. This is what Netflix writes about the film:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Teetering on the edge of madness, striking dancer Valentina (Guillermina Quiriga) keeps the obsessive love she has for her husband, Eduardo (Jordi Caballero), in check by dancing the tango with him. But as time goes on, she slowly drifts into insanity. As Valentina&#39;s family tries to rescue her, they instead find themselves drawn into her nightmarish world. George Perez and Dianna Miranda co-star in this passionate drama peppered with dark comedy.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watched this movie right after reading this, and I had to re-read it just after finishing it, as I couldn&amp;rsquo;t really make it fit. It is all written in codes, you see. Let me translate that for you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tango dancer Valentina (Guillermina Quiroga) has an &amp;ndash; uhm &amp;ndash; unusal apetite for her husband Eduardo (Jordi Caballero). Performing with him is essential to keeping her satisfied. When he gets hurt so he can&amp;rsquo;t dance, she starts drinking and dreaming. While Eduardo cannot run his club, the couple&amp;rsquo;s grown up sons create an awful mess. George Perez and Dianna  Miranda co-star in this meant to be erotic drama with occational black humour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A rather embarrasing affair, to be honest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not even the dancing is up to par, it takes two to tango, and Guillermina&amp;rsquo;s partners aren&amp;rsquo;t really up to the task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt; While occationally funny, it is clearly going to the &amp;lsquo;stay away from&amp;rsquo;-list together with Tango fatal. What is it with tango and film&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Funny observation:&lt;/strong&gt; It struck me that the male dancer in the animated short &lt;em&gt;En tus brazos&lt;/em&gt; that &lt;a href=&#34;simbatango.com/2009/06/24/great-tango-shorts/&#34;&gt;I mentioned&lt;/a&gt; a while ago might well be modeled after the Eduardo character in Valentina&amp;rsquo;s Tango, wheelchair and all.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nice film tangos</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/20/nice-film-tangos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2009 20:44:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/20/nice-film-tangos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;ldquo;&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;600&amp;rdquo; caption=&amp;ldquo;From Happy Together&amp;rdquo;]&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.timezone.fr/uploaded_images/happy_together_tony_leslie_8_d302bfe6a3de421aa6c37d9b4627eca7-798476.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;From Happy Together&#34; /&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, tango is not always portrayed as completely kitsch in films. So I found that a handful of very nice films, with equally nice tango mandated a post of its own. These are all highly recommended, tango or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0118845/&#34;&gt;Happy together&lt;/a&gt; by Wong Kar-Wai. He is actually one of my favourite directors, and uses tango as one way to tell us about the relationship and love between two people. One of whom work for some time in a tango bar in Buenos Aires. Not in a cliched fashion, which is quite a feat, given &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/05/24/tango-in-popular-culture/&#34;&gt;what is out there&lt;/a&gt;. Come to think of it, I probably should see this film again sometime soon myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the eccentric characters in the Almodóvaresque &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0310001/&#34;&gt;Piedras&lt;/a&gt; by Spanish director Ramón Salazar, actually go to a milongas. The man, who is an Argentine brings a women, and he talks to her about the Argentine saying &amp;lsquo;Sacando viruta al piso&amp;rsquo;.  As far as I can remember, the dancing in the Madrid milonga was quite &amp;lsquo;authentic&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0436445/&#34;&gt;No suis là pour être aimé&lt;/a&gt; (Not here to be loved) almost made it to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/04/19/tango-film-club/&#34;&gt;film club post&lt;/a&gt;, as the main characters in this movie actually take tango lessons. And the lessons have a profound impact on the characters&amp;rsquo; lives. In addition, they watch a show by Geraldine and Javier. So plenty of tango, and a nice film. How she came to fall for him is still a mystery, though. Never underestimate the power of tango, I guess&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it is indeed possible. There must be more that I am unaware of or have forgotten. What are your favourites?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clichés</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/06/clich%C3%A9s/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2008 10:31:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/06/clich%C3%A9s/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever since I started dancing, the topic of tango clichés has fascinated me. The rose in mouth, castanets, head flicks, dramatic poses are all parts of what usually pops into people&amp;rsquo;s heads when they hear the word tango. Where did they come from, and why did they stick? Going through a lot of Hollywood production at least gives a partial answer, and Rudolph Valentino is one of the people to blame, the rose in mouth appears in the film &lt;em&gt;Blood and sand&lt;/em&gt;, where he plays a bullfighter, while the film he dances the tango is _Four horsemen of the apocalypse. _The tango in &lt;em&gt;Some like it hot&lt;/em&gt; must have reinforced the image further into the public memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what lies behind the clichés, do they reveal something of interest, which we may overlook, just because the cliché is so easily dismissed? Could the tango have more important influence from the flamenco than is commonly acknowledged? The rose at least played a role in the real tango porteño in the way that the orchestra of Pugliese used a single rose on the piano during their performances to mark the maestro&amp;rsquo;s absence while he was held in prison for his political beliefs. The head flicks seem to come from the ballroom version of tango, and to my knowledge they have little relation to the &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; tango. Many of the dramatic poses, though, could have their roots in early tango moves such as cortes and quebradas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/images/pugliese_ausencia.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Osvaldo Pugliese in absentia&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, many sayings about tango, are often dismissed as being &lt;em&gt;merely clichés&lt;/em&gt;, but I have found that many of them go deeper than we first think. That tango is really about dancing for the woman is one such statement. Often heard, rarely seen outside Buenos Aires, is my experience. Even by those who say it.  I heard women talk about this for years, &lt;em&gt;X dances for himself&lt;/em&gt; etc. It took me many years before I started noticing what they were &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; talking about. But when I finally realized, it transformed my way of seeing tango, both my own and others&amp;rsquo;. It may appear superficial, a subtle adjustment, a cliché. In fact, what is needed is a fundamental change. Starting to dance for the woman, rather for one self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now read those &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/index.php/2008/06/01/gavito-dixit/&#34;&gt;Gavito quotes&lt;/a&gt; again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>