<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Djing on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>https://simbatango.github.io/tags/djing/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Djing on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="https://simbatango.github.io/tags/djing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>A Better Slogan</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2010/05/28/a-better-slogan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2010 20:50:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2010/05/28/a-better-slogan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/66164549@N00/2080363220/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2250/2080363220_d46ea28d4a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The King... by law_keven, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-sa/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/66164549@N00/&#34;&gt; law_keven&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time to upgrade my deejaying slogan. While I still sort of like the tongue in cheek fluffy deejay advertisment in-joke of **&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/01/06/keine-komische-musik/&#34;&gt;Keine komische Musik&lt;/a&gt;, **it has several problems. It is in German, and doesn&amp;rsquo;t really translate well. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure people get the joke, they may not even understand German. Also it may come off a bit negative. I would prefer a more positive note, so to speak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still in my somewhat sarcastic and protestish mood, I came up with **The Non-Alternative Alternative. **While it is probably somehow accurate, it also fails the non-negativity criterion, and while the recursive definition is all geeky and nice, it is sort of syllogistic, so better move on to something more straight to the point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resolving the recursion and going back to the basics, what about **Puro Tango &lt;strong&gt;or in English &lt;/strong&gt;Pure Tango**? This has the nice property that it translates well to English. It is close to the spirit of my milongas, tango pure and simple. The best music. But it is not quite true. Besides vals and milonga, I occationally play other music as well: Chacarera has recently become popular in my community, and I have played Cumbia in the past, some times Rock &amp;lsquo;n Roll, Swing or Salsa music. Despite rumors to the contrary I don&amp;rsquo;t even have a strict rule never to play electrotango, it&amp;rsquo;s just that I always find something better in my collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the last milonga I deejayed, a friend told me how one of the guys &amp;ldquo;complained&amp;rdquo; that he never got to rest. &amp;ndash;He&amp;rsquo;s killing me! That was a great compliment, I think, so maybe I could use it&amp;hellip;  **DJ Simba: **&lt;strong&gt;Killing You Softly.&lt;/strong&gt; That would be something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I deejay under a different alias, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work quite that well in that case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;****Then I remembered something from a &lt;a href=&#34;http://tangopilgrim.com/2010/04/danceable-music-and-dance-ability/&#34;&gt;discussion over at tangopilgrim&lt;/a&gt;. Great (tango) dance music should make you want to move, but it should also be &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/moving&#34;&gt;moving&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;La música que te mueve&lt;/strong&gt; could work. It translates well to English, for instance as &lt;strong&gt;Moving Music&lt;/strong&gt; or alternatively &lt;strong&gt;(The )Music that Moves You&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally at the essence of what it&amp;rsquo;s all about. It&amp;rsquo;s positive, I get an alliteration and it translates well, also to my native language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you think? How do you native speakers feel about the two last ones?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Showing off</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2008/12/10/showing-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2008 22:12:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2008/12/10/showing-off/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/ku_non/105677936/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/52/105677936_943d6756f8.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Peacock by *- mika -*, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/ku_non/&#34;&gt; &lt;em&gt;- mika -&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who hasn&amp;rsquo;t been tempted&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; to do some flashy moves when someone sitting next to the dance floor watches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; to show all the tricks of the trade when getting to dance with a really good dancer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; to play some obscure gem from the record collection when djing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; to  play some &lt;insert non-tango genre here&gt; music to be innovative&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is, it does not impress anyone. Least of all the ones you try to impress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is just annoying. I am not impressed when you do a jump on the floor of a milonga, I have to make an effort not to start laughing (yes &amp;ndash; this happened). I am not impressed when you play Madonna (this too), just irritated that I have to wait 15 more minutes until there is a slight chance of getting some danceable music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A dj that plays great dance music all night long without directing attention to himself. A performance of pure excellent movement in harmony with the music, both letting the other shine. Now &lt;strong&gt;that&lt;/strong&gt; is impressive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I started DJing</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2008/11/17/how-i-started-djing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2008 15:44:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2008/11/17/how-i-started-djing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://flickr.com/photos/emotionblog/31746277/sizes/l/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/11/turntable.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Turntable&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/emotionblog/&#34;&gt; AllegaertMe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started dancing tango, the &amp;ldquo;milonga&amp;rdquo; was in a café where we basically heard the same double &lt;a href=&#34;http://musicbrainz.org/release/980413af-3c95-445e-9855-0f975c1f0f13.html&#34;&gt;cd&lt;/a&gt; over and over and over. In general, everybody knew exactly what song came next and started humming on the next song before it started. Knowing the music is all good, but,  well&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-I guess I would start djing, was the dry comment from an American dancer we met in Bs As a few years ago when I told this story. Well, as it happens that was exactly what I ended up doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, that was a long time ago, up in the ice desert, so not much tango music available, and nobody really seemed to care (about the music), don&amp;rsquo;t ask me why. And nobody knew about tango djs, apparently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some dancers in our community had been to Argentina, but they all moved out of town. And none of the active dancers in our community had been there. So when I went with my partner (later wife), we were kind of breaking new ground. And much so in the case of tango music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As many others starting out in tango, I found the typical tango to be dull sounding, and it all sounded much the same to me. So I was searching for new recordings with fresh sound. After searching record stores in my home town, I found little other than Piazzolla, but coming to Zival&amp;rsquo;s in Buenos Aires, the selection was huge. (You will have to remember that this was before the wealth of information available online today, and it was before the crisis in Argentina, so everything there was pretty expensive.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I had no idea what to search for, but I had a list from my teachers in Buenos Aires, with strange names like Troilo, D&amp;rsquo;Arienzo and Pugliese&amp;hellip;  Most cds were short on milongas and valses, so I remember using the number of vals and milonga on a cd as a selection criterion. In retrospect, it all went really well, my next record extravaganza was far from as successful. I also  bought modern orchestras like El Arranque, Color tango and Los cosos de al lao. As s many others, I have grown to prefer the classic recordings, but that&amp;rsquo;s a different story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, and they did not play it like on our cd in the milongas, (3 tangos, 1 milonga, 1 vals, repeat). There was this concept of tandas and cortinas. I found some information on the web, &lt;a href=&#34;http://tejastango.com/tango_music.html&#34;&gt;Stephen Browns pages&lt;/a&gt; were a great help I remember, but the concept was unheard of in my local town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back from Bs As, I started assembling tandas of similar sounding music sitting on our livingroom floor, writing notes, this and that track from this cd, then this and that track from that cd, and then all the cds to the computer in the office to create a cd of precompiled tandas&amp;hellip;  A lot of work, and far too little music to make a good selection. But it was the start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward a few years, and I have a real collection of tango music (You really like D&amp;rsquo;Arienzo, don&amp;rsquo;t you? asked one visiting instructor, borrowing some cds for classes) all neatly tagged on my computer for instant access and on-the-fly tanda composition at the milonga. I did a lot of mistakes on the way, of course, but I have improved vastly. And people are finally starting to pay attention to the music in my local community, and we have a few aspiring djs for whom I gave a seminar on tango djing last year. Now even more are interested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Encouraging.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>