<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Community Building on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/categories/community-building/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Community Building on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2009 19:20:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/categories/community-building/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to organize a Milonga</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/07/how-to-organize-a-milonga/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2009 19:20:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/07/how-to-organize-a-milonga/</guid>
      <description>by Chris and Sue
Starting a milonga is easy, right? You just need a place to dance, put some music on, and there you go&amp;hellip;
&amp;hellip;well not exactly. There are lots of small and not so small details that work together to create a good environment for social dancing. Based on my experience as organizer of both unsuccessful events and much more successful events and experience from various milongas and practicas over the world, I attempt to gather some advice on how to approximate the authentic milonga in your own community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Urban dance</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/24/urban-dance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2009 20:09:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/24/urban-dance/</guid>
      <description>by lrargerich
Tango is and always was a very urban culture. The dance even more so. Sometimes visitors to Buenos Aires that are tango dancers somehow expect everybody they meet to be a dancer, and taxi drivers to know all the milongas by name.
Not so.
Even in Buenos Aires, tango dancing is very much a niche activity, and the world of the milongas is very small even in the great city with millions of inhabitants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I started DJing</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/17/how-i-started-djing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2008 15:44:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/17/how-i-started-djing/</guid>
      <description>by AllegaertMe
When I started dancing tango, the &amp;ldquo;milonga&amp;rdquo; was in a café where we basically heard the same double cd over and over and over. In general, everybody knew exactly what song came next and started humming on the next song before it started. Knowing the music is all good, but, well&amp;hellip;
-I guess I would start djing, was the dry comment from an American dancer we met in Bs As a few years ago when I told this story.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>