<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Community Building on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>https://simbatango.github.io/categories/community-building/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Community Building on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="https://simbatango.github.io/categories/community-building/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>How to organize a Milonga</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/06/07/how-to-organize-a-milonga/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2009 19:20:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/06/07/how-to-organize-a-milonga/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/chrisandsue/106645400/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/56/106645400_f90d08881c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Milonga by Chris and Sue, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/chrisandsue/&#34;&gt; Chris and Sue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting a milonga is easy, right? You just need a place to dance, put some music on, and there you go&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;well not exactly. There are lots of small and not so small details that work together to create a good environment for social dancing. Based on my experience as organizer of both unsuccessful events and much more successful events and experience from various milongas and practicas over the world, I attempt to gather some advice on how to approximate the authentic milonga in your own community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;location-location-location&#34;&gt;Location, location, location&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First you need a place &amp;ndash; large enough, but not too large. It really depends on how many attendants you can be expected to draw. To create the right social dynamics, it is necessary to feel that people fill the space without making it so crowded it is impossible to move or get a seat. Outside Buenos Aires, problems with the ronda are rarely caused by too little space available, as I discussed in a &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/05/10/on-circulation/&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If possible, choose a not too remote location. It should be easy to get there by public transportation and there should be parking available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not start your milonga in an obscure cafe with a slow night on Mondays because you can stay there for free. There is a reason why that day is a slow night. And tango dancers generally spend little on drinks for some reason, so it won&amp;rsquo;t be a good deal for the owner and you may get thrown out again. And one thing you do want is stability, knowing you won&amp;rsquo;t have to cancel due to some random football match.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, beginners are often intimidated by people watching, which also makes it a good idea to stay off public areas such as cafes or bars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many things may be said about sound system, floor etc, I will concentrate on factors that can be more easily changed in this overview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;time&#34;&gt;Time&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going to the milonga means going out. It is not a workout. Hence, it should be placed accordingly. If there is no regular milonga in your city, I suggest Friday night. Then you avoid most people having to leave early to go to work in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t start too early, let people have time to get home and get ready for their night out. So the exact timing depends on local customs, but 8 PM or 9 PM should work well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;music&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Music&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use a dj that knows what he&amp;rsquo;s doing. Or is willing to learn. Selecting music for a milonga is like cooking, the most important is that it is done &amp;lsquo;con mucho amor&amp;rsquo;. Just putting on a random cd will not cut it. Ideally the dj is not noticed, but facilitates dancing, creating a good mood&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use tandas and cortinas. This is much debated outside Bs As, but I prefer it mainly because it facilitates good dancing and circulation between partners. Remove as many barriers as possible for the activites you promote. Tandas and cortinas also socializes beginners into the general structure of a milonga and makes it easier for them to appreciate changes in the music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only play &lt;a href=&#34;http://tejastango.com/tango_music.html&#34;&gt;the good stuff&lt;/a&gt;. This includes playing tango, milonga and vals. Different schemes are possible, 4T-4T-3M-4T-4T-3V usually works well. To get the party going you might consider using 4T-3M-4T-3V the first hour(s).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless it is a niche you feel needs to be filled, avoid playing too much untraditional music. Stay with the true and proven tango music, predominantly golden age music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Play loud enough that the music dominates the venue, but not so lound that it is impossible to talk at the tables. Ideally, talk from the tables should not be disturbing people at the dance floor, but this depends a lot on the sound system installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;layout&#34;&gt;Layout&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need seating, and preferably also tables. Having chairs along the walls does not create a nice atmosphere, rather it mimics the dreaded image of an old fashioned dancing school, where people sit (un)patiently waiting to be asked to dance/nervously trying to gather the courage to move across the floor and ask someone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Place tables surrounding the dance floor. Make space in the corners for easy access to the dance floor. Make it possible to walk around &lt;strong&gt;behind the tables&lt;/strong&gt;. Then people won&amp;rsquo;t have to cross the floor to walk over to their friends, asking someone to dance, going to the bar etc. In fact, make it possible to move around the entire dance floor without ever entering the dance floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Place the tables perpedicular to the edges of the floor with no chair on the end facing the floor nor the oposite end. Keeping chairs with people away from where people move facilitates movement on and off dance floor and avoids intimidating dancers unnecessarily by having people facing the dance floor &amp;lsquo;staring&amp;rsquo; at the dancers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create a rectangular dance floor, but not too stretched out. Use tables to shape the size of the floor on all four sides. However, if your attendance is too small to fill up the tables all around the floor, it is probably better to concentrate people on some sides, and use the walls on the others to avoid rows of empty tables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may seem overly detailed, but these small details actually matter and they require little work to adjust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid to make the dance floor smaller, it often improves flow and behaviour on the dance floor, as people actually need to pay attention to the others on the floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the entrance, it is useful to have someone to take cover charge and greet the guests. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have enough people to have one sitting at the door, you may use the &amp;lsquo;honor system&amp;rsquo;, but be prepared that quite a few of your guests will &amp;lsquo;forget&amp;rsquo; to pay the entrance. Using a list or some other visual reminder by the entrance that payment is expected might improve the honesty rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dj needs to sit so that he can watch the dance floor, changing the music depending on the crowd&amp;rsquo;s reactions and desires. The dj should not have other responsibilites while playing, as that is enough work for one person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lighting&#34;&gt;Lighting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is tempting to lower the lights to create a cozy atmosphere. Resist the temptation and keep it light enough to use the cabeceo and for watching the dance floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;bar&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If possible, it should be a bar where you can buy something to drink (and eat). That includes wine, beer and champagne. Not that drinking much is important, but it reinforces the concept of going out, creating a relaxed social atmosphere. Most tango dancers don&amp;rsquo;t drink much as far as I have experienced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serving at the table is nice, but usually economically unviable in most smaller communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;dresscode&#34;&gt;Dresscode&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dresscode is rarely strictly enforced, but dressing up is part of going to a milonga. It can be encouraged in several ways, by a mild formulation in the listings and by dressing up yourself. Many tango people like to dress up a little, and dressing up implies taking care of personal hygiene, which I have often seen mentioned as tips before &lt;em&gt;going&lt;/em&gt; to the milonga.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, the key words are &lt;strong&gt;going out&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;not workout&lt;/strong&gt;. Leave practice for the practica.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;host&#34;&gt;Host&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If possible, get some help and be available as a host. Greeting people as they come, make them know you appreciate their attendence. Pay extra care to newcomers, possibly introduce them to some dancers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Buenos Aires, you will routinely be escorted to your table, which is a nice gesture. I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen it outside of Buenos Aires, though. Competition for the nice tables would require a really large community, I presume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t engage in heated debates with people who are only up to trouble. Smile and suggest you discuss it some other time, as the milonga is a place to enjoy yourself. Show them the way out if they refuse to stop. People who ruin the night for everybody else are not welcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be a good role model, be nice with everybody and play by the rules yourself. This means dressing up appropriately, greeting people with a smile, dance a little, relax and have a drink :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-crowd&#34;&gt;The crowd&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most important success factors of a milonga is the crowd that frequents the place. This is not something you can control directly, of course, but providing good facilities and above all good music gives you a fair chance to attract the crowd you would like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find that experienced dancers often prefer the real stuff (dancing tango to.. tango music) and tend to arrive late, and stay late. A common arrangement is to cater for beginners early (classses and &amp;lsquo;easy music&amp;rsquo; and for the more experienced (more complex music) later in the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;formal-informal&#34;&gt;Formal/informal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A traditional milonga in Buenos Aires is actually a rather formal event. For some reason people in other parts of the world seem to have a problem with this, and many have as an explicit goal to make an &amp;lsquo;informal&amp;rsquo; atmosphere. In small communities, you will have to strike a balance there, but the more formal atmosphere of the Buenos Aires milongas makes a lot of things easier for dancers once you know the codes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think what they should rather be going for is friendly and positive, rather than informal, some structure makes the night easier to work out for the dancers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the implicit means listed above to facilitate the behaviour without enforcing strictly any rules works well in my experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;pr&#34;&gt;PR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider giving a class before the milonga starts with entrance to the milonga included, as classes often draw more people. This is a commonly used trick to promote milongas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create a clean website with updated information on hours, prices and how to get there. Keep it up to date rather than fancy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make flyers to distribute at other milongas if they exist in your city&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add your milonga to online listings and consider creating an online calendar ala google calendar that people can subscribe to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start a mailing list with information about special events etc.Let people opt in and keep the number of postings low with relevant content. Ask organizers from other places, festivals etc to send you flyers to distribute at your milonga rather than spam your subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Place a table by the entrance with flyers, or place them directly on the tables. Having them in one spot makes it easier to administrate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Advertise truthfully what kind of music people can expect. If you play more than an occational set of alternatives before closing time, make it explicit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Urban dance</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/02/24/urban-dance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2009 20:09:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/02/24/urban-dance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/lrargerich/2983925297/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3225/2983925297_ca40b65a23.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Buenos Aires at Night by lrargerich, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/lrargerich/&#34;&gt; lrargerich&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tango is and always was a very urban culture. The dance even more so. Sometimes visitors to Buenos Aires that are tango dancers somehow expect everybody they meet to be a dancer, and taxi drivers to know all the milongas by name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even in Buenos Aires, tango dancing is very much a niche activity, and the world of the milongas is very small even in the great city with millions of inhabitants. And creating and sustaining a tango scene in a small town next to the north pole is indeed an uphill battle. It requires a certain amount of crazy people to gather week after week in order to listen to grandparents music. And not even their own grandparents&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But where the pool of people reaches a critical size, the tango scene takes on a life of itself. Everywhere else, it needs to be kept alive by someone particularly crazy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I started DJing</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2008/11/17/how-i-started-djing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2008 15:44:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2008/11/17/how-i-started-djing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://flickr.com/photos/emotionblog/31746277/sizes/l/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/11/turntable.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Turntable&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/emotionblog/&#34;&gt; AllegaertMe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started dancing tango, the &amp;ldquo;milonga&amp;rdquo; was in a café where we basically heard the same double &lt;a href=&#34;http://musicbrainz.org/release/980413af-3c95-445e-9855-0f975c1f0f13.html&#34;&gt;cd&lt;/a&gt; over and over and over. In general, everybody knew exactly what song came next and started humming on the next song before it started. Knowing the music is all good, but,  well&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-I guess I would start djing, was the dry comment from an American dancer we met in Bs As a few years ago when I told this story. Well, as it happens that was exactly what I ended up doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, that was a long time ago, up in the ice desert, so not much tango music available, and nobody really seemed to care (about the music), don&amp;rsquo;t ask me why. And nobody knew about tango djs, apparently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some dancers in our community had been to Argentina, but they all moved out of town. And none of the active dancers in our community had been there. So when I went with my partner (later wife), we were kind of breaking new ground. And much so in the case of tango music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As many others starting out in tango, I found the typical tango to be dull sounding, and it all sounded much the same to me. So I was searching for new recordings with fresh sound. After searching record stores in my home town, I found little other than Piazzolla, but coming to Zival&amp;rsquo;s in Buenos Aires, the selection was huge. (You will have to remember that this was before the wealth of information available online today, and it was before the crisis in Argentina, so everything there was pretty expensive.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I had no idea what to search for, but I had a list from my teachers in Buenos Aires, with strange names like Troilo, D&amp;rsquo;Arienzo and Pugliese&amp;hellip;  Most cds were short on milongas and valses, so I remember using the number of vals and milonga on a cd as a selection criterion. In retrospect, it all went really well, my next record extravaganza was far from as successful. I also  bought modern orchestras like El Arranque, Color tango and Los cosos de al lao. As s many others, I have grown to prefer the classic recordings, but that&amp;rsquo;s a different story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, and they did not play it like on our cd in the milongas, (3 tangos, 1 milonga, 1 vals, repeat). There was this concept of tandas and cortinas. I found some information on the web, &lt;a href=&#34;http://tejastango.com/tango_music.html&#34;&gt;Stephen Browns pages&lt;/a&gt; were a great help I remember, but the concept was unheard of in my local town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back from Bs As, I started assembling tandas of similar sounding music sitting on our livingroom floor, writing notes, this and that track from this cd, then this and that track from that cd, and then all the cds to the computer in the office to create a cd of precompiled tandas&amp;hellip;  A lot of work, and far too little music to make a good selection. But it was the start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward a few years, and I have a real collection of tango music (You really like D&amp;rsquo;Arienzo, don&amp;rsquo;t you? asked one visiting instructor, borrowing some cds for classes) all neatly tagged on my computer for instant access and on-the-fly tanda composition at the milonga. I did a lot of mistakes on the way, of course, but I have improved vastly. And people are finally starting to pay attention to the music in my local community, and we have a few aspiring djs for whom I gave a seminar on tango djing last year. Now even more are interested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Encouraging.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>