<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Embrace on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/categories/embrace/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Embrace on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/categories/embrace/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Perfect Embrace</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2015/02/14/the-perfect-embrace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2015 19:22:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2015/02/14/the-perfect-embrace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/virgoh/8413961643/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm9.static.flickr.com/8364/8413961643_62e7a83368.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;the dark side of the embrace by virgoh, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/people/virgoh/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/people/virgoh/&#34;&gt;virgoh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, this is nothing new to tango dancers, but understanding the mechanisms is interesting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;A caress feels best when it is delivered with a small amount of force and a speed of about 1 inch per second. Stroke slower, and it feels like an unwelcome crawling bug; faster, and it feels perfunctory rather than loving. &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Perform your caress not on the glabrous skin of the palm or sole, but on the hairy skin of the limbs where the caress sensing fibers are found. Move your hand at about 1 inch per second, exert moderate force, don’t clutch a cold drink immediately beforehand, and you will optimally activate your partner’s caress-sensing fibers and then strongly excite the posterior insular region of your sweetheart’s brain. And for a moment, all will be right with the world.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slate.com/articles/health_and_science/science/2015/02/touch_research_how_to_perform_the_ideal_caress_for_valentine_s_day.single.html&#34;&gt;Read the full article @ Slate.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Fundamentals of Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/04/14/three-fundamentals-of-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2010 21:13:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/04/14/three-fundamentals-of-tango/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/pforret/4489579181/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4001/4489579181_e399aebb7b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Brussels Tango Festival - Saturday -Exhi by Peter Forret, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/pforret/&#34;&gt; Peter Forret&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever I hear the postulate that everything in tango is either a step forward, a step backwards or a side step, I get a little irritated. I know what they mean, and it&amp;rsquo;s not that it is entirely wrong, it&amp;rsquo;s rather that it is incomplete, and it tends to send people off in a very step oriented direction. But &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2008/11/09/nuevo-tools-nuevo-problems/&#34;&gt;I have written about that before&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me instead remind you of three quite different fundamentals in the tango, or maybe rather governing principles. It is a very important insight.  Simple, yet profound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dancing the tango, you have three partners. And tango is about embrace, embrace and embrace. In order to dance well, you need to embrace them all:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;embrace-your-partner&#34;&gt;Embrace your partner&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is all about the woman.  No partner, no dancing. Respect your partner, take care of her and protect her, make it a pleasant experience for her. Listen to her, feel her presence, wishes and desires&amp;hellip; In return, she will make you both beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;embrace-the-music&#34;&gt;Embrace the music&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The movement has to come from the music. Without music we would just stand there, hugging each other. That can be nice, too, of course, but it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be dancing. Listen to what the music tells you and find your inspiration there. Then embrace the music and dance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;embrace-the-dance-floor&#34;&gt;Embrace the dance floor&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are not alone on the floor. We are dancing with the other couples on the floor as well. Respect their space, keep moving at a reasonable pace and avoid dangerous movements. (The &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/KISS_principle&#34;&gt;KISS principle&lt;/a&gt; is apt here.)  In return you will feel the energy of the floor. Sometimes people complain about dancers not socializing enough, but as I see it, sharing the floor is also socializing. Embrace your fellow dancers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Naveira-Salas model may help you to learn steps. Which can be useful. &lt;em&gt;To learn to dance, you need to learn how to embrace your three partners.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS: I am talking about social dancing here. For performance/stage dancing, I guess you could substitute dance floor with audience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Look! No hands!</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/17/look-no-hands/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2010 21:07:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/17/look-no-hands/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/mag3737/2289757349/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3248/2289757349_cf72d3a41f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;No hands by mag3737, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/mag3737/&#34;&gt; mag3737&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There seems to be a common misunderstanding that you are not supposed to use your arms when dancing tango.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is wrong on so many levels. I can see where it comes from, as it is a common mistake among beginners to do try leading with their hands, and not using the rest of their bodies. But one thing is to make point to beginners and quite another to elevate it to a universal truth. Yes, it is possible to lead and follow without using your arms and hands. So what? It is possible to lead and follow with no physical contact, too. It just isn&amp;rsquo;t what I would think of as tango.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember the &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/07/15/homenaje-a-los-milongueros/&#34;&gt;homenaje a los milongueros&lt;/a&gt;? &amp;ldquo;The milongueros are soft and precise in their lead, using their &lt;strong&gt;entire body&lt;/strong&gt; to lead&amp;rdquo; Last time I checked, both arms and hands were part of the body, at least it is still true for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, you know what the spanish word for embrace is? Abrazo.  Ever thought about what &lt;strong&gt;brazo&lt;/strong&gt; means? ( It means arm.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Important difference</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/27/important-difference/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2009 02:44:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/27/important-difference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/pforret/2240668302/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/09/abrazo.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Nosotros birthday milonga by Peter Forret, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/pforret/&#34;&gt; Peter Forret&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much as I love embracing the beautiful women in tango&amp;ndash;there is nothing quite like &lt;em&gt;being embraced by&lt;/em&gt; the beautiful women in tango.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on a popular embrace</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/07/notes-on-a-popular-embrace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2009 03:07:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/07/notes-on-a-popular-embrace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/pforret/2997016257/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/09/popular-embrace.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Demo Maestros @ Tiempo Argentino by Peter Forret, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/pforret/&#34;&gt; Peter Forret&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have seen quite a few dismissive comments of a certain embrace lately, someone calling it &amp;lsquo;Reaching for the man&amp;rsquo;s back pants pocket&amp;rsquo;-embrace just recently (&lt;a href=&#34;http://tangocherie.blogspot.com/2009/08/tango-salon-winners-in-mundial-2009.html&#34;&gt;in the comments, here&lt;/a&gt;). Which doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound very nice to me. I assume it is the one pictured above that is referred to, although I would have to say she is a little off if she is going for this pockets. I suspect the misunderstanding concerning the pockets comes from seeing this as a intention downwards embrace, while it is quite the oposite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, people may embrace as they please, but this crititcism seems a little narrow-minded to me. I, on the other hand get an urge to dance every time I see someone embracing this way because, when done correctly, it feels very good and improves the connection with my partner, who can participate actively with her left hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone dismissed it as a fad. That may well be, but it sure is a long lived one. If you see the famous film snip of Carmencita Calderón dancing with the legendary El Cachafaz, you see her using a variation of this embrace. (As opposed to having her arm around his neck). That footage is from the 1930s. So I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t put much money on it going out of fashion anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheek to cheek</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/22/cheek-to-cheek/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2008 17:47:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/22/cheek-to-cheek/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0027125/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/11/top_hat.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;From Top Hat&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Heaven, I&#39;m in Heaven,
And my heart beats so that I can hardly speak;
And I seem to find the happiness I seek
When we&#39;re out together dancing, cheek to cheek.

Heaven, I&#39;m in Heaven,
And the cares that hang around me thro&#39; the week
Seem to vanish like a gambler&#39;s lucky streak
When we&#39;re out together dancing, cheek to cheek.

Oh! I love to climb a mountain,
And to reach the highest peak,
But it doesn&#39;t thrill me half as much
As dancing cheek to cheek.

Oh! I love to go out fishing
In a river or a creek,
But I don&#39;t enjoy it half as much
As dancing cheek to cheek.

Dance with me
I want my arm about you;
The charm about you
Will carry me thro&#39; to Heaven

I&#39;m in Heaven,
and my heart beats so that I can hardly speak;
And I seem to find the happiness I seek
When we&#39;re out together dancing cheek to cheek.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Irving_Berlin&#34;&gt;Irving Berlin&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;httpvh://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=NWmK9Xl82CU&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of cover version of this, I prefer the Fred &amp;amp; Ginger way. And it fits so well on me, as I used to be an avid climber and downhill skier, now completely lost in the tango.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Masquerade</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/31/masquerade/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2008 21:07:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/31/masquerade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/10/masquerade.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/10/masquerade.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who are you when you are dancing? Are you the leader? The follower? The man? The woman? I was once confronted with my using the terminology man/woman in class. The person complaining said that she was dancing a &lt;em&gt;role&lt;/em&gt; (she was dancing the man&amp;rsquo;s part) and that was the role of the leader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know this easily gets messy, but I never liked the euphemism leader/follower when what we are talking about is a man and a woman in most cases. Being a follower implies being passive, and sort of gives the leader higher value. When it can easily be argued that it is quite the oposite. The man dances _ for the woman_, remember? &lt;em&gt;She&lt;/em&gt; is the high value part of the relationship. To be cherished and taken good care of. Embraced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, with love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few years back I took a class about communication and backleading. We were asked to try and verbalize what we were communicating in our dance. While I did not like the lesson much, something interesting came up. I tried finding the words, my mood maybe, happy or sad, if I had a good day at work and so on. The interesting part was the answer from another couple at the class. They dismissed the whole idea of the communication comprising more than &lt;em&gt;mere movements&lt;/em&gt;. While they were very good dancers, I think they miss out on something very important if they limit the dance to merely movements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a related note, Javier in a class talked about daring to enjoy embracing and walking together, and how using too many steps like sacadas etc would create a distance between the two in the couple. And he was not talking about the physical distance between the dancers, but about not connecting with your partner on a deeper level than merely doing steps together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lower the mask and dare dance as yourself. Don&amp;rsquo;t play games. Dare showing your true self. You might be lucky and get the same in return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&#34;http://flickr.com/photos/36291563@N00/&#34;&gt;August Rush&lt;/a&gt;@flickr, &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/deed.en&#34;&gt;CC-licensed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Putting the baby to sleep</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/14/putting-the-baby-to-sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 20:49:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/14/putting-the-baby-to-sleep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I quite recently became a father, and the poor child is exposed to a lot of tango music, naturally. (And I get out to dance less, hence the blog writing.) Before he was born, I used to talk about how we would practice walking together, he and I. Now this is how it turned out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scene: Unpatiant 12 days old boy, waiting for his mother to get ready for breast-feeding. Father to find something to entertain the child, and preferably also himself in the meantime. Time for tango. Di Sarli&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Nido Gaucho&lt;/em&gt; on the stereo, practicing the tango walk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boy seemed to enjoy the experience, I would say. Not as big eyes as with the milonga a few days earlyer (yes - really). After one tango and a half, he became more quiet. A few other songs from the same album, then the &lt;em&gt;Porteño y bailarín&lt;/em&gt; album from the start. The boy fell asleep in my arms. And I got to practice my walk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The funny thing about this, is that having a baby in your arms, getting it to sleep is a quite common metaphor for the way the woman should be held in the embrace. Soft, yet firm and secure.  I know at least El &amp;ldquo;Negro&amp;rdquo; Capello and Javier Rodríguez have used this metaphor. The thing is, I spent quite a lot of time practicing my tango embrace, but not making babies sleep. I got the idea, of course, but now I could apply the metaphor in the reverse direction, using my tango skills to get the boy to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, I fell asleep quite happily that night myself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>