<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tango in Japan on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/tags/tango-in-japan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tango in Japan on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2012 10:09:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/tags/tango-in-japan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hope for CTA, AMP, Audio Park reissues?</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2012/11/15/hope-for-cta-amp-audio-park-reissues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2012 10:09:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2012/11/15/hope-for-cta-amp-audio-park-reissues/</guid>
      <description>by eerkmans
Many CTA discs and others are available in Europe through the Austrian DJ Bernhard Gehberger. He recently went to Japan and met with the guys behind CTA, AMP and Audio Park. From his report from that trip, it seems like he is working on facilitating reissues of these out-of-print discs. Which would be of great benefit to the tango community if he pulls it through. Today they are both hard to get and expensive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Japan Update</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/10/01/japan-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 01:49:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/10/01/japan-update/</guid>
      <description>Finally somevideos of the new champions. Bear over with the person holding the camera not being able to keep still, and make sure you get the milonga at the end. The Argentine newspaper Clarin has a short interview with them.
I mentioned in a previous post that Japan was important because of the collectors of tango music there, and Royce recently posted several posts (here, here and here [UPDATE: She added part 4, part 5 and part 6] ) on this topic that are well worth a read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big in Japan</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/01/big-in-japan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:05:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/01/big-in-japan/</guid>
      <description>by skyseeker
Seeing the reactions from many after the Japanese couple Hiroshi &amp;amp; Kyoko Yamao won the mundial de tango salón as the first non-Argentines, it seems many in the tango world are unaware of the long traditions of tango in Japan. Or maybe some practice selective memory&amp;hellip;
Todotango has an interesting article on the rise of tango in Japan. While the tradition is certainly shorter in terms of years since the first impact than in Europe (Megata&amp;rsquo;s first contact with tango was in Paris in the 1920s), it does not lack much, and in a way it represents a tradition closer to the original than in Europe.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>