<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Finesse on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/tags/finesse/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Finesse on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 May 2009 01:13:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/tags/finesse/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Necessary</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/14/necessary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2009 01:13:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/14/necessary/</guid>
      <description>by OpenThreads
Breaking the dance of tango down to its smallest parts is a popular exercise. Why stop at forward-side-back-steps? What it really comes down to is one simple concept. If you can do it, you can tango. Or at least you need to be able to do it to dance it.
Standing on one leg.
For a week-end class, we had one student with some condition that made it impossible for her to stand on one leg.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chasing cucarachas</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/20/chasing-cucarachas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2008 16:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/20/chasing-cucarachas/</guid>
      <description>by seretuaccidente
Speaking of lack of finesse&amp;hellip;
What&amp;rsquo;s with the watching the floor all the time, checking the floor before each step, head moving from side to side, constantly, as if chasing cucarachas. I did not come up with this description myself, but it is very fitting, I think.
Whoever came up with this new &amp;lsquo;style&amp;rsquo; (or rather lack thereof)? Somebody near them should tell them that it looks ridiculous.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pas de finesse...</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/19/pas-de-finesse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2008 12:55:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/19/pas-de-finesse/</guid>
      <description>by Jayanth Sharma
Staying in Buenos Aires for a few months provided several eye-openers. One of the great revelations was concerning the logic of the dance, or rather the lack of it, and how this adds spice to the dance:
We were taking lessons with various teachers, with very different philosophies with respect to tango, how to dance it and how to learn it. Gustavo Naveira, the great master, dissected each step carefully, explaining exactly how and why and which steps were crossed and which were open etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>