<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technique on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/categories/technique/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technique on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/categories/technique/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Kung Fu Tango -- Learning From Bruce Lee</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2013/02/11/kung-fu-tango----learning-from-bruce-lee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2013 22:04:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2013/02/11/kung-fu-tango----learning-from-bruce-lee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://graphics8.nytimes.com/images/2009/05/16/arts/lee-600.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;--What is the highest technique you hope to achieve?
--To have no technique.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is impossible not to think of tango, hearing some of the conversations in the Bruce Lee film &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0070034/&#34;&gt;Enter the Dragon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;--Kick me (Bruce Lee to one of his students)
student kicks
--What was that? An exhibition? We need emotional content. Try again.
student kicks again
--I said emotional content. Not anger. Now, try again. With _me._
student kicks again
--That&#39;s it,  how did it feel to you?
--Let me think...
slaps student
--Don&#39;t think! Feeeeeeel!&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My apologies to TP for ripping off some of his old fb posts (&amp;ldquo;I was learning tango from Bruce Lee&amp;rdquo;), but even if I have no clue about martial arts, I find it very intrigueing, and getting lost in &lt;del&gt;procrastination&lt;/del&gt; research for this post,  I kept finding analogies with tango. There are great differences, of course, but the smooth movement, the groundedness, playing at the limits of balance&amp;hellip; If you ever thought of giros and ganchos being metaphors of street fights as far fetched, have a look at the final fight between Bruce Lee and the Big Boss in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0067824/&#34;&gt;The Big Boss&lt;/a&gt; (yes, I know). Some ganchos!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Martial arts using balance to trip the opponent over, tango challenging balance, only to make sure your partner is perfectly safe and on balance. I would be very surprised if a solid foundation in martial arts was not a great asset when learning tango. Or maybe rather taking up the practice of tango. In many ways tango is better thought of as a practice, rather than something you &amp;ldquo;learn&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching several Bruce Lee films over the last months, including several documentaries, and it struck me that his moves seem so fresh, even today, more than forty years later. Indeed a testimony to the greatness of this icon of martial arts. The ballet like choreographies are, somewhat paradoxically very extravagant, in contrast to Bruce Lee&amp;rsquo;s philosophy of a minimalist martial art. The art of &amp;ldquo;fighting without fighting&amp;rdquo; as he says in Enter the Dragon. The screen tests he did before starring in Green Hornet were brilliant, and some of his &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=j432nqUlJss&#34;&gt;demos from California likewise&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the documentaries I learnt that Bruce Lee was actually a capable dancer, and won a Hong Kong Cha Cha competition, and earned some extra pocket money teaching dance at the boat to the US when reclaiming his US citizenship. One of the Kung Fu masters interviewed in one documentary told the story about how he made a deal with Bruce that he showed Bruce his Kung Fu tricks, and Bruce would teach him Cha Cha. &amp;ndash;But after three nights, he knew all my tricks, and I never got beyond the basic step&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bruce Lee was trained in a style of Kung Fu called &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wing_Chun&#34;&gt;Wing Chun&lt;/a&gt;, and there is a documentary on youtube about Wing Chun that seems authentic to me. Again the tango similarities jump at me. Maintaining center line, groundedness, pivots and relaxed, economic movement, and a technique called &amp;ldquo;sticky hands&amp;rdquo; where you keep contact with the opponent all the time with the arms to feel his next movement almost before he does himself.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/uVkjj8568d8&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This 10 year old practicing the Chen style of Taiji is also adorable:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/fS0QYq26V2g&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I used to dismiss Taiji as old people moving slowly in the parks of Beijing to keep in shape. But if the old guys in the park are only a bleak shadow of ancient fighters, at the roots are real fighting. And like anyone who&amp;rsquo;s tried practicing tango in slow motion knows it doesn&amp;rsquo;t exactly make it any easier. In a completely other context I came over a saying that puts it nicely:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Slow is smooth; smooth is fast.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The break of rhytm is also a very interesting concept. This concept of establishing one rhythm and speed and then deviate from it as a surprise also works wonders in the tango.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently learned that one of my favourite directors, Wong Kar Wai (of &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0118694/&#34;&gt;In the mood for love&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; fame), will release a Kung Fu epic called &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1462900/&#34;&gt;The Grandmaster&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; based on the life of&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yip_Man&#34;&gt; Ip Man&lt;/a&gt;, Bruce Lee&amp;rsquo;s teacher. El maestro del maestro. There is also a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=v3SZUobEuao&#34;&gt;documentary about the making of this film&lt;/a&gt;, and the ordeals they went  through to get to the authentic Wing Chun, unfortunately not with English subtitles. And &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wongkarwai.net/the-road-to-the-grandmasters-documentary-and-a-new-poster-are-released/&#34;&gt;at this points we touch Argentina and tango again&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;The documentary revealed that the idea of making ’The Grandmasters’ started in 1996 when Wong Kar-wai was working on ’Happy Together’ in Argentina. He saw a  local magazine with Bruce Lee on its cover and felt that the superstar’s influence on the world. Yet because the Bruce Lee story has already made many times, he wanted to explore Bruce Lee’s master Ip Man more and how he turned Bruce Lee into a legendary figure&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Struggle to find the authentic, master of the master, does it sound familiar?&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/XKWXnNfAXfM&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The trailer uses another phrase that resonates with a tango guy like me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;In his practice what I saw wasn&#39;t movement, but essence.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to learn tango from Bruce Lee, too. Or rather, from Ip Man. El maestro del maestro.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution?</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/04/27/evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2010 20:35:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/04/27/evolution/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/bQb7JWpEVRo&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I hear it every so often: that tango technique, especially for women, has gone through a tremendous evolution since the resurgence in the early 1980s. Let&amp;rsquo;s just say I&amp;rsquo;m not quite convinced. Watch this clip from the 1988 movie &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0096221/&#34;&gt;Tango Bar&lt;/a&gt;, and draw your own conclusions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experiment shows: walking heel first more efficient</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/16/experiment-shows-walking-heel-first-more-efficient/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2010 17:51:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/16/experiment-shows-walking-heel-first-more-efficient/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/heel-first-toe-first-e1266332407571.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/heel-first-toe-first-e1266332407571.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will not, of course, settle the agelong debate of whether to walk toe first or heel first in tango. Still, I found it interesting that there has recently been  published research on the efficiency of the human walk, specifically investigating walking heel first versus walking toe first.  If you are striving for the most efficient walk, their conclusion might be worth noting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

&gt; 
&gt; When human subjects walked with their heels slightly elevated in a ‘low-digitigrade’[toe first] posture, COT [cost of transport] increased by 53% above that of normal plantigrade [heel first] walking.
&gt; 
&gt; 

&gt; 
&gt; Cunningham, C. B., Schilling, N., Anders, C. andCarrier, D. R. (2010).
[The influence of foot posture onthe cost of transport in humans](http://jeb.biologists.org/cgi/content/full/213/5/790?ijkey=ce57e4d265e26213e5a9717dc550495b1e75a6c9).
J. Exp. Biol. 213, 790-797
&gt; 
&gt; 
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The researchers were wondering why we are not walking and running toe first like many other animals and wanted to test the hypothesis that walking heel first is more efficient. They did experiments with different walks and runs on a treadmill where they could measure the oxygen consumption of their subjects at normal walking speed. They also did experiments with running subjects, where this difference does not exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, the reasons for the increased efficiency of walking heel first are (p. 796):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;lower collisional losses of the body as a whole&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;increased recovery of kinetic and potential energy&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;lower ground reaction force moments specifically at the ankle joint.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not very surprising, maybe, to anyone who has tried both ways, but now you&amp;rsquo;ve got the reference :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their paper says nothing about style, of course&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Illustration taken from the original paper.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking on high heels</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/04/walking-on-high-heels/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2009 02:10:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/04/walking-on-high-heels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;ldquo;&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;599&amp;rdquo; caption=&amp;ldquo;Cinderella discovers the risk involved in dancing too wildly while wearing glass shoes&amp;rdquo;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wulffmorgenthaler.com/strip.aspx?id=d4269d90-fc41-4bfe-b444-9dcc17424911&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.wulffmorgenthaler.com/striphandler.ashx?stripid=d4269d90-fc41-4bfe-b444-9dcc17424911&#34; alt=&#34;Cinderella discovers the risk involved in dancing too wildly while wearing glass shoes&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Sure he was great, but don&#39;t forget that Ginger Rogers did everything he did, backwards... and in high heels.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had the pleasure of dancing with a woman in Buenos Aires who really knew how to operate her feet. She worked in television in her country, and was known as  &amp;rsquo;the woman that knows how to walk on high heels&amp;rsquo;. That skill she had developed on the tango dance floor. Whenever they needed someone classy walking around with high heels, they called her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Buenos Aires I suspect it to be the other way around. Women bring their skill in high heels to their first tango lesson. And that must be a great start in learning how to dance. It often amazes me how well dancers in Buenos Aires dance after a couple of years, compared with the very best dancers back home. Even after dancing for ten years, practicing a lot and taking hundreds and hundreds of lessons. When porteños walk into their first lesson, they already know the music. And they already know how to walk like a porteño (Duh!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, sitting at a café, watching people walk by, or walking in the streets myself, I have noticed that women walking in the streets at home and in south of Europe and Buenos Aires walk very differently (The same goes for the men, but they are usually not in high heels). Shoes with high heels are much more common in the two latter places, and the women wearing them are much more likely to walk well, while the ones in Northern Europe and the US tend to stumble around. Like they are afraid the shoes are about to break into pieces. Well - maybe they are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came in as la princesa was catching up on the tv series &amp;lsquo;Sex &amp;amp; the City&amp;rsquo; (If this were a wikipedia article, this would be the &amp;hellip;in popular culture-section). It is a series where expensive designer stilettos played a major part if I understand it correctly, and I watched the main character walking, or rather not-falling, down some stairs and out on the street. I asked myself why she even bothered with the fancy shoes, when she didn&amp;rsquo;t know how to wear them. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t really look good when you cannot walk. According to la princesa, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t even the worst example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cat-like, smooth steps, on the other hand, are practical as well as beautiful, as the time of impact is stretched, reducing the forces at work at any given time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going directly from a life in flat shoes to long nights with Comme il faut in the milongas may indeed cause pain, both in feet/Achilles and back. This is true both for women and men (even without the Comme il fauts), but probably more for women. The shoes are called &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stiletto&#34;&gt;stiletto&lt;/a&gt;s for a reason; they are dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have thought of four things that may help you from getting hurt from dancing with stiletto heels (which may be necessary, but not necessarily sufficient):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The right technique&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shoes that fit&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Strength&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A good partner&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish I could reveal the &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2008/11/11/the-secret-dont-tell-anyone/&#34;&gt;secret&lt;/a&gt; to the right technique walk in this post, but as you know, it&amp;rsquo;s not that simple. If you have been walking on them since you were&amp;hellip; &amp;ndash; well, younger, you know how to do it. If not, you have to catch up somehow. Just like with the music. You have put in the hours, and you have to walk the miles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Important things to work on are balance, placing the weight on the inside of the ball of the foot, actually walking on the heel when going forwards, pushing off with the grounded foot for each step and absorb the impact slowly when putting weight on the other foot. Using the muscles in the leg. And use the toes to spread out and support you. You have four joints to help you absorb the shock and push you into the next step. Toes/forefeet, ankles, knees and hips. Use all four in different amount, depending on how you like your tango. But then, rather than rely on a text on the internet, take some privates with someone really good. Then practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as I was writing this, there was a report on the news that many women get orthopedic problems because they wear too small shoes. Make sure your &lt;strong&gt;shoes fit&lt;/strong&gt; your foot, ladies! You need space for your toes to use them correctly, at the same time you need a shoe that sits firmly on. Quoting la princesa: It is like a good abrazo: Let the shoe give your foot an embrace that is firm and secure, yet allows your toes to move and your foot to &amp;lsquo;breathe&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good technique alone is not enough, you also need to develop foot &lt;strong&gt;strength&lt;/strong&gt; to enjoy long nights of tango in these exquisite stilettos. Unfortunately, that takes some time. I remember from my time as a rock climber that finger strength took a long time to develop, as there really aren&amp;rsquo;t much muscles in the fingers. They are in the underarm, and are rather small, hence it takes extra time to grow them stronger. The same is true for the foot, I believe, except the muscles are in the leg, of course&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In earlier times they didn&amp;rsquo;t use special &amp;lsquo;tango shoes&amp;rsquo;, they would walk right in from the street into the milonga and start dancing (without changing shoes), many still do. Being used to walking in high heels also outside the milonga must really help building foot strength over time. By the way, some Argentine tango teachers told us that women (in tango) used to wear steeper shoes before, but that these are hard to find these days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are not dancing alone, and whether you are able to walk well ultimately depends on the man&amp;rsquo;s skills as well. The woman needs to be able to move confidently by herself, and a &lt;strong&gt;good partner&lt;/strong&gt; will give her that freedom. No guessing games. You might need to be more selective with dancing partners. If your partner is throwing you around, no amount of good technique or strength is going to help you in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So are the high heels any good?&lt;/strong&gt; Apart from that they look gorgeous, I have wondered if they offer any practical advantage. I am still not sure they do, but it definitely feels better dancing with a woman who knows how to walk in high heels when she&amp;rsquo;s wearing her Comme il fauts, compared with the same dancer in &amp;lsquo;tango sneakers&amp;rsquo; ala Fabio shoes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wonder if using low heels or flat shoes tempt to put down the free leg, thus working against being ready for next step? Walking (as in actually walking) backwards, they can make life easier by letting you put down your heel, preparing for the next back step. This depends on absolutely crystal clear lead from your partner and under no circumstances any feints. As I wrote above: no guessing games. I can&amp;rsquo;t really see how the woman is supposed to get more rest in flat shoes; then she never gets to put her weight down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;High heels seem to have a bad reputation in killing women&amp;rsquo;s  feet. I am not sure how much is because of the inherent danger of the shoe itself, and how much is because of &amp;lsquo;wrong use&amp;rsquo;. Finding out is made more difficult by the selection bias, both with respect to who gets in trouble and goes to the doctor with foot pain (missing technique/wrong size etc overrepresented?), and who stays with the tango over time/life (those who don&amp;rsquo;t get into serious foot trouble?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer:&lt;/strong&gt; you might still get in trouble with your feet, maybe due to some unknown weakness that gets exposed after taking up dancing, even if you have a brilliant partner, excellent technique and strong feet. (But I think it is far less likely).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, a word from la princesa, who was kind to read over this before I  posted: walk &lt;strong&gt;with&lt;/strong&gt; your high heels, not **on **them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Necessary</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/14/necessary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2009 01:13:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/14/necessary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/openthreads/457204337/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/240/457204337_b2d45ca69a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Flamingo - Albuquerque BioPark by OpenThreads, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/openthreads/&#34;&gt; OpenThreads&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Breaking the dance of tango down to its smallest parts is a popular exercise. Why stop at forward-side-back-steps? What it really comes down to is one simple concept. If you can do it, you can tango. Or at least you need to be able to do it to dance it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standing on one leg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a week-end class, we had one student with some condition that made it impossible for her to stand on one leg. Which was sad because the communication did not work at all. I was sorry to realize that she would never be able to dance tango, even if she really wanted to. We did our best to make it work and for her to have a good time, of course,  but it was quite clear that tango was not for her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may seem all too obvious to write a blogpost about, no? Well, there is a more subtle point I wanted to make. The best dancers have a clarity and elegance, simplicity of movement that we all long for (I suppose). And to a large degree it stems from their ability to stand on exactly one leg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No less, no more&amp;hellip; ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Up and down</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/03/02/up-and-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2009 15:29:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/03/02/up-and-down/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/ableman/534153791/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1125/534153791_20e37d5eec.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The Mind Eraser by Scott Ableman, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/ableman/&#34;&gt; Scott Ableman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;-Have you been practicing tango nuevo?&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guilty as charged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He knew immediately. And it was not because I used an open embrace, we were practicing milonga, using a very confined embrace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I often wonder why people get so hang up on the somewhat arbitrary distinction between open and close embrace (all teachers, both &amp;ldquo;nuevo&amp;rdquo; and others usually promote very close embrace at times, but for some figures it is not possible to maintain the closest embrace.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some say that the technique is the same. Well, it is mostly compatible, and that is what matters, but there are some differences. Which was clearly demonstrated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What gave me away was that my energy was going down. That might not be the correct way of putting it, but you get the idea. What he wanted was energy going &lt;strong&gt;up.&lt;/strong&gt; So the difference was in the energy going up or down (up-traditional, down-nuevo). While staying well grounded, of course. Stretching the spine, effectively going up and down at the same time. Talk about dissosiation&amp;hellip; And it doesn&amp;rsquo;t require less in the balance department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might argue that whatever makes it possible (or easier) to do &lt;insert favorite fancy move here&gt; is worth it. Like in skiing, sacrificing elegance for ability to go faster or jump longer. Bending down for improved balance? Feet more apart?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Myself, I never saw the point of doing as many steps as possible (volcadas/minute anone?). It&amp;rsquo;s not like it&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/03/01/competition/&#34;&gt;competition&lt;/a&gt;, remember?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boleos helados</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/15/boleos-helados/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2008 21:34:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/15/boleos-helados/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/hettiemcfarlane/225531507/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/79/225531507_fb9f3664ee.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;icecream cow, Budapest, Hungary by Hettie McFarlane, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/hettiemcfarlane/&#34;&gt; Hettie McFarlane&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.limericktango.com/blog/&#34;&gt;Limerick&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s post on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.limericktango.com/2008/11/boleos/&#34;&gt;boleos&lt;/a&gt; made me think of the concept of boleos helados, or frozen boleos. I went to a workshop with Chicho and Lucía a couple of years back, and while the frozen boleos were sort of fun, it ruins your boleo technique if you shape your boleos that way. Methinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The intrigueing thing about boleos is their free flowing unmanaged quality. Or as Limerick says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;You don’t do boleos, boleos happen.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>