<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tanguero on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/tags/tanguero/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tanguero on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/tags/tanguero/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Tango Movies: &#34;Tanguero&#34; and &#34;La cantante de tango&#34;</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/11/12/upcoming-tango-movies-tanguero-and-la-cantante-de-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2010 17:16:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/11/12/upcoming-tango-movies-tanguero-and-la-cantante-de-tango/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;A short update on a couple of upcoming tango movies. I find it somewhat promising that none of them seem to be about a middle aged dancer or hit man coming to Buenos Aires and there discovering tango and through it, themselves. Still, they may include other clichés such as lost love and finding oneself through tango:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tanguero&#34;&gt;Tanguero&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Omar, a Tango instructor, is forced to return to Buenos Aires because of an important phone call. He discovers an unrecognizable city, meets relatives, old friends and meets Veronica, his childhood friend. They remember the time they had spent together years before and decide to take on a difficult challenge. That’s how Omar rediscovers himself in Tango.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tangueromovie.com/&#34;&gt;Tanguero&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;la-cantante-de-tango&#34;&gt;La cantante de tango&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/_VIzIi-ii7U&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;Helena, una talentosa cantante de tango, se encuentra profundamente enamorada. Cuando consigue presentarse en un prestigioso teatro de Buenos Aires, su carrera parece despegar. Pero justo en ese momento la alcanza la tragedia: el hombre que ella ama ya no está enamorado de ella. Obsesionada y torturada por su pérdida, no puede recuperarse de su ruptura y lentamente se convierte en una sombra de la mujer que solía ser. Pero ¿Y si dejara atrás la pena y se atreviera a una nueva vida en un país distinto? Quizás así Helena podría también dejar atrás el dolor y,  lentamente, aprender a vivir y amar de nuevo.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://lacantantedetango.com.ar/&#34;&gt;La cantante de tango&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HT: &lt;a href=&#34;http://tinatangos.com/blog/&#34;&gt;Tina&lt;/a&gt; (Tanguero) and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.2xtango.com/?p=7720&#34;&gt;2XTango&lt;/a&gt; (La cantante de tango)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>