<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tango Culture on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/categories/tango-culture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tango Culture on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 19:02:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/categories/tango-culture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dancing to the music of time</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2016/01/29/dancing-to-the-music-of-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 19:02:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2016/01/29/dancing-to-the-music-of-time/</guid>
      <description>But among so many lessons, with so many teachers, I find contradictions and clichés. My feet are shovels; my feet are paintbrushes. My feet must caress the floor, intensely; my feet are too firm against the floorboards. My embrace must be close, like the embrace of a lover; my embrace must leave space for the tension between us. I am a cat, I am a lion, I am a horse-rider. Carina tells me I need to work on my ochos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>El Corte Documentary</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2013/02/19/el-corte-documentary/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2013 15:09:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2013/02/19/el-corte-documentary/</guid>
      <description>[vimeo 28409308 w=500]
I missed this when it came out. A doucumentary about the legendary El Corte in Nijmegen, The Netherlands. Eric Jørissen and El Corte have had a great influence on the European tango scene in general, and if I am not mistaken, on the tango marathon culture in particular.
HT: Veronica</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning From Early Music</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/07/10/learning-from-early-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 11:54:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/07/10/learning-from-early-music/</guid>
      <description>by madabandon
In a sense, dancing Argentine Tango in 2011 in a country far away from Argentina is an inescapable anachronism. How could it ever be authentic? Should it be? Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t any art form evolve and develop in a quest for ever improvement? In the (un)concious choice between opposing traditions, which would be the right to follow?
Now, these questions are not unique for tango of course:
The idea of revival has become a touchstone for the Early Music Movement, and consequently the fact that some styles of performance have been going on long enough to develop and build their own continuity presents some philosophical complications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributing to the Digital Tango Archive</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/12/11/contributing-to-the-digital-tango-archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2010 13:46:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/12/11/contributing-to-the-digital-tango-archive/</guid>
      <description>by erielookingproductions
I have written about the effort of Tango Via to digitally archive the entire tango catalogue, and how I was impressed with their ambitions, the work so far and the significance of preserving the tango culture for the future.
This is an update to point your attention to their donation page, you can donate via Help Argentina if you are outside Argentina. If in Argentina, they suggest you get in touch with them to get instructions for donations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of the Cabeceo Part I: Are You Flirting With Me?</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/10/23/the-art-of-the-cabeceo-part-i-are-you-flirting-with-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2010 13:45:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/10/23/the-art-of-the-cabeceo-part-i-are-you-flirting-with-me/</guid>
      <description>by pedrosimoes7
&amp;ndash;Nobody asks me to dance, complained our Canadian classmate. We were sitting at our table in the Buenos Aires Golf Club, overlooking the dark course and the city skyline. We started chatting about the cabeceo, surely she knew the habit of the Porteño dancer to ask by catching a potential partner&amp;rsquo;s eye and confirming with a slight nod towards the pista?
Of course she didn&amp;rsquo;t. On the contrary, she brought her habit of avoiding to meet the eye of men she did not know, avoiding unwanted attention and flirts from strangers, as she did back home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extraordinary dancing, thoughts about tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/08/23/extraordinary-dancing-thoughts-about-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2010 19:51:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/08/23/extraordinary-dancing-thoughts-about-tango/</guid>
      <description>This extraordinary video gave me some food for thought and made me finish a line of reasoning that started after noticing a youtube comment. Complaining that the dancing was all acrobatics, but had no feeling for the music. Sounded very familiar, only this time it was not tango dancers, but b-boys they were complaining about.
Hip hop and tango have quite some things in common (and obvious differences, of course).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning the Language of Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/06/27/learning-the-language-of-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2010 17:30:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/06/27/learning-the-language-of-tango/</guid>
      <description>by Simba tango
If you don&amp;rsquo;t know the language of tango, you&amp;rsquo;ll miss out on a lot, and for once, I don&amp;rsquo;t mean in a metaphorical sense. One anecdote I remember from my early days of tango was being told of a workshop that started with the following announcement: &amp;rdquo;This is an advanced class, hence it will be taught in Spanish&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;m not sure who it supposedly was that said it, but I have a similar experience with Gustavo Naveira teaching in Buenos Aires with lots of foreigners present: &amp;ndash;Is there anyone here that speaks absolutely no Spanish?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is it not in the public domain?</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/01/02/why-is-it-not-in-the-public-domain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2010 01:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/01/02/why-is-it-not-in-the-public-domain/</guid>
      <description>by Ioan Sameli
Entering a new year, it can be wise to give thought to how things could have been. Most of the world follows the USA when it comes to copyright laws, and they keep extending the copyright terms again and again. Which makes very little sense from a society stand point. Extending the copyright on the 1930s recordings of Juan D&amp;rsquo;Arienzo isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly making him pour out new hit records every month&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inside the digital archive</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/22/inside-the-digital-archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2009 01:45:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/22/inside-the-digital-archive/</guid>
      <description>by Erica_Marshall
After Ignacio Varchausky gave his musicality seminar at theCasa de tango here in Buenos Aires, where the TangoVía project resides, he was kind to show us around the premises and demonstrate the current state of the digital archive.
They have a very nice set of equipment, he showed us the machine they use to clean the discs properly before doing the transfers, the different turntables for different kinds of discs, amplifiers and ADC as well as tape equipment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tailored for Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/11/06/tailored-for-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2009 23:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/11/06/tailored-for-tango/</guid>
      <description>by wmacphail
&amp;ndash;Come back here! You are not entering the floor without buttoning your jacket! Her voice left no doubt, and the young aspiring dancer stepped back, buttoned his jacket and went back on the dance floor. He was smiling, but he would not commit the same error again.
In one of my very first tango lessons, I was told that the Argentine dancers would never take off their jacket for dancing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homero Manzi, un poeta en la tormenta</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/23/homero-manzi-un-poeta-en-la-tormenta/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 23:35:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/23/homero-manzi-un-poeta-en-la-tormenta/</guid>
      <description>A new film about the tango poet Homero Manzi was just released in Argentina. Manzi is the author of famous tangos like Malena, Sur and Barrio de tango. He worked with Troilo for several years, and in cooperation with Sebastián Piana, he revitalized the milonga genre with Milonga sentimental in 1931.
The film is apparently a combination of archive material and reconstruction of scenes from his life. It will be interesting to watch, I will probably wait until it is available on dvd, hopefully it won&amp;rsquo;t take that long.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In search for the authentic</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/07/in-search-for-the-authentic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2009 02:18:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/07/in-search-for-the-authentic/</guid>
      <description>by MR38
We love our Argentine Tango (or maybe Tango Argentino) to be sure. Do not bastardize it, please. We want the real thing!
On the other hand, there is no one tango. Tango is a living expression of the people who play, sing, listen to and dance it. My tango is different from yours, or I sure hope so. Not too different, but a little different. That&amp;rsquo;s what makes it interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>--A labour of love that needs more lovers</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/31/a-labour-of-love-that-needs-more-lovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2009 20:59:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/31/a-labour-of-love-that-needs-more-lovers/</guid>
      <description>by alexkerhead
Man of action. Man of ambition:
[Tango Vía](http://www.tangovia.org/), the organization this tango double-bass player from the famous [Orquesta El Arranque](http://www.orquestaelarranque.com.ar) presides, is up to nothing less than archiving every single tango recording in a super-high definition, archive-grade digital format, following strict technical processing that will drastically enhance the sound quality to make it an almost-perfect match to the pristine original.   [Buenos Aires Herald](http://buenosairesherald.com/PrintedEdition/View/4262)    Wonder how we could help them succeed with this project, arranging some sort of fund raiser or something?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technological advances in tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/09/technological-advances-in-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2009 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/09/technological-advances-in-tango/</guid>
      <description>by carrotcreative
I have to say I feel a bit like an oldie, writing this, but I am kind of old-school when it comes to tango, so I guess that&amp;rsquo;s ok..
I can&amp;rsquo;t help but notice how many things have changed since I first started with tango. Not the dance itself, but things around it. Technological changes that the newcomers in tango seem to take for granted, were simply not available only a few years back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sport and Culture</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/15/sport-and-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2009 13:02:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/15/sport-and-culture/</guid>
      <description>by Wigwam Jones
People often think of ballroom dancing when they hear I dance tango. Assuming I participate in competitions. And we would not want anybody to think that, would we?
It appears absurd to me, but it occurred to me the other day that they assume dancing is about sports. Which it is obviously not. It is all about culture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On circulation</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/11/on-circulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2009 00:57:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/11/on-circulation/</guid>
      <description>by pdcawley
Ms Hedgehog is researching the dynamics of flow in the ronda, comparing with traffic and pondering about the importance of song length.
While song length can probably have some influence, I believe other factors are much more significant. And it is kind of hard to perform real experiments, even though she deserves credit for the attempt.
According to Jorge Dispari, the flow on the dance floors of Buenos Aires used to be much better than today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango Film Club</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/04/19/tango-film-club/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2009 15:26:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/04/19/tango-film-club/</guid>
      <description>by atomicjeep
I was planning to write a separate post for each of those, but I never seem to find the time&amp;hellip; The recent posts by tangocommuter prompted me to write up this list of my favorite tango films. I never was all that interestesd in instructional videos, but films about the culture I find fascinating. In our small community we arranged public showings in an informal tango film club to make these gems available to the rest of the community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Color -- like no other</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/26/color-like-no-other/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2009 21:32:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/26/color-like-no-other/</guid>
      <description>The world is not black and white, there are grays in between&amp;hellip; it is often said when some take a clear position in a debate. And they do have a point of course. But they also sometimes miss the point entirely.
Tango is not gray, it is full of colour! You just have to open your eyes and take them in.
I am thinking of the &amp;ldquo;nuevo&amp;rdquo; versus &amp;ldquo;traditional&amp;rdquo; debate, of course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Un beso...</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/26/un-beso/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2009 17:33:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/26/un-beso/</guid>
      <description>by Kevin Steele
Buenos Aires is not like home. And when in Rome, drive like the Romans&amp;hellip;
And the Argentines kiss when they meet. Better get used to it.
(...) would lean over, ready to commit the act that, I thought, was reserved only for girlfriends and, on occasion, family. This guy used a few months it seems, but has written a really entertaining account of the argentinian kissing habits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Entering the milonga</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/17/entering-the-milonga/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2008 15:45:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/17/entering-the-milonga/</guid>
      <description>by Untitled blue
The moment or should I say process of entering a milonga is very special for me. I think savoring the moment is something very important in tango, and for me it starts at the moment I am standing outside the milonga entrance. There is a certain amount of expectation for the night even before, of course, but this is when I really start enjoying the sensation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yes honey, but is it tango?</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/04/yes-honey-but-is-it-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2008 15:58:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/04/yes-honey-but-is-it-tango/</guid>
      <description>Roy Lichtenstein: Girl with Ribbon (1965)
There is always a lot of fuzz in the tango communities of the world about what is the right tango. And rightly so. There is good and there is bad tango.
But in the middle of these heated arguments, we need to remind ourselves of one thing. Tango culture is rich. There is a lot of diversity in tango. Tango is not only dance. It is also music for listening.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All you need to know about style</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/03/all-you-need-to-know-about-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2008 17:56:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/03/all-you-need-to-know-about-style/</guid>
      <description>by DCCXLIX
A lot can be said about styles in tango. More on that in later posts. All you need to know about styles is the following:
Traditionally, we make a distinction between social tango (tango salón) and performances (tango fantasía).
Tango salón In a milonga, good navigation and connection with your partner is very important, as is dancing with the rest of the dance floor, which in general means no high boleos, ganchos etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>