<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tango Culture on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/categories/tango-culture/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tango Culture on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/categories/tango-culture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Dancing to the music of time</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2016/01/29/dancing-to-the-music-of-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 19:02:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2016/01/29/dancing-to-the-music-of-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.intelligentlifemagazine.com/sites/default/files/0116IL_PL_WIN_04-web.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;But among so many lessons, with so many teachers, I find contradictions and clichés. My feet are shovels; my feet are paintbrushes. My feet must caress the floor, intensely; my feet are too firm against the floorboards. My embrace must be close, like the embrace of a lover; my embrace must leave space for the tension between us. I am a cat, I am a lion, I am a horse-rider. Carina tells me I need to work on my ochos. “There is no such thing as an ocho,” says Oscar Casas, at our next lesson. There is only a change in direction, that’s all.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.intelligentlifemagazine.com/places/dancing-to-the-music-of-time&#34;&gt;refreshingly unclichéd take on dancing tango in Buenos Aires&lt;/a&gt;. (In Argentina, tango is a way of life, as Tara Isabella Burton discovered when she went to Buenos Aires, following in her grandmother’s footsteps, from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.intelligentlifemagazine.com/places/dancing-to-the-music-of-time&#34;&gt;Intelligent Life Magazine&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>El Corte Documentary</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2013/02/19/el-corte-documentary/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2013 15:09:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2013/02/19/el-corte-documentary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[vimeo 28409308 w=500]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I missed this when it came out. A doucumentary about the legendary &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.elcorte.com/&#34;&gt;El Corte in Nijmegen&lt;/a&gt;, The Netherlands. Eric Jørissen and El Corte have had a great influence on the European tango scene in general, and if I am not mistaken, on the tango marathon culture in particular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HT: Veronica&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning From Early Music</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/07/10/learning-from-early-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 11:54:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/07/10/learning-from-early-music/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/madabandon/3713669441/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3518/3713669441_12d9bc0fd2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Early Music by madabandon, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/madabandon/&#34;&gt; madabandon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a sense, dancing Argentine Tango in 2011 in a country far away from Argentina is an inescapable anachronism. How could it ever be authentic? Should it be? Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t any art form evolve and develop in a quest for ever improvement? In the (un)concious choice between opposing traditions, which would be the right to follow?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, these questions are not unique for tango of course:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;The idea of revival has become a touchstone for the Early Music Movement, and consequently the fact that some styles of performance have been going on long enough to develop and build their own continuity presents some philosophical complications.

(...)

Labels such as &#34;authentic performance&#34; and &#34;composer&#39;s intentions&#34; have likewise been mostly abandoned, but this time primarily for philosophical rather than practical reasons. There are two basic facts underlining this decision. The first is that knowing precisely how a work was originally performed, especially one rather distant in time, is not really possible. The second is that, perhaps with a few exceptions, composers do not state their intentions with regard to hypothetical performances hundreds of years in the future. The idea that the composer &#34;wants&#34; the music to sound today exactly as it did for the first performance is simply a philosophical one.

(...)

[The] composition of a piece, especially one which we would want to hear centuries later, was a creative act made in the context of creative musicians. In this sense, if musicians today are to abandon any creativity when rendering old music, then they are _not_ authentic, because that is not the frame of mind under which the original was made. The same frame of mind is indeed impossible today, because the piece will never be new again. Of course, for many individuals, it will seem new, and that is part of what has made the revival aspect of early music so successful and exciting.

&gt; 
&gt; [http://www.medieval.org/emfaq/misc/whatis.htm](http://www.medieval.org/emfaq/misc/whatis.htm)
&gt; 
&gt; 
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe we have something to learn from the Early Music Movement. Tango dancing is from a not so distant past, but it has not been very well documented, and that leaves us with many of the same problems as interpreters of Early Music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I understand it, one important conductor of early music is &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roger_Norrington&#34;&gt;Roger Norrington&lt;/a&gt;, and one of his pet peeves is the contemporary (over) use of the vibrato. (According to Mark Katz, due to the different needs of recorded music, a &amp;lsquo;phonographic effect&amp;rsquo;. A&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/0520261054/&#34;&gt; recommended read&lt;/a&gt;.) Norrington has some interesting thoughts on the motivation for searching information on early performances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;[If] Brahms expected to hear a particular sound, I want to know what that was. Or at least I want to hear it a few times before deciding that it is rubbish. But what I have discovered, all the way from Monteverdi to Mahler, is that when music is played as it should be, the sound is wonderful, the expression is wonderful and the instruments match together.

(...)

[They] are beginning to realise you don&#39;t need to put vibrato on everything, like sugar. I know that I&#39;m still the only conductor that really asks them not to. And that many great musicians simply don&#39;t know why they should even reconsider what they essentially learned in college. But I can&#39;t live without trying to see the skull beneath the skin. In the end, I know this project might still fail, or be shelved for 30 years. So if, on the day I die, the world is playing without vibrato, of course I will be delighted. But even if they aren&#39;t, I&#39;ll still be delighted because at least I did.

&gt; 
&gt; [http://www.guardian.co.uk/books/2007/jul/21/music](http://www.guardian.co.uk/books/2007/jul/21/music)
&gt; 
&gt; 
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This mirrors some of my thoughts about learning how the old milongueros danced back in the day.  I may or may not want to dance exactly like they did, but it&amp;rsquo;s worth giving it a try. Maybe, just maybe, they actually knew something that has gone out of fashion, forgotten by most teachers and considered unimportant by most dancers who &amp;lsquo;just want to dance&amp;rsquo;. There are not many left, but there may still be things to learn from the few milongueros still with us, or from people who studied with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One might find that through learning about the idiosyncrasies of a time past, we can discover something that &amp;ndash; even if it is not new &amp;ndash; feels new and refreshing. That by improving our understanding, we can reintroduce the creative act where it seemed lost in new fashions and conformity. That by imposing constraints, paradoxically, we might find freedom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe we need an Early Tango Movement?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributing to the Digital Tango Archive</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/12/11/contributing-to-the-digital-tango-archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2010 13:46:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/12/11/contributing-to-the-digital-tango-archive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/erielookingproductions/4080575123/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2464/4080575123_c522fec054.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Library Donations Box by erielookingproductions, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/erielookingproductions/&#34;&gt; erielookingproductions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have written about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/07/31/a-labour-of-love-that-needs-more-lovers/&#34;&gt;effort of Tango Via to digitally archive the entire tango catalogue&lt;/a&gt;, and how &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/12/21/inside-the-digital-archive/&#34;&gt;I was impressed with their ambitions, the work so far&lt;/a&gt; and the significance of preserving the tango culture for the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an update to point your attention to their &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tangovia.org/membresias.htm&#34;&gt;donation page&lt;/a&gt;, you can &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.helpargentina.org/en/digitalarchive&#34;&gt;donate via Help Argentina&lt;/a&gt; if you are outside Argentina. If in Argentina, they suggest you get in touch with them to get instructions for donations. If you have important original material, that is also a way to contribute to the project, but I suspect hard cash is what my readers are most likely to have for offer. US residents get a tax exempt under the terms of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/501(c)#501.28c.29.283.29&#34;&gt;501(c.3)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read more about the digital archive and &lt;a href=&#34;http://tangovia.org&#34;&gt;Tango Vía&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/08/10/tango-via-in-el-tangauta/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/10/29/ignacio-varchausky-interview/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.guardian.co.uk/culture/2010/oct/05/argentina-dance-tango-buenos-aires&#34;&gt;in The Guardian&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of the Cabeceo Part I: Are You Flirting With Me?</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/10/23/the-art-of-the-cabeceo-part-i-are-you-flirting-with-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2010 13:45:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/10/23/the-art-of-the-cabeceo-part-i-are-you-flirting-with-me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/pedrosimoes7/60010574/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/32/60010574_149e48d8af.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rita N by pedrosimoes7, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/pedrosimoes7/&#34;&gt; pedrosimoes7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;Nobody asks me to dance, complained our Canadian classmate. We were sitting at our table in the Buenos Aires Golf Club, overlooking the dark course and the city skyline. We started chatting about the cabeceo, surely she knew the habit of the Porteño dancer to ask by catching a potential partner&amp;rsquo;s eye and confirming with a slight nod towards the pista?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course she didn&amp;rsquo;t. On the contrary, she brought her habit of avoiding to meet the eye of men she did not know, avoiding unwanted attention and flirts from strangers, as she did back home. That is effectively the same as wearing a sign saying you&amp;rsquo;re not interested in dancing, and that habit had be brought to an end in the milongas. Instead, watching attentively and gently transmit the intent of watching out for dancers, is the way to go. If dancing is what you&amp;rsquo;re after, of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the golf club, the women wore furs, black dresses and pearls, and mostly went with their suit-clad husbands, who were in turn occupied with taking care of their women or occasionally a close friend in their company. Yet there also were also people interested in dancing with people outside their own table&amp;hellip; Our classmate headed over towards the bar, where she kept her eyes open for dancing opportunities. It didn&amp;rsquo;t take long before she was out on the floor. And on the floor she remained for the rest of the night, dancing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extraordinary dancing, thoughts about tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/08/23/extraordinary-dancing-thoughts-about-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2010 19:51:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/08/23/extraordinary-dancing-thoughts-about-tango/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/LIckScLypGA&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This extraordinary video gave me some food for thought and made me finish a line of reasoning that started after noticing a youtube comment. Complaining that the dancing was all acrobatics, but had no feeling for the music. Sounded very familiar, only this time it was not tango dancers, but &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/B-boy&#34;&gt;b-boys&lt;/a&gt; they were complaining about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hip hop and tango have quite some things in common (and obvious differences, of course). Both span several cultural expressions in being essentially urban subcultures. Different times, different places, both have a reputation for somewhat old fashioned gender roles and have grown from local fenomenon to global activity with a strong pop culture image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, in addition to being fascinating in its own artistic right, a few things got me thinking about tango about this video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dancer&amp;rsquo;s statements&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The choice of music&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The role of the internet&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**The internet: **As more and more material gets posted on youtube and other places, ideas on how to dance tango spreads much faster around the globe than before. Now even old footage of several of the old milongueros begin to become available. While we often had to rely on someone&amp;rsquo;s teacher&amp;rsquo;s teacher&amp;rsquo;s teacher, often we can see for ourselves. People always watched and learned from each other, now it is more available than before. Some see this development as a problem, to me it is mainly a positive force. The dedicated beginner can learn a lot from a few hours before the computer that took years of traveling not many years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dancing to the &amp;lsquo;wrong&amp;rsquo; music:&lt;/strong&gt; All the dance numbers in this video are performed to music not associated with this kind of dancing. It is music from a different culture. It is not music from the streets, it is &amp;ldquo;art music&amp;rdquo;. Besides the effect of the unexpected, I assume the connotations of the more respected art form are very much intended for, demonstrating the artistic value of the dance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But at the same time betraying the very culture that fostered these talented dancers. It is a powerful effect, but it could wear off soon. That is what I think happened  with the electrotango in the wake of the first Gotan Project and Bajofondo albums. It first sounded very refreshing and promising, but after a while the classics proved why they were classics, once again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What works well in a show does not always work in the social dancing setting. Some people think electrotango is a way of building a bridge between familiar pop music and the real tango. Lately, I have found that I believe it is counter productive in building musical awareness, as people tend to end up thinking tango is danced to any music, and even after dancing for years, they can&amp;rsquo;t tell tango from other rhythms. At one point I played a short tanda of cumbia at a milonga (requested by several dancers), and some people started dancing milonga. The visiting teacher was shaking his head&amp;hellip;. &amp;ndash;This is &lt;strong&gt;cumbia&lt;/strong&gt;, not milonga!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Memorable quotes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;It&#39;s all about details -- everything I move has purpose.
--J Smooth&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;when I&#39;m dancing... &#39;cause at that point it&#39;s just my body and the music, it&#39;s not really a conscious decision, I&#39;m gonna do this next, I&#39;m gonna do this.  It&#39;s kind of like this other level where you can&#39;t make choices anymore, and it&#39;s just your body reacting to certain sounds, and the music
--Kid David&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;it&#39;s never what you do, it&#39;s how it&#39;s done.
--Kid David&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;you create power, then you tame it.
--Lil &#34;C&#34;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**
**&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning the Language of Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/06/27/learning-the-language-of-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2010 17:30:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/06/27/learning-the-language-of-tango/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/simba_tango/4735758259/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4081/4735758259_6f8ae59c6a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;El tango by Simba tango, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-sa/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/simba_tango/&#34;&gt; Simba tango&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t know the language of tango, you&amp;rsquo;ll miss out on a lot, and for once, I don&amp;rsquo;t mean in a metaphorical sense. One anecdote I remember from my early days of tango was being told of a workshop that started with the following announcement:  &amp;rdquo;This is an advanced class, hence it will be taught in Spanish&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;m not sure who it supposedly was that said it, but I have a similar experience with Gustavo Naveira teaching in Buenos Aires with lots of foreigners present: &amp;ndash;Is there anyone here that speaks absolutely no Spanish? (lots of hands in the air) No Spanish at all? (fewer, but still quite a few hands in the air) Then he would go on teaching in Spanish with a few very short, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0335266/&#34;&gt;Lost in translation&lt;/a&gt;-style summaries in English every now and then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is that learning a little Spanish has been of tremendous value in the process of learning the tango. And with one noteable exception, all our main teachers the last few years have been Spanish only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember our first trip to Buenos Aires, taking classes where the instruction sounded more or less like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Blah blah blah blah blah **atras**, blah blah blah blah, **adelante **blah blah blah blah **ocho** blah blah blah....&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As time went by, the number of words we picked up grew, but atras (backwards) and adelante (forwards) and ocho were ones that stood out from the beginning. Fast forward to today, and my Spanish (well Catalan, really) colleague introduces me to a fellow Spanish guy as &amp;ldquo;the guy that speaks &lt;em&gt;Argentine&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;. A bit of an exaggeration, but still, we&amp;rsquo;ve come a long way, and it really helps connecting with people when you go there, even if they actually speak English themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some Argentines insist they speak Castellano, not Español (Spanish), this is also a lesson from our very first trip, and we generally stuck to using the word castellano, as that seemed to insult or irritate noone, and made sure we knew they were no longer a Spanish colony :-) . Anquises &lt;a href=&#34;http://zigurat-anquises.blogspot.com/2009/08/espanol-o-castellano.html&#34;&gt;argues that Español is the more correct term&lt;/a&gt;, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the process of improving one&amp;rsquo;s understanding of a language, a good dictionary is priceless. I already got the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Diccionario-Lunfardo-Spanish-Athos-Espindola/dp/9504909833&#34;&gt;dictionary of Lunfardo&lt;/a&gt;, a regular Spanish dictionary, what I was searching for was an &lt;em&gt;Argentine&lt;/em&gt; dictionary, but that turned out to be uavailable even in one of the great bookstores in Buenos Aires, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/El_Ateneo&#34;&gt;El Ateneo&lt;/a&gt;. The guy in the bookstore told us they used the Spanish ones in school and everywhere else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the Spanish dictionary will take you a long way, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t cover all the local usage. This was clearly demonstrated once as we went to the local pharmacy after looking up what we wanted in the dictionary, only to have them rolling over the counter laughing when we tried to put our newfound knowledge to work. What saved us was a little improvised acting combined with key Spanish words which finally revealed the term used in Argentina. A little body language trumps everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also there are a lot of slang expressions, and we found the slang dictionary &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Puto-El-Que-Lee-Spanish/dp/9872281203/&#34;&gt;Puto el que lee&lt;/a&gt; (diccionario argentino de insultos, injurias e improperios) in a bookstore, and found it would fill in nicely. The Argentines have an astounding number of names for prostitutes and both female and male genetalia, which all come in handy when you want to insult someone or just talk to your friends in a playful manner (¡Che, boludo!). It also has a hilarious appendix with a few tables letting you construct your own insults very easily as well as illustrations, for example covering &amp;lsquo;Grandes hijos de puta del Mundo&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;Grandísimos hijos de puta del Mundo&amp;rsquo; and correspondingly for Argentina. Unfortunately, I&amp;rsquo;m not enough into Argentine politics to get all the Argentines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, one of the last days of our last stay, we started chatting about this with our great host, and he suggested we got the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Diccionario-del-Habla-Argentinos-Spanish/dp/9500430282/&#34;&gt;Diccionario del habla de los Argentinos&lt;/a&gt;. At last. This relatively recent publication actually passed our little test of words we learnt from some of our porteño friends, and we could look them all up in the dictionary. It was too late to buy it in Buenos Aires, but we ordered it  from Argentina via Amazon. Amazing that you can actually get all of these books on Amazon! A bit more expensive, but it comes with this fuzzy feeling inside when there is mail from Argentina in the mailbox :-) The illustration photo is from this dictionary.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is it not in the public domain?</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/01/02/why-is-it-not-in-the-public-domain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2010 01:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/01/02/why-is-it-not-in-the-public-domain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/biwook/145765624/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2010/01/copyright.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A copyright will protect you from PIRATE by Ioan Sameli, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-sa/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/biwook/&#34;&gt; Ioan Sameli&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Entering a new year, it can be wise to give thought to how things could have been. Most of the world follows the USA when it comes to copyright laws, and they keep extending the copyright terms again and again. Which makes very little sense from a society stand point. Extending the copyright on the 1930s recordings of Juan D&amp;rsquo;Arienzo isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly making him pour out new hit records every month&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the US copyright law valid until 1978 were still in effect (and equivalent law in the rest of the world), &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.law.duke.edu/cspd/publicdomainday/pre1976&#34;&gt;recordings made up to 1953 would today enter the public domain&lt;/a&gt;. Since it is not, we have to resort to quasi (ill)legal means to get copies of some of the very gems of the golden age tango recordings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tangocommuter &lt;a href=&#34;http://tangocommuter1.blogspot.com/2010/01/something-worrying.html&#34;&gt;is feeling the pain&lt;/a&gt;. I say it&amp;rsquo;s time to do something about these ridiculous laws.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inside the digital archive</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/22/inside-the-digital-archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2009 01:45:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/22/inside-the-digital-archive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/erica_marshall/2656065581/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3148/2656065581_1d1732991b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Hard Drive Guts by Erica_Marshall, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/erica_marshall/&#34;&gt; Erica_Marshall&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Ignacio Varchausky gave his &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/12/19/what-to-listen-for-in-tango/&#34;&gt;musicality seminar&lt;/a&gt; at the&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.visittangobuenosaires.com/La_Casa_del_Tango-sp.htm&#34;&gt; Casa de tango&lt;/a&gt; here in Buenos Aires, where the &lt;a href=&#34;http://tangovia.org/&#34;&gt;TangoVía&lt;/a&gt; project resides, he was kind to show us around the premises and demonstrate the current state of the digital archive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They have a very &lt;a href=&#34;http://tangovia.org/archivo_audio.htm&#34;&gt;nice set of equipment&lt;/a&gt;, he showed us the machine they use to clean the discs properly before doing the transfers, the different turntables for different kinds of discs, amplifiers and ADC as well as tape equipment. In addition to the recordings themselves, they are scanning or photographing the covers and where available, the original scores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the really interesting part was when Ignacio sat down in front of a computer and demonstrated the already working database with everything that was already digitized and properly catalogued. From a nice web interface, one could perform all kinds of searches in the music, matrix number, original format, artist, year etc. From the results page, you could play an mp3 version of the material directly, and where available you could open the scores and watch them while listening to the music. Very impressive, and no doubt this will become an important tool for musicians, dancers and researchers in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, I was very interested in their plans with respect to releasing the material they are collecting. That is the next phase, said Ignacio, first they have to collect the material, and archive it properly. Then the legal issues have  to be resolved. They hope to be able to put the database online eventually, for everybody to enjoy the richness of tango through the ages. Then they will think about releasing records. They don&amp;rsquo;t get much if any help from the record companies, in fact in a way they are competitors, as the record companies don&amp;rsquo;t have access to all the material themselves anymore. The record companies have themselves to blame, of course, as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.totango.net/rca.html&#34;&gt;they burned the masters&lt;/a&gt; themselves&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TangoVía are collaborating with a lot of important and knowledgeable collectors, including the local partner of the Japanese Akihito Baba of Club Tango Argentino &amp;lsquo;fame&amp;rsquo;. In addition to published recordings, they will digitize rare gems; tracks recorded from radio broadcasts, outtakes. Ignacio demonstrated a few such hidden jewels of the collections, Horacio Salgán playing and Alfredo Gobbi (violinist) playing solo piano.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can you and I help? If you didn&amp;rsquo;t already listen to the interview by Keith Elshaw, I can tell you that they are launching a program for donating money around March 2010. For U.S. citizens, it will even be tax deductable. I will keep you posted when they launch the new program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to spreading the word, you can start thinking about organizing some charity milongas or adding a voluntary donation to festival/marathon/milonga payment options. I think this is a project clearly worthy of the support from the entire tango community all over the world!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tailored for Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/11/06/tailored-for-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2009 23:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/11/06/tailored-for-tango/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wmacphail/3231382603/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3377/3231382603_9083a84d93.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Emil Fusaro - Shears by wmacphail, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/wmacphail/&#34;&gt; wmacphail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;Come back here! You are not entering the floor without buttoning your jacket! Her voice left no doubt, and the young aspiring dancer stepped back, buttoned his jacket and went back on the dance floor. He was smiling, but he would not commit the same error again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In one of my very first tango lessons, I was told that the Argentine dancers would &lt;strong&gt;never&lt;/strong&gt; take off their jacket for dancing. After going to Buenos Aires, one realizes that it must have been quite some time since a man would refuse to take off his jacket for such a mundane reason as it being a little warm, making him uncomfortable. People mostly dress nice, but suits are not all that common. But there is something there. You should keep your jacket on, and there are many reasons why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Suits do have [..] a way of looking superior (p 114)&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This quote, and all the following, are from the book &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/Sex-Suits-Evolution-Modern-Dress/dp/1870626672&#34;&gt;Sex &amp;amp; Suits&lt;/a&gt;, written by Anne Hollander, and it helped me fill out some blanks and connect some stuff about the relations between tango and how clothes make the dancer. Or maybe the dance, we&amp;rsquo;ll get back to that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find that tango generally looks better when the man wears a suit, (I will explain why later). It could be just out of habit, of course, as tango was developed when men basically wore suits, but I thought it was something more there. And if we are to believe Hollander, there is indeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hollander sees a clear connection between the development of the suit and the rise of the modern movement as seen in other art forms such as music, painting and architecture. At the same time, in Argentina, starts the evolution of tango. Tango is a very modern dance in the same sense of the word, and was breaking loose from earlier dances which were heavily choreographed and didn&amp;rsquo;t allow physical proximity in that way. Think film adaptations of Jane Austen novels. Man and woman met only briefly during the dance. This changed with the invention of modern couple dancing, led by the walz and followed by the tango, introduced in Paris in the 1910s. Hollander notices this as well, but only mentions it very briefly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;The changes in women&#39;s fashion coincided with the spread of close couple-dancing as an ordinary pastime (..) p 136&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeing the evolution of tango in relationship with the modern movement in general can be revealing in other respects, too, but we will concentrate on the topic of clothing here. Early signs of modernism appeared when the West rediscovered (again) the classical ideals and the art of Ancient Greece. One thing that changed as a consequence of this, writes Hollander, is that the youth ideal was revived with other classical ideals, and the ideas about what a body should look like changed from the reigning pear shaped ideal to a more athletic (young) body ideal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following from that came the development of something that resembles a modern suit. The lines were made cleaner, one saw a removal of clutter, in exchange for an easy elegance. The tailors set out to transform their clients&amp;rsquo; bodies towards this new ideal, and in the process invented modern tailoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;(...) by the turn of the century, elegance had shifted entirely away from wrought surfaces to fundamental form, and away from courtly refinement to natural simplicity. (p 90)&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;In their pure form, they express a confident adult masculinity, unflavored with either violence or passivity. The suit reflects purposeful development (...) it has the modern look of carefully simplified dynamic abstraction that has its own strong sexual appeal. (p 113)&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The suit enhances how the man wearing it looks, moving in direction of the ideal, athletic body. At the same time, it is simple, and reveals that there is indeed a moving body inside, from which it takes much of its strength, if we are to believe Hollander. It is also interesting to note that the (three piece) suit was originally used for leisure, and seen as  &amp;rsquo;informal&amp;rsquo; attire, which is obviously something that has since changed, now being associated with work and formal occasions like weddings and tango nights&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find that not only does the suit enhance the dancer (how he looks) by enhancing the body shape, it also enhances the dance (in terms of how it looks).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By allowing some movement, while gently hiding other details, for instance by deemphasizing the chest lead and dissossiation both lead to more surprises for the onlookers, while simultaneously making the dancer look calm, athletic, powerful and elegant (as usually associated with suits). This is especially true with figures like enrosques, giros and lapises where the male dancer&amp;rsquo;s upper and lower body almost seem to be disconnected. The torso calm, clean and in control, the feet shooting around in intricate steps at high speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And one thing that is characteristic of tango, is the dissosiation between the upper and lower body. The upper body calm, introvert, embracing your partner, following the melody. The feet moving with the rhythm, making fast movements, intermingling with your partners&amp;rsquo; feet. Two different modes at once.  I believe many dancers choose how to dress to emphasize this image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sometimes wonder if the dancers often associated with Gustavo Naveira and his very structural approach to tango are more interested in exposing the inner workings of the movements, rather than hiding them, celebrating the raw movement rather than the &amp;lsquo;magic&amp;rsquo; and surprise? Like the more contemporary &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.greatbuildings.com/buildings/Centre_Pompidou.html&#34;&gt;Centre Pompidou&lt;/a&gt; in Paris is exposing the inner workings of the building, maybe they want to expose the mechanics of the dance? Make all structural elements visible, to tell the true story, one could imagine the nuevo movement going in this direction, in their search to uncover every secret of the tango movements. Show everything. Make it all clear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess you would need to dress in tight fitting t-shirt and trousers to make every movement transparent.  And it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really seem like they move in that direction, exactly. However, the further development of clothing in the 20th century fits in well with the &amp;lsquo;rebels&amp;rsquo; of tango, in moving on towards outfits even more derived from leisure clothing, throwing away the jacket and going for the shirt, sweater or t-shirt instead. Some dancers (e.g. Naveira, Chicho) notoriously dance in large tunikas or shirts which to some degree hides disossiation, though much less than a proper suit. Large, baggy pants, emphasizing leg movements, but hiding to some degree the exact placement of the legs. Trousers with light, fluffy fabrics that follow and emphasize the movements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a sense, argues Hollander, this further development of clothing is also based on the suit and has a subversive element as has all fashion. It exposes what was once essentially underwear, shirts and t-shirts, once worn under the suit, now daringly exposed. As is the mechanics of the movement itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now how about women? I always adored how the womens&amp;rsquo; skirts enhance the round movements like ochos, giros, boleos etc. Caressing the lady, creating nice lines and following, then extending the curved movement. Very nice indeed, when the skirt continues a movement in one direction, while the body already has started on the counter movement like in a boleo for instance. Hollander sees this fashion as the wave of modernity arriving much later for womens clothing  than for men, essentially at the same time that tango really took off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;(...)evening dresses were more gauzy and feminine than ever, now calf-length to show feet and ankles in exciting shoes and stockings, and very loose and revealing above the waist. Withouth tight waists and big petticoats, the bodies wearing them looked very real indeed, the breasts and hips connected in an organic human relation, and the feet and legs in plain sight. Posture, formerly very straight and queenly to go with the expanse and stiffness of the clothes, now allowed for an easy and relaxed slouch---another defining and irreversible sigh of female modernity(...) p 131&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;In the second decade of [the 20th] century, however, the furs and soft wollens and silks clinging to the yielding figure seemed at last to confess that a woman could feel her own body; and they straightforwardly invited others to grasp and stroke her as a physically responsive living creature. p134&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;By 1925, modern skirts were knee-length and not cumbersome, and they gave off no mysterious suggestions. After that, the hem moved up and down, but never all the way down for good. Skirts tended to delineate the pelvis and thighs, to move with them instead of independently, and to cover with what seemed like a single layer of fabric, just as men&#39;s trousers did. p146f&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I won&amp;rsquo;t go as far as suggesting that tango was determined by changes in fashion at the  time, but it seems clear to me that like many other things falling into place at the time created an environment where the tango could develop into the form we know it today during the golden age. And the changes in dressing is one of these pieces that shaped preferences or what was considered good form at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading the book only reinforced my view that &amp;lsquo;traditional&amp;rsquo; is a bit of a misnomer for a dance that really has &lt;strong&gt;modern&lt;/strong&gt; written all over it in capital letters. And it is a paradox that the clothing that many today see as stiff and formal once was the clothing of leisure, like t-shirts, sportswear and jeans are today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well &amp;ndash; myself I have always been a nostalgic for the modern, so for me it makes perfect sense to dress up for tango. And as I explained above, I think it makes the dance (look) better. Depending on the fabrics, it may also feel better. Not long ago one of the comments to a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7gSQgrXfwKE&#34;&gt;youtube video&lt;/a&gt; complimenting the male dancer ended &amp;lsquo;(&amp;hellip;) and the man knows how to dress!!&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coincidence? I think not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Credit to &lt;a href=&#34;http://mshedgehog.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Ms Hedgehog&lt;/a&gt; for&lt;a href=&#34;http://mshedgehog.blogspot.com/2009/06/priscilla-queen-of-desert-sex-and-suits.html&#34;&gt; directing my attention to the book&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homero Manzi, un poeta en la tormenta</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/23/homero-manzi-un-poeta-en-la-tormenta/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 23:35:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/23/homero-manzi-un-poeta-en-la-tormenta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/09/23/homero-manzi-un-poeta-en-la-tormenta/manzi/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/09/manzi.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;manzi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.manzilapelicula.com.ar/&#34;&gt;new film&lt;/a&gt; about the tango poet &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.todotango.com/english/creadores/manzi.html&#34;&gt;Homero Manzi&lt;/a&gt; was just released in Argentina. Manzi is the author of famous tangos like &lt;em&gt;Malena&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Sur&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Barrio de tango&lt;/em&gt;. He worked with Troilo for several years, and in cooperation with Sebastián Piana, he revitalized the milonga genre with &lt;em&gt;Milonga sentimental&lt;/em&gt; in 1931.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film is apparently a combination of archive material and reconstruction of scenes from his life. It will be interesting to watch, I will probably wait until it is available on dvd, hopefully it won&amp;rsquo;t take that long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.10tango.com/notas/135391-homero-manzi-biopic&#34;&gt;more about the film here&lt;/a&gt; or watch the trailer here:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/Ljh5eGAiChU&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;HT: &lt;a href=&#34;http://jantango.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;Janis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In search for the authentic</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/07/in-search-for-the-authentic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2009 02:18:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/07/in-search-for-the-authentic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/mr38/143786705/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/52/143786705_0c712c0e95.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;AUTHENTIC REPRODUCTIONS by MR38, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/mr38/&#34;&gt; MR38&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We love our &lt;strong&gt;Argentine Tango&lt;/strong&gt; (or maybe &lt;strong&gt;Tango Argentino&lt;/strong&gt;) to be sure. Do not bastardize it, please. We want the real thing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, there is no one tango. Tango is a living expression of the people who play, sing, listen to and dance it. My tango is different from yours, or I sure hope so. Not too different, but a little different. That&amp;rsquo;s what makes it interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I do love Italy and Italian food (no wonder I love Buenos Aires?), I thought I would share this interesting &lt;a href=&#34;http://blindtaste.com/2009/07/24/the-problem-with-fetishizing-pork-jowl/&#34;&gt;article discussing authenticity in the Italian kitchen&lt;/a&gt;. Serves well (pun intended) as an apropos to the very same discussion on tango.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buon appetito!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>--A labour of love that needs more lovers</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/31/a-labour-of-love-that-needs-more-lovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2009 20:59:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/31/a-labour-of-love-that-needs-more-lovers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alexkerhead/2739759537/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3253/2739759537_9eaa446d5b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Three minutes to the End by alexkerhead, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/alexkerhead/&#34;&gt; alexkerhead&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Man of action. Man of ambition:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;[Tango Vía](http://www.tangovia.org/), the organization this tango double-bass player from the famous [Orquesta El Arranque](http://www.orquestaelarranque.com.ar) presides, is up to nothing less than archiving every single tango recording in a super-high definition, archive-grade digital format, following strict technical processing that will drastically enhance the sound quality to make it an almost-perfect match to the pristine original.

&gt; 
&gt; [Buenos Aires Herald](http://buenosairesherald.com/PrintedEdition/View/4262)
&gt; 
&gt; 
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wonder how we could help them succeed with this project, arranging some sort of fund raiser or something? &lt;a href=&#34;http://buenosairesherald.com/PrintedEdition/View/4262&#34;&gt;Read the entire article here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AFP on youtube:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/QQQiR2mx5i8&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;BBC:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HT: &lt;a href=&#34;http://jantango.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;Janis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technological advances in tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/09/technological-advances-in-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2009 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/09/technological-advances-in-tango/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/carrotcreative/2511539541/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2039/2511539541_b8c0356486.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Twitter Pack  by carrotcreative, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/carrotcreative/&#34;&gt; carrotcreative&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to say I feel a bit like an oldie, writing this, but I am kind of old-school when it comes to tango, so I guess that&amp;rsquo;s ok..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t help but notice how many things have changed since I first started with tango. Not the dance itself, but things around it. Technological changes that the newcomers in tango seem to take for granted, were simply not available only a few years back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;comme-il-faut&#34;&gt;Comme il faut&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sexy and life threatening stilettos of comme il faut did not exist when my tango career started. I think they started around 2003, at least that&amp;rsquo;s when I first heard about them. Definitely not by 2001. And surprisingly, noone has been able to copy their formula just yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One (post Comme il faut) tango friend commented on La Princesa&amp;rsquo;s (pre Comme il faut) shoes and thought it &amp;lsquo;impossible&amp;rsquo; to dance with such clunky, heavy shoes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before they were comme il faut. Now there is Comme il faut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;online-music&#34;&gt;Online music&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, it is not quite there, both Rhapsody and Napster (the legal one) have very limited tango catalogues, and I believe the same to be the case with Spotify. I have a large collection already, but for beginners, I presume it can be very useful. It took time and effort and money to get something remiscent of a tango collection, the first step is now much easier, and lots of music is available at tangostore.com and amazon.com as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before they would give you Piazzolla. Now you can get Racciatti.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;youtube&#34;&gt;YouTube&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An old VHS that some friends had copied from another friend, taped from Solo tango was all we had. Watching old shows at their place. Then we ordered vastly overpriced dvds from CITA once a year for some years. The last time I ordered the dvd, I was talking with the friends with the VHS about how I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really thrilled by the latest CITA dvd. I realized it was because I preferred watching my favorite dancers (not on CITA) at youtube. For free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you had to ask: how is their dancing? Now you can check it out yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;social-networking&#34;&gt;Social networking&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So many of my tango friends and aquaintances are now on facebook, I think it will be much easier to get into the flow the next time in Buenos Aires. Before, one would have to track down the latest &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eltangauta.com&#34;&gt;Tangauta&lt;/a&gt; to know what was going on. Today it is all online, available even before you leave home. It will be interesting to see if twitter will have any use in tango, I can see it as a means of coordination, but facebook seems like a stronger contestant at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you would hope some friends showed up. Now you can follow them on your favorite social networking site. Who are you on twitter?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sport and Culture</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/15/sport-and-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2009 13:02:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/15/sport-and-culture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wigwam/2255847374/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2304/2255847374_3ac4e43ccf.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;8th Annual University of Michigan Ballro by Wigwam Jones, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/wigwam/&#34;&gt; Wigwam Jones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People often think of ballroom dancing when they hear I dance tango. Assuming I participate in competitions. And we would not want anybody to think that, would we?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It appears absurd to me, but it occurred to me the other day that they assume dancing is about sports. Which it is obviously not. It is all about culture.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>