<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Learning Tango on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/categories/learning-tango/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Learning Tango on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/categories/learning-tango/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Do the Argentines have it in their blood?</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/18/do-the-argentines-have-it-in-their-blood/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2010 18:13:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/18/do-the-argentines-have-it-in-their-blood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/themanwithsalthair/1444011429/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1402/1444011429_f533d7804c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;African Tribal Dance, Togo by themanwithsalthair, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/themanwithsalthair/&#34;&gt; themanwithsalthair&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;You have to realize, Simba, that there are great non-Argentine teachers, too! This argument came up in a heated debate, and while I agree in principle, the teachers she had in mind were mediocre at best, so it didn&amp;rsquo;t really change my opinion much. In an online debate along similar lines, I once noticed an attempt to ridicule the ones pointing out the Argentines&amp;rsquo; comparative advantage in tango by comparing them to people holding the view that the &amp;lsquo;negroes had it in their blood&amp;rsquo; (when talking about rhythm, obviously).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Easy to agree in principle, but is it supported by evidence? Anyone who has seen African dance performed by Africans alongside their Northern European caucasian imitators would be tempted to conclude otherwise. As in the case with the Argentines and tango, mind you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, I am not saying they actually have it in their blood, that it is something genetical. Still, there is a difference, and it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t come as a surprise that I think it is cultural. Getting cultural impulses since birth makes quite a difference. It is  tango by osmosis. Hearing the music, knowing the places, the language, the way they walk&amp;hellip; It goes on and on. Seeing dancers in the milongas that actually know what they are doing, and being able to take lessons with great teachers regularly over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While in the U.S. I once witnessed a mother of African heritage and her son just a few years old. The son suddenly burst out into a spontaneous dance. The mother cheered with joy: &amp;ndash;Yeah baby, do your dance!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if not in their blood, possibly in their mother&amp;rsquo;s milk?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which led me to think: Then, when will we see someone that grew up with tango fanatics outside of Argentina? Admittedly, it would still not be quite the same as growing up in Argentina, but growing up with tango parents would reduce the gap considerably, being exposed to music and dance from an early age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The resurgence of tango started in the early eighties, and they would have needed some time to learn tango confidently themselves, so say babies born in the late eighties or early nineties&amp;hellip; should be around twenty by now. It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t surprise me if a hot shot couple from the old world entered the scene soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How less becomes more</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/01/how-less-becomes-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 20:02:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/01/how-less-becomes-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/hooverine/2802881741/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3199/2802881741_b187d6c530.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;less is more by hooverine, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/hooverine/&#34;&gt; hooverine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was something she said that stayed with me. So well put. &amp;lsquo;When he leads a step, say backwards for the woman&amp;rsquo;, Graciela said, &amp;lsquo;then there is one possibility: going backwards. There are not three possible steps. Not three, not two. &lt;strong&gt;One.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the time I see so called &amp;lsquo;advanced&amp;rsquo; dancers, throwing their partners around, the women looking like nervous chicken trying to guess the right thing to do for each and every step. It looks like they are thinking: Did he mean here, or here, or maybe here&amp;hellip; .Waiting till the last possible moment before moving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then they teach &amp;lsquo;active following&amp;rsquo;, taking the opportunity to teach women to take over control, thereby totally missing the point. It is like deciding which step next is more important than anything else, so we have to make sure we decide 50% each, and to make sure we pass control back and forth all through the tango. Yeah, that sounds nice. My turn! Your turn! My turn!&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the lead is absolutely crystal clear and make﻿s the woman 100% confident she knows exactly what step is led, she will feel like she has all the time in the world to shape the way she makes that step, thus enabling her to express the music. This is what giving the woman space is about, not sending control back and forth. It is a simplification, but we often say that in tango, the man decides &amp;lsquo;what&amp;rsquo;, the woman &amp;lsquo;how&amp;rsquo;. And you have probably heard that in tango, the &lt;strong&gt;how&lt;/strong&gt; is more important than the &lt;strong&gt;what&lt;/strong&gt;, no?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the man is actually listening (figuratively speaking) to the woman throughout the dance, he will feel her suggestions and ideas, maybe even before she knows it herself and vice versa. That is when the magic occurs. Passing a stick back and forth is not very magical. Well, maybe if it were a wand&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trouble is, I am afraid you have to dance with some really, really good dancers to understand what I mean. Then you may feel how by taking away, you add something. Remove some possibilities and open up for others. Remove the noise and free the signal. Removing all unnecessary cruft from one&amp;rsquo;s dancing is one of the things that make tango a life long project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the magic that arises makes it totally worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treating the symptoms</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/06/treating-the-symptoms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2009 00:41:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/06/treating-the-symptoms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/dradd/2410180992/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2175/2410180992_402a6c1c23.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Pill Mosaic Redux II by Dradd., on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/dradd/&#34;&gt; Dradd.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a laugh when I read &lt;a href=&#34;http://movementinvitesmovement.wordpress.com/2009/11/26/sweating-and-tango-something-is-wrong/&#34;&gt;this part&lt;/a&gt; by MovementInvitesMovement. In their wonderful, provocative style, they wrote an entire post about something that I hinted at &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/11/06/tailored-for-tango/#comment-473&#34;&gt;in a comment&lt;/a&gt; in my &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/11/06/tailored-for-tango/&#34;&gt;post about clothes and tango&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Some hard core dancers would say that if it gets too warm with the jacket on, you are waisting energy ![;-)](http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif)&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When my beloved wife read that, her immediate reaction was: &lt;strong&gt;hard core dancers&lt;/strong&gt;? Why didn&amp;rsquo;t you write &lt;strong&gt;milonguero&lt;/strong&gt;? I see her point, while in our household, they can be considered synonyms, it opens for misunderstandings. Isn&amp;rsquo;t the clueless guy spinning around like a ventilador (we all know how that &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/11/24/hola-papa-noel/&#34;&gt;may turn out&lt;/a&gt;) from festival to festival hard core? Milonguero resolves the ambiguity elegantly by removing the cluelessness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I sometimes wonder if this obsession with sweat is an anglo-american thing, as all the posts I can remember about this have been from that cultural sphere, but that is probably just exposing my prejudice. Of course, you should take the natural precautions, just as everywhere else, but if you have to resort to sportswear to keep dry&amp;hellip; I said it before, and I will repeat it now: Going to a milonga means &lt;strong&gt;going out&lt;/strong&gt;, not, I repeat: &lt;strong&gt;NOT work out&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While learning to dance tango certainly takes a lot of effort, dancing in a social context doesn&amp;rsquo;t really require much effort. On stage is a different matter, of course, but there is an awful lot of steps and sequences you can do without getting all wet if you do it right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One practical tip for those of you still tempted to just numb your body and go on as before: work on your pivots. Yes gentlemen, I am talking to you. It is frustrating to see so called advanced dancers throwing themselves and their partner around in order to make the next step of the giro on the beat, when all it takes is a little pivot. I don&amp;rsquo;t know about &amp;lsquo;most efficient&amp;rsquo;, but certainly a lot more efficient and clearly a lot more elegant.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting out of the quagmire</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/10/09/getting-out-of-the-quagmire/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2009 03:40:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/10/09/getting-out-of-the-quagmire/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/HWwDIfb6J30&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I was considering using a grandiose title for this post. Something like &lt;em&gt;Return of a King&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;The Comeback&lt;/em&gt; or something along those lines. But it doesn&amp;rsquo;t quite feel that way. I feels more like finally getting a kick in the butt, and slowly getting out of the quagmire, one millimeter at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually it was rather two kicks in the butt. The first was that a couple we know here that is in the same situation as us actually went to a tango dance &lt;em&gt;before us&lt;/em&gt;. And they don&amp;rsquo;t even dance&amp;hellip; The second was an announcement that made a tiny, but unmissable spark in the eyes of La Princesa. Graciela Gonzalez is giving workshops for one week-end. Since we never took lessons from her, but know she&amp;rsquo;s done great work with women&amp;rsquo;s technique and worked with great masters such as Pupi Castello and Pepito Avellaneda, we really wanted to go. Not only to sharpen up our dancing, but also to see how she teaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been a long time, and rusty doesn&amp;rsquo;t even come close. But we are going to take some classes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thrill your partners...  (1940)</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/26/thrill-your-partners...--1940/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2009 02:21:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/26/thrill-your-partners...--1940/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/09/thrill-your-partners.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/09/thrill-your-partners.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;thrill your partners&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;**Jim used to wonder** why he never enjoyed dancing---why he hesitated whenever he asked a friend to be his partner. One evening when he was trying to make up his mind to ask a very charming young lady to dance, he suddenly realized that if his dancing were more modern... he would get more enjoyment out of life. Jim took a few lessons at the Arthur Murray Studios. Today he is not only an excellent dancer, but he has also gained poise and confidence.

&gt; 
&gt; Ad in [LIFE - Oct 14, 1940](http://books.google.com/books?id=LEoEAAAAMBAJ&amp;pg=PA14&amp;dq=tango&amp;as_pt=MAGAZINES#v=onepage&amp;q=tango&amp;f=false)
&gt; 
&gt; 
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The illusion of effortlessness requires a great effort indeed</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/11/the-illusion-of-effortlessness-requires-a-great-effort-indeed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2009 14:34:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/11/the-illusion-of-effortlessness-requires-a-great-effort-indeed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/mjzitek/475244661/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/184/475244661_4fd502446d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Weight Lifting by mjzitek, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/mjzitek/&#34;&gt; mjzitek&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elegance. You know it when you see it, but it can be hard to point your finger at exactly what it is that makes a couple elegant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Effortlessness. Natural movement. Simple, clean and concise. No wasted energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t come easy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Up and down</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/03/02/up-and-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2009 15:29:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/03/02/up-and-down/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/ableman/534153791/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1125/534153791_20e37d5eec.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The Mind Eraser by Scott Ableman, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/ableman/&#34;&gt; Scott Ableman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;-Have you been practicing tango nuevo?&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guilty as charged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He knew immediately. And it was not because I used an open embrace, we were practicing milonga, using a very confined embrace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I often wonder why people get so hang up on the somewhat arbitrary distinction between open and close embrace (all teachers, both &amp;ldquo;nuevo&amp;rdquo; and others usually promote very close embrace at times, but for some figures it is not possible to maintain the closest embrace.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some say that the technique is the same. Well, it is mostly compatible, and that is what matters, but there are some differences. Which was clearly demonstrated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What gave me away was that my energy was going down. That might not be the correct way of putting it, but you get the idea. What he wanted was energy going &lt;strong&gt;up.&lt;/strong&gt; So the difference was in the energy going up or down (up-traditional, down-nuevo). While staying well grounded, of course. Stretching the spine, effectively going up and down at the same time. Talk about dissosiation&amp;hellip; And it doesn&amp;rsquo;t require less in the balance department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might argue that whatever makes it possible (or easier) to do &lt;insert favorite fancy move here&gt; is worth it. Like in skiing, sacrificing elegance for ability to go faster or jump longer. Bending down for improved balance? Feet more apart?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Myself, I never saw the point of doing as many steps as possible (volcadas/minute anone?). It&amp;rsquo;s not like it&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/03/01/competition/&#34;&gt;competition&lt;/a&gt;, remember?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Body parts</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/22/body-parts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2009 20:02:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/22/body-parts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/balakov/763594852/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1072/763594852_838e7d276f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Stacked Focus Cogs by Balakov, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/balakov/&#34;&gt; Balakov&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Privates can be tough. Very useful, but tough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our first trip to Buenos Aires, my wife and I took privates with Julio &amp;amp; Corina, and we worked on the basics. Of course. We learnt a lot, but it was so much to think about. So much we did wrong. So much to fix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my own sake, it felt like they deconstructed my whole body, just to leave the parts on the floor. For me to pick up and bring back for the next lesson. I felt like I could not dance at all for about a week. (Which was maybe not so far from the truth, as I had not really been dancing for that long.) Even at the prácticas, I felt out of place, unable to relax and enjoy the dance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took some time to reassemble, but it was definitely worth the effort. In reaching the next level, one&amp;rsquo;s awareness of the things that need to be fixed, can give some headache, but when you finally get there, it really improves your dancing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The general feeling has been repeated with various other teachers over the years, but with more experience it takes less effort to put myself together after groundbraking changes. Well &amp;ndash; maybe not less effort. But it breaks me down for a shorter time. And I am better prepared in advance. Maybe the errors I have to fix are not as grave as they used to be. I like to think of it that way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empty movement</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/04/empty-movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2009 20:43:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/04/empty-movement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/bass_nroll/2397838219/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2043/2397838219_d126f3b0c9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;[empty] by bass_nroll, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/bass_nroll/&#34;&gt; bass_nroll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you probably know, tango is not merely a dance. Among other things, the dance is also a language. It is not like a language, because the different movements have different meanings, which can be used for actual communication. It is not a metaphor. However, when people copy movements without realizing the underlying meaning, &lt;a href=&#34;http://lonewalker.blog.co.uk/2009/01/25/midsummer-nights-tango-part-5441668/&#34;&gt;the result is movements with no meaning&lt;/a&gt;. Empty movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or even worse, you may be saying something without knowing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is somehow like writing calligraphy for decoration only, selecting the &amp;ldquo;nice letters&amp;rdquo;, not knowing the meaning of what you are writing. How about a tattoo reading &amp;ldquo;A fool and his money are easily parted&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Prostitute&amp;rdquo; in Chinese? Don&amp;rsquo;t laugh, it recently happened that a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.independent.co.uk/arts-entertainment/tv/news/chinese-classical-poem-was-brothel-ad-1058031.html&#34;&gt;science journal used an ad for a brothel to decorate the front page&lt;/a&gt; of a special issue on China. They thought the letters &amp;ldquo;looked nice&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So be careful with your tango, remember its mythical origin&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Un beso...</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/26/un-beso.../</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2009 17:33:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/26/un-beso.../</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kevinsteele/36713395/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/22/36713395_059483d0f2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;kiss on the cheek by Kevin Steele, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/kevinsteele/&#34;&gt; Kevin Steele&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buenos Aires is not like home. And when in Rome, drive like the Romans&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the Argentines kiss when they meet. Better get used to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;(...) would lean over, ready to commit the act that, I thought, was reserved only for girlfriends and, on occasion, family.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This guy used a few months it seems, but has written a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.roadjunky.com/article/12/man-kiss-argentina&#34;&gt;really entertaining account of the argentinian kissing habits&lt;/a&gt;. With special attention to male kissing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wikipedia also has &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cheek_kissing&#34;&gt;rich coverage of the topic&lt;/a&gt;, and the Freakonomics blog wonders &lt;a href=&#34;http://freakonomics.blogs.nytimes.com/2009/01/09/who-changes-the-kissing-rules/&#34;&gt;how kissing rules change&lt;/a&gt;. Who decides?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up north, where I live, people are generally very afraid of touching other persons, unless part of the closer circle as the quote mentions. Which makes it kind of hard to to learn how to dance tango. &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2008/11/22/cheek-to-cheek/&#34;&gt;Cheek to cheek&lt;/a&gt;, as it is supposed to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lately, we have used the exotic Argentine greeting habits in class to break the ice. We had everybody greet each other &amp;ldquo;the Argentinian way&amp;rdquo;. People hesitated at first, but as they moved around the circle (everybody greeting all potential partners), the tension gradually receded, and they ended up less afraid to touch each other, and possibly also remembered a few names. A nice start for their tango career.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The real stuff</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/10/the-real-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2009 15:12:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/10/the-real-stuff/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/oed/106075839/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/42/106075839_f5859a6db9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Smallville by oed, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/oed/&#34;&gt; oed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Ah -- you dance **real** milonga (echte Milonga).&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After struggling with my milonga for years, this was the ultimate sign I was finally getting somewhere. And one of my favorite compliments ever. I got a tip from the Argentine host to ask this woman to dance, he thought I should dance with someone good. So I did. And was not disappointed. Starting almost right out with a milonga, which would have terrified me only a year earlier. I used to make sure never to dance milonga with someone unknown to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three months in Buenos Aires working on my milonga more or less every day, practicing the rhythm while brushing my teeth, almost being thrown off the roof by Javier because I did so bad; It made a difference. And not only to the milonga. I think my tango changed to the better as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In many ways the milonga is the crux of the tango, so few know how to do it well. So often you see people dancing &lt;em&gt;fast tango&lt;/em&gt; to milonga music. Which is not the same by far. The milonga appears to be simple, but is not. It is very subtle, and understanding the music is harder, it is not just about the speed. Many of the best milongas aren&amp;rsquo;t that fast, actually. It is about subtle timing, syncopes and clarity. All of which are also needed in tango, but the lack of them is more easily revealed in the milonga.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember we had some friends participating in the 2007 campeonato metropoletano, and is was so much easier to tell the good from the mediocre in milonga. So to find the good dancers, maybe it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to watch their milonga.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy New Year!</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/01/happy-new-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 13:47:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/01/happy-new-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/basibanget/3153089995/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3112/3153089995_1cfcb04f04.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;happy new year 2009 by basibanget, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/basibanget/&#34;&gt; basibanget&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ready for a new year of tango? Remember that if you want to improve, there is &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2008/11/11/the-secret-dont-tell-anyone/&#34;&gt;no secret&lt;/a&gt;, all you have to do is to follow three simple steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn from the best&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Practice (&lt;a href=&#34;http://tango.yyquest.net/learning-process/2009/10000-hour-rule/&#34;&gt;a lot&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Listen to lots of music&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody ever said it was gonna be easy ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yes honey, but is it tango?</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/04/yes-honey-but-is-it-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2008 15:58:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/04/yes-honey-but-is-it-tango/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/11/roy-lichtenstein.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/11/roy-lichtenstein.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Roy Lichtenstein: Girl with Ribbon (1965)&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Roy Lichtenstein: Girl with Ribbon (1965)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is always a lot of fuzz in the tango communities of the world about what is the right tango. And rightly so. There is good and there is bad tango.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in the middle of these heated arguments, we need to remind ourselves of one thing. Tango culture is rich. There is a lot of diversity in tango. Tango is not only dance. It is also music for listening. Tango song is a world of its own. Tango dance is not only for the milonga, but also for the stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One possible source of much of the confusion is that people are unaware of both the richness and the suitness for different purposes. Explore the possibilities and adjust according to circumstances. Nobody minds you practicing lifts or jumps or ganchos or volcadas or whatever you are into. Just behave on the dancefloor. Simple, really.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://enlamilonga.blogspot.com/2008/08/entonces-es-o-no-es-tango.html&#34;&gt;This article by Una milonguera&lt;/a&gt; is also recommended for readers of spanish/castellano.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why we never tire of tango music</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/29/why-we-never-tire-of-tango-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2008 22:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/29/why-we-never-tire-of-tango-music/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/nadworks/219864640/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/63/219864640_5bb97d5c4a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;MY FAVOURITE MUSIC... by nadworks, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/nadworks/&#34;&gt; nadworks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tango music for the non-argentine 21st century tango lover is often something of an acquired taste. At least for tango dancers. The recordings are old, the music sounds strange, we don&amp;rsquo;t understand the lyrics &amp;ndash; but we love the dance&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some time, we get more into the music, it all changes, and we become total fanáticos de tango, we can never get enough of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://tejastango.com/classic_tangos.html&#34;&gt;classics of tango music&lt;/a&gt;. Why do we never get tired of listening to these old recordings, often transferred from old, scratchy 78s, since &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.totango.net/rca.html&#34;&gt;the masters were burnt&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will often hear tango lovers rave about the &lt;em&gt;complexity&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;richness&lt;/em&gt; of tango music. So let us investigate a bit further what is the source of this richness. The title of the first record by the orchestra Escuela de tango, &lt;em&gt;De contrapunto&lt;/em&gt; gives us the first clue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One way to categorize music is by the musical textures, and the three main categories are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Monopohonic&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Homophonic&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Polyphonic&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monophony&#34;&gt;Monophonic&lt;/a&gt; music consists of a single melody line, and is the simplest form of musical texture. Perhaps the best known example in western music is the Gregorian chant. The monophonic music is also the easiest to understand or interpret.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Homophony&#34;&gt;Homophonic&lt;/a&gt; music is slightly more complex, as it consists of a principal melody line accompanied by a chordal accompaniment. Perhaps a bit surprisingly, it is the most recent &amp;ldquo;invention&amp;rdquo;, as it basically did not occur in music created earlier than the end of the 16th century. It was used in a lot of romantic music for increased clarity and thus emotional impact, in contrast with the most complex form, polyphony.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polyphony&#34;&gt;Polyphonic&lt;/a&gt; music is the kind that is the most demanding of the listener. Several melodic lines, or &amp;ldquo;voices&amp;rdquo;, are present at the same time, forming harmonies as they go. To appreciate this, you may have to disregard some parts of the music, and the melodic line (horizontal) will become apparent. This gives a different listening experience than &amp;ldquo;just listening&amp;rdquo; to all the sounds present at the same time (vertical). Depending on which lines you choose, the same piece may be experienced somewhat differently each time. And this is what is actually meant when dancers talk about dancing to different instruments. All voices need not be present at the same time, of course, and some melodic lines will move from instrument to instrument, so dancing different voices would be a more precise definition of what you are actually doing. (The clue from de contrapunto is that &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Counterpoint&#34;&gt;counterpoint&lt;/a&gt; is one special case of polyphonic music)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To quote Aaron Copland in the book &lt;em&gt;What to listen for in music&lt;/em&gt; (on which this post leans heavily),  &amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;repeated hearings keep up your interest better than music of homophonic texture. Even supposing that you do not hear all the separate voices equally well, there is every likelihood that when you return to it again, there will be something different for you to listen to. You can always hear it from a different angle.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pop music springs out from the homophonic tradition from the romantic music. While being popular music, tango from the golden age has a certain quality that you will not generally find in today&amp;rsquo;s popular music, the polyphony. And that also explains why it is much less interesting to dance to pop music than the real stuff. It is simply not enough to throw in some bandoneón samples or having more or less the right rhythm. More on that in a later post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The polyphonic nature of most tango music means there are a lot of ways to listen to the same tune, you can discover something new time after time. And it makes the music sound fresh every time. And thus the dance stays fresh as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technique vs. Feeling</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/27/technique-vs.-feeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2008 21:42:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/27/technique-vs.-feeling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/abhijit/1399642105/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1009/1399642105_b924d9730b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Violinist from MC Rai - 2 BW by my hovercraft is full of eels, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/abhijit/&#34;&gt; my hovercraft is full of eels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which one is most important? Technique or dancing with feeling? I sometimes get the impression that tango dancers are divided in two camps, the technique camp and the feelings camp. The first emphasizes the technical matters of the dance, the latter paying solely attention to the feeling. As long as we can hug each other, all is well ;-) Both seemingly ignoring the other point of view completely. As a matter of fact, I used to get a little annoyed by people who dismissed technique and just wanted to be in the embrace, feeeeeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By what interests me nowadays, I can easily be mistaken for belonging in the feelings camp. I find the technical extravaganzas of many performances quite boring at times, as they convey no emotional content whatsoever (to me, that is). So have I moved to the other camp?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not really, I would rather say I belong in the both are necessary camp. I just  heard an interview on the radio with a conductor visiting one of the major symphony orchestras here, and he made the following statement about the two leading violinists in the orchestra (quoted as I remember it):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;They have very good technique, which allows them to express their musicality.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this is at the heart of the matter. You need good technique. You need it to express your musicality through your dance. You should work hard to improve it, but technique alone will not do. It is a necessary condition, but hardly sufficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And just as the music critics rather discuss the interpretation of an orchestra or musician, I think the artistic interpretation is more interesting to discuss than the technical points. Technique is simple, really: all you need is good teachers and a lot of practice&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>