<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Food on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/tags/food/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Food on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/tags/food/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>In search for the authentic</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/07/in-search-for-the-authentic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2009 02:18:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/07/in-search-for-the-authentic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/mr38/143786705/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/52/143786705_0c712c0e95.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;AUTHENTIC REPRODUCTIONS by MR38, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/mr38/&#34;&gt; MR38&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We love our &lt;strong&gt;Argentine Tango&lt;/strong&gt; (or maybe &lt;strong&gt;Tango Argentino&lt;/strong&gt;) to be sure. Do not bastardize it, please. We want the real thing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, there is no one tango. Tango is a living expression of the people who play, sing, listen to and dance it. My tango is different from yours, or I sure hope so. Not too different, but a little different. That&amp;rsquo;s what makes it interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I do love Italy and Italian food (no wonder I love Buenos Aires?), I thought I would share this interesting &lt;a href=&#34;http://blindtaste.com/2009/07/24/the-problem-with-fetishizing-pork-jowl/&#34;&gt;article discussing authenticity in the Italian kitchen&lt;/a&gt;. Serves well (pun intended) as an apropos to the very same discussion on tango.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buon appetito!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sabor a tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/12/sabor-a-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2009 20:22:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/12/sabor-a-tango/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/simba_tango/3192178602/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3525/3192178602_b05990b3b2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Tango fruit by Simba tango, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/simba_tango/&#34;&gt; Simba tango&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is common to say that we taste four diffent tastes: sweet, salt, bitter and sour. Combinations of these make up all other tastes. Sounds familiar? You may be guessing what I&amp;rsquo;m getting at&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The experience of taste, or should I say the experience of a meal, which we humans make for the pure pleasure of enjoying the different tastes and combinations, consists of &lt;strong&gt;a lot more&lt;/strong&gt; than these four basic tastes (some also include umami, but that&amp;rsquo;s not the point).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the four basic tastes, the &lt;strong&gt;consistency&lt;/strong&gt; of what we eat obviously makes quite a difference, porridge and beef are quite different in this respect, spaghetti needs to be &lt;em&gt;al dente&lt;/em&gt;. Whether it is hot or cold,  hard or soft, wet or dry&amp;hellip; The list goes on and on. We also have &lt;strong&gt;pain&lt;/strong&gt; receptors in the mouth, which respond to things like chili, adding the spicy sting that the Argentines do not seem to enjoy very much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;smell&lt;/strong&gt;s are also very important. This is a point frequently made by the wine connoisseurs, much of what we consider taste, is actually smell, try to enjoy a nice vintage while your nose is blocked by a cold&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presentation&lt;/strong&gt;, or the visual aspect of food also makes quite a difference. No surprise that the finest cuisines make a lot of effort in presenting their food as delicately and elegantly as possible, balancing colour, volumes and textures for the best possible visual experience in addition to the tastes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the &lt;strong&gt;ambience&lt;/strong&gt; or context of the meal also adds a lot (or reduces, depending on the circumstances). Sitting alone in a nice restaurant does not create the same feelings for the food as sharing it with good friends in a nice environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You probably guessed already, the same goes for tango. What makes up a good dance, or a good night depends on a lot of factors, and we need to add some spice to the dance to keep it interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t dance all porridge, add some spice to your dance. And make sure to savor &lt;strong&gt;everything it has to offer&lt;/strong&gt;. Why not explore some new flavours the next time you go out dancing?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>