<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Twitter on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/tags/twitter/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Twitter on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/tags/twitter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Technological advances in tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/10/technological-advances-in-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2009 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/10/technological-advances-in-tango/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/carrotcreative/2511539541/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2039/2511539541_b8c0356486.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Twitter Pack  by carrotcreative, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/carrotcreative/&#34;&gt; carrotcreative&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to say I feel a bit like an oldie, writing this, but I am kind of old-school when it comes to tango, so I guess that&amp;rsquo;s ok..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t help but notice how many things have changed since I first started with tango. Not the dance itself, but things around it. Technological changes that the newcomers in tango seem to take for granted, were simply not available only a few years back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;comme-il-faut&#34;&gt;Comme il faut&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sexy and life threatening stilettos of comme il faut did not exist when my tango career started. I think they started around 2003, at least that&amp;rsquo;s when I first heard about them. Definitely not by 2001. And surprisingly, noone has been able to copy their formula just yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One (post Comme il faut) tango friend commented on La Princesa&amp;rsquo;s (pre Comme il faut) shoes and thought it &amp;lsquo;impossible&amp;rsquo; to dance with such clunky, heavy shoes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before they were comme il faut. Now there is Comme il faut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;online-music&#34;&gt;Online music&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, it is not quite there, both Rhapsody and Napster (the legal one) have very limited tango catalogues, and I believe the same to be the case with Spotify. I have a large collection already, but for beginners, I presume it can be very useful. It took time and effort and money to get something remiscent of a tango collection, the first step is now much easier, and lots of music is available at tangostore.com and amazon.com as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before they would give you Piazzolla. Now you can get Racciatti.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;youtube&#34;&gt;YouTube&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An old VHS that some friends had copied from another friend, taped from Solo tango was all we had. Watching old shows at their place. Then we ordered vastly overpriced dvds from CITA once a year for some years. The last time I ordered the dvd, I was talking with the friends with the VHS about how I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really thrilled by the latest CITA dvd. I realized it was because I preferred watching my favorite dancers (not on CITA) at youtube. For free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you had to ask: how is their dancing? Now you can check it out yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;social-networking&#34;&gt;Social networking&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So many of my tango friends and aquaintances are now on facebook, I think it will be much easier to get into the flow the next time in Buenos Aires. Before, one would have to track down the latest &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eltangauta.com&#34;&gt;Tangauta&lt;/a&gt; to know what was going on. Today it is all online, available even before you leave home. It will be interesting to see if twitter will have any use in tango, I can see it as a means of coordination, but facebook seems like a stronger contestant at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you would hope some friends showed up. Now you can follow them on your favorite social networking site. Who are you on twitter?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>