<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Argentine Culture on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>https://simbatango.github.io/categories/argentine-culture/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Argentine Culture on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="https://simbatango.github.io/categories/argentine-culture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Dancing to the music of time</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2016/01/29/dancing-to-the-music-of-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 19:02:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2016/01/29/dancing-to-the-music-of-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.intelligentlifemagazine.com/sites/default/files/0116IL_PL_WIN_04-web.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;But among so many lessons, with so many teachers, I find contradictions and clichés. My feet are shovels; my feet are paintbrushes. My feet must caress the floor, intensely; my feet are too firm against the floorboards. My embrace must be close, like the embrace of a lover; my embrace must leave space for the tension between us. I am a cat, I am a lion, I am a horse-rider. Carina tells me I need to work on my ochos. “There is no such thing as an ocho,” says Oscar Casas, at our next lesson. There is only a change in direction, that’s all.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.intelligentlifemagazine.com/places/dancing-to-the-music-of-time&#34;&gt;refreshingly unclichéd take on dancing tango in Buenos Aires&lt;/a&gt;. (In Argentina, tango is a way of life, as Tara Isabella Burton discovered when she went to Buenos Aires, following in her grandmother’s footsteps, from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.intelligentlifemagazine.com/places/dancing-to-the-music-of-time&#34;&gt;Intelligent Life Magazine&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carlos Di Sarli Documentary</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2013/03/30/carlos-di-sarli-documentary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 08:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2013/03/30/carlos-di-sarli-documentary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/DiSarli.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/DiSarli.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DiSarli&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Realidad Bonaerense, there is a new &lt;a href=&#34;http://realidadbonaerense.blogspot.no/2013/03/se-estrena-el-film-carlos-di-sarli-el.html&#34;&gt;documentary about Carlos di Sarli&lt;/a&gt; coming out, directed by Alberto Freinquel. No information about dvd or download edition, but there will be several public viewings in Buenos Aires and in Bahía Blanca, I think. The article mentions several dramatized sequences, which makes me a bit sceptical, but I guess you have to do something if there is little historical material available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EDIT: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.enterateantes.com.ar/merecida-reparacion-historica-a-carlos-di-sarli/&#34;&gt;A bit more information here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baroque Zamba</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2011/04/11/baroque-zamba/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2011 20:59:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2011/04/11/baroque-zamba/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/romero-cover-detail.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/romero-cover-detail.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Going to Argentina for the tango, you end up falling in love with other things Argentine as well. One of these things is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zamba&#34;&gt;Zamba&lt;/a&gt;, not to be confused with its Brazilian &lt;del&gt;homonym&lt;/del&gt; homophone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine the surprised look on Simba&amp;rsquo;s face listening to a radio show reviewing some new &amp;lsquo;classical&amp;rsquo; releases. Suddenly they play an  Argentine Zamba, or at least something very similar. The cd in question was the new release from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.clematis-ensemble.be/en/records.php?ID_cat=112&#34;&gt;Clematis Ensemble&lt;/a&gt; with music by composer &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mateo_Romero_(composer)&#34;&gt;Mateo Romero&lt;/a&gt;. It was actually announced as an Argentine Zamba, which I found hard to believe as I thought that was a much later music form, but that was what they said. Anyway, it was beautiful music, all of it, and fortunately already &lt;a href=&#34;http://open.spotify.com/album/6AEgnmfHfTsdsJWiJDK7ez&#34;&gt;available at Spotify&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wondered if the Zamba actually came from the Native Americans, but a little wikipedia research and getting my hands on the leaflet cleared the apparent contradiction. As I originally thought the Zamba is much more recent, but the recording was based on what is supposedly the earliest transcribed piece with the rhythm that is used in Zamba. They probably play it a lot more like the contemporary Zamba tradition, though. Nevertheless, beautiful music, great musicality and highly recommended. If you like early baroque music, that is.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jorge Luis Borges</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2010/11/13/jorge-luis-borges/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2010 15:52:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2010/11/13/jorge-luis-borges/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[](&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wired.com/underwire/2009/12/hey-oscar-wilde/9/)[![](http://www.wired.com/images_blogs/underwire/2009/12/sci_fi_authors_9a.jpg)](http://www.wired.com/underwire/2009/12/hey-oscar-wilde/9/&#34;&gt;http://www.wired.com/underwire/2009/12/hey-oscar-wilde/9/)[![](http://www.wired.com/images_blogs/underwire/2009/12/sci_fi_authors_9a.jpg)](http://www.wired.com/underwire/2009/12/hey-oscar-wilde/9/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jorge_Luis_Borges&#34;&gt;Jorge Luis Borges&lt;/a&gt; is mainly the man to blame for perpetuating the myth that tango was born in the brothels. Which is amazing, since he was &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.todotango.com/english/biblioteca/cronicas/jlborges.html&#34;&gt;not much if anything of a tanguero&lt;/a&gt;. He was Argentine, though, and easily the best known Argentine author.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, my first encounter with Argentine culture was when I read an anthology of his short stories in high school. They were quite interesting, often playing mind games, exploring absurtities like a library of all combinations of letters, which would imply that it contain all texts already written, as well as those still unimagined. And a guy that never forgets anything. Anything. Really. That&amp;rsquo;s how I remember Borges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also remember him in the incarnation of a fictional character in the novel&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Name_of_the_Rose&#34;&gt; The Name of the Rose&lt;/a&gt; by Umberto Eco. A blind librarian in a maze of a library. Very appropriate, and my friend that introduced me to Borges got a nice card from me when I somehow ended up living in the street  &lt;a href=&#34;https://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;amp;source=s_q&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;geocode=&amp;amp;q=jorge+luis+borges,+buenos+aires&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;hq=&amp;amp;hnear=Jorge+Luis+Borges,+Palermo,+Ciudad+Aut%C3%B3noma+de+Buenos+Aires,+Argentina&amp;amp;z=16&#34;&gt;Jorge Luis Borges in Palermo&lt;/a&gt; once, not far from where he was born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact I quite would like to read Borges in the original tongue, and I was tempted by nice and relatively cheap editions of his collected works in Buenos Aires bookstores on several occasions. It always ended up pure wishful thinking, though, as there was never  any room in the suitcase, all filled up with shoes, cds, yerba and dulce de leche.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently Borges was bitter that he never received the Nobel price for literature, and when the prize for 2010 was awarded Mario Vargas Llosa, I learnt the reason why he never got it. The reason was not literary, rather it was political, probably because at one point he accepted an honor from the Chilean dictator Augusto Pinochet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest I was mostly looking for an excuse to use this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wired.com/underwire/2009/12/hey-oscar-wilde/9/&#34;&gt;awesome drawing by Cameron Stewart&lt;/a&gt; as an illustration for a post. And since it is unlikely I will find even a remote  a good connection with tango for Pablo Picasso, just check out this &lt;a href=&#34;http://opinionator.blogs.nytimes.com/2010/11/11/drawing-funny/&#34;&gt;nice drawing by Tom Bachtell&lt;/a&gt;. Picasso cannot be blamed for anything when it comes to tango, as far as I know.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fresh Supplies</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2010/10/15/fresh-supplies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 19:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2010/10/15/fresh-supplies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/simba_tango/5083604459/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4085/5083604459_bf0455e6c6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mate &amp;amp; Dulce de leche by Simba tango, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-sa/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/simba_tango/&#34;&gt; Simba tango&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A box of goodies was waiting for me when I got back from work this afternoon: Cruz de Malta, Rosamonte mate&amp;hellip;. and Salamandra Dulce de Leche..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up buying from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mate-tee.de/&#34;&gt;mate-tee.de&lt;/a&gt;, it just took a few days, and the price all included was somewhere around 1o-12 dollars a kg. Which is a lot more reasonable than going on buying the &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2010/09/19/the-worlds-most-expensive-yerba/&#34;&gt;world&amp;rsquo;s most expensive yerba&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now off to dance, and when the little guy wakes me up at 5 AM, there is freshly brewed mate comforting his father. And dulce de leeeeeche.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The World&#39;s Most Expensive Yerba?</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2010/09/19/the-worlds-most-expensive-yerba/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2010 21:03:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2010/09/19/the-worlds-most-expensive-yerba/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/benpender/224168170/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/85/224168170_37549c4206.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Yerba Mate by Benjamin Pender, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/benpender/&#34;&gt; Benjamin Pender&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We always bring&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yerba_mat%C3%A9&#34;&gt; yerba mate&lt;/a&gt; back from Buenos Aires. It has become another habit as a biproduct of the passion for tango. Everywhere you will see porteños with their little thermoses and the cup with a metal straw, the bombilla, sipping away. In the queue, in the park, on the bus, in tango classes etc etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway &amp;mdash; we ran out of the stuff after a couple of months after our return, and went to the specialist tea and coffee store in town. And got what must be the most expensive yerba mate the earth has ever seen. In Buenos Aires, it is really cheap, and often associated with lower social classes, somewhere between fifty cent and a dollar a package (500g). The supermarkets got millions of brands, and everybody got their favorite yerba. In out tea store they got one kind. And 500g cost about $20. And it didn&amp;rsquo;t really taste that good, no idea what brand it is. I should go there and ask if they know how it is used, it is priced the same as black/green tea, of which one uses but a small fraction of  the amount for each serving compared with the preparation of  a mate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we&amp;rsquo;re not planning on going back soon, the solution will have to be found on the internet. Not as cheap as in the supermercado, of course, but more reasonable priced. Anyone got a tip for a good store that ships to Europe and carries Cruz de Malta and Rosamonte?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning the Language of Tango</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2010/06/27/learning-the-language-of-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2010 17:30:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2010/06/27/learning-the-language-of-tango/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/simba_tango/4735758259/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4081/4735758259_6f8ae59c6a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;El tango by Simba tango, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-sa/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/simba_tango/&#34;&gt; Simba tango&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t know the language of tango, you&amp;rsquo;ll miss out on a lot, and for once, I don&amp;rsquo;t mean in a metaphorical sense. One anecdote I remember from my early days of tango was being told of a workshop that started with the following announcement:  &amp;rdquo;This is an advanced class, hence it will be taught in Spanish&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;m not sure who it supposedly was that said it, but I have a similar experience with Gustavo Naveira teaching in Buenos Aires with lots of foreigners present: &amp;ndash;Is there anyone here that speaks absolutely no Spanish? (lots of hands in the air) No Spanish at all? (fewer, but still quite a few hands in the air) Then he would go on teaching in Spanish with a few very short, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0335266/&#34;&gt;Lost in translation&lt;/a&gt;-style summaries in English every now and then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is that learning a little Spanish has been of tremendous value in the process of learning the tango. And with one noteable exception, all our main teachers the last few years have been Spanish only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember our first trip to Buenos Aires, taking classes where the instruction sounded more or less like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Blah blah blah blah blah **atras**, blah blah blah blah, **adelante **blah blah blah blah **ocho** blah blah blah....&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As time went by, the number of words we picked up grew, but atras (backwards) and adelante (forwards) and ocho were ones that stood out from the beginning. Fast forward to today, and my Spanish (well Catalan, really) colleague introduces me to a fellow Spanish guy as &amp;ldquo;the guy that speaks &lt;em&gt;Argentine&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;. A bit of an exaggeration, but still, we&amp;rsquo;ve come a long way, and it really helps connecting with people when you go there, even if they actually speak English themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some Argentines insist they speak Castellano, not Español (Spanish), this is also a lesson from our very first trip, and we generally stuck to using the word castellano, as that seemed to insult or irritate noone, and made sure we knew they were no longer a Spanish colony :-) . Anquises &lt;a href=&#34;http://zigurat-anquises.blogspot.com/2009/08/espanol-o-castellano.html&#34;&gt;argues that Español is the more correct term&lt;/a&gt;, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the process of improving one&amp;rsquo;s understanding of a language, a good dictionary is priceless. I already got the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Diccionario-Lunfardo-Spanish-Athos-Espindola/dp/9504909833&#34;&gt;dictionary of Lunfardo&lt;/a&gt;, a regular Spanish dictionary, what I was searching for was an &lt;em&gt;Argentine&lt;/em&gt; dictionary, but that turned out to be uavailable even in one of the great bookstores in Buenos Aires, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/El_Ateneo&#34;&gt;El Ateneo&lt;/a&gt;. The guy in the bookstore told us they used the Spanish ones in school and everywhere else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the Spanish dictionary will take you a long way, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t cover all the local usage. This was clearly demonstrated once as we went to the local pharmacy after looking up what we wanted in the dictionary, only to have them rolling over the counter laughing when we tried to put our newfound knowledge to work. What saved us was a little improvised acting combined with key Spanish words which finally revealed the term used in Argentina. A little body language trumps everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also there are a lot of slang expressions, and we found the slang dictionary &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Puto-El-Que-Lee-Spanish/dp/9872281203/&#34;&gt;Puto el que lee&lt;/a&gt; (diccionario argentino de insultos, injurias e improperios) in a bookstore, and found it would fill in nicely. The Argentines have an astounding number of names for prostitutes and both female and male genetalia, which all come in handy when you want to insult someone or just talk to your friends in a playful manner (¡Che, boludo!). It also has a hilarious appendix with a few tables letting you construct your own insults very easily as well as illustrations, for example covering &amp;lsquo;Grandes hijos de puta del Mundo&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;Grandísimos hijos de puta del Mundo&amp;rsquo; and correspondingly for Argentina. Unfortunately, I&amp;rsquo;m not enough into Argentine politics to get all the Argentines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, one of the last days of our last stay, we started chatting about this with our great host, and he suggested we got the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Diccionario-del-Habla-Argentinos-Spanish/dp/9500430282/&#34;&gt;Diccionario del habla de los Argentinos&lt;/a&gt;. At last. This relatively recent publication actually passed our little test of words we learnt from some of our porteño friends, and we could look them all up in the dictionary. It was too late to buy it in Buenos Aires, but we ordered it  from Argentina via Amazon. Amazing that you can actually get all of these books on Amazon! A bit more expensive, but it comes with this fuzzy feeling inside when there is mail from Argentina in the mailbox :-) The illustration photo is from this dictionary.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Champagne tango</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/12/31/champagne-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2009 19:11:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/12/31/champagne-tango/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/simba_tango/4203564990/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2674/4203564990_e17ca23de2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Chandon bottles by Simba tango, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-sa/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/simba_tango/&#34;&gt; Simba tango&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Argentines have this thing about champagne. Not usually the real thing, but their own version. Which is actually quite good, and of course much cheaper. Going shopping in our closest super market makes this very clear, they have coolers, a fridge with pre cooled &amp;lsquo;champan&amp;rsquo; (as they like to call it), rows and rows of different brands and special promotions: Buy this and that and get half a bottle for free!. And what&amp;rsquo;s more, they have four-packs of quarter bottle. Amusing, and very tempting :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever we go out with friends, it is so nice to get a bottle of champan for the entire table, it lifts the spirit very effectively. A couple of times we have taken people from our community out to milongas here in Buenos Aires, and when the bottle of champan arrives, it is always an instant success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[flickr-gallery mode=&amp;ldquo;photoset&amp;rdquo; photoset=&amp;ldquo;72157622918739415&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cachafaz alfajores</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/12/23/cachafaz-alfajores/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2009 02:17:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/12/23/cachafaz-alfajores/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/12/cachafaz.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/12/cachafaz.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you ever get the alfajores of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.havanna.com.ar/&#34;&gt;Havanna&lt;/a&gt; in Buenos Aires recommended? And they did not live up to your expectations? Well, maybe I can tell you why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, an &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alfajor&#34;&gt;alfajor&lt;/a&gt; is a sort of biscuit or cookie, normally two layers with &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dulce_de_leche&#34;&gt;dulce de leche&lt;/a&gt; in between. They exist in different varieties, the main ones are the ones covered with chocolate, and the ones of maizena (of which I prefer the latter).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, the first time we saw the Cachafaz brand, we thought it was amusing because of the famous dancer that was called &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.todotango.com/Spanish/creadores/cachafaz.html&#34;&gt;El Cachafaz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, and we tried it out. It was delicious. Note that it may take some time getting used to these super dulce delicacies of Argentina. But like with the tango, it is worth the extra time spent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interesting turn came when a friend, a porteña, was visiting, and noticed a box of cachafaz alfajores (and conitos) on top of the fridge. She told us that the Havanna alfajores (that are sort of famous) used to taste so much better, until Havanna was sold to new owners about ten-fifteen years ago. The new owners changed the recipe, and the alfajores were never the same again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until Cachafaz entered the scene. According to our friend, some of the original owners of Havanna started Cachafaz, using the original recipe of Havanna. Including the maizena variety, which Havanna no longer sells. Needless to say, she agreed that they were delicious, and we had one conito each after our late dinner. Mmmmm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS: I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find much information at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://cachafaz.com&#34;&gt;cachafaz&lt;/a&gt; website, but &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.quelapaseslindo.com.ar/2009/07/03/havanna-vs-el-cachafaz-el-referendum/&#34;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; seems to be consistent with our friend&amp;rsquo;s story.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Luna de Avellaneda</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/05/03/luna-de-avellaneda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2009 13:05:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/05/03/luna-de-avellaneda/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;ldquo;&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;460&amp;rdquo; caption=&amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;Castillo&amp;rdquo; singing at club &amp;ldquo;Luna de Avellaneda&amp;rdquo;&amp;ldquo;]&lt;img src=&#34;http://image.guardian.co.uk/sys-images/Film/Pix/pictures/2007/03/07/LunaDeAvellaneda460.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Castillo singing at club Luna de Avellaneda&#34; /&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/04/19/tango-film-club/&#34;&gt;tango films&lt;/a&gt;, there are several films where tango is not a main theme, but with some interesting tango scenes. The film &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0347449/&#34;&gt;Luna de Avellaneda&lt;/a&gt; is quite nice, and stands out in that respect. For tango lovers, the opening scene is not to be missed, as it reconstructs the grand party of a community milonga in the golden age of tango. With music, dancing and &amp;ndash; well it looks like one h*** of a party!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2008/10/09/old-tango-hero/&#34;&gt;Alberto Castillo&lt;/a&gt; is singing at the club the night the main character of the movie is born, and the place of the dance hall reminded me a lot of Sunderland in Villa Urquiza. I often wonder what it was like, going out dancing in Buenos Aires in the 40s, and this scene attempts to show us how it was. With a little extra drama thrown in for effect of course..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main theme of the film is how the community and its members struggle during the economic crisis after &lt;sup&gt;2001&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2002&lt;/sub&gt;, somehow using the club as a metaphor for the Argentinian community at large. The film may add some perspective both to the economic conditions in Argentina, and to the perpetual struggle to build and maintain a community in spite of forces working against it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I enjoyed the rest of the film as well, the opening scene is what I will always remember. It is brilliant. The great singers and orchestras were clearly stars, and here it really shows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The enjoyment of the rest of the film was reduced on my part because I didn&amp;rsquo;t pay attention when I ordered the dvd, and got one without subtitles, and the subtitles I was able to find on the web were not synchronized. But that was all my fault, not a fault of the film itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is amusing to see how many of the argentine films I&amp;rsquo;ve seen that star &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0201857/&#34;&gt;Ricardo Darín&lt;/a&gt;. He is a good actor, and must be all over the place. If you would like to watch some other Argentine films (not related to tango), I can wholeheartedly recommend &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0247586/&#34;&gt;Nueve reinas&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0420509/&#34;&gt;El aura&lt;/a&gt;. Luna de Avellaneda is part of a trilogy, and I will try to find an opportunity to see the other two at some point as well, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0292542/&#34;&gt;Hijo de la novia&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0210843/&#34;&gt;El mismo amor, la misma lluvia&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mateando</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/04/06/mateando/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2009 23:19:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/04/06/mateando/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/simba_tango/3415436068/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3600/3415436068_cd1c5dcafb.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mate by Simba tango, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/simba_tango/&#34;&gt; Simba tango&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First things first. Got to get the essensials in place. Like espresso cups and what&amp;rsquo;s needed for preparing mate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And &amp;ndash; apparently, &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.wired.com/business/2009/04/tech-millionair.html&#34;&gt;tea is the new coffee&lt;/a&gt;. But I think they forgot to count mate, both the new tea **and **coffee ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Super super dulce...</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/02/24/super-super-dulce.../</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2009 20:24:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/02/24/super-super-dulce.../</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VFx02G3kg9E&#34;&gt;httpv://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VFx02G3kg9E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Argentines are crazy about sweets, and so will you be after staying there for a while. Take care, the alfajores de Havanna are dangerously good. The cones are for the conoisseurs&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QT6JHS5lgQM&#34;&gt;httpv://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QT6JHS5lgQM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while you are relaxing before going out for the milongas, they got a tv show just for making sweets and desserts, called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wrighton.com.ar/?p=478&#34;&gt;super dulce&lt;/a&gt;. I did not find it on youtube, the theme song is hilarious, and you can find a short sample on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.utilisima.com/videos/tv-cocina/super-dulce/&#34;&gt;super dulce home page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>