<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dancing For The Woman on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>https://simbatango.github.io/tags/dancing-for-the-woman/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dancing For The Woman on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="https://simbatango.github.io/tags/dancing-for-the-woman/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Pas de finesse...</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2008/12/19/pas-de-finesse.../</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2008 12:55:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2008/12/19/pas-de-finesse.../</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jayanthsharma/501996653/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/202/501996653_a49cf868cc.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;There’s no charge to get charged by Jayanth Sharma, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/jayanthsharma/&#34;&gt; Jayanth Sharma&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Staying in Buenos Aires for a few months provided several eye-openers. One of the great revelations was concerning the logic of the dance, or rather the lack of it, and how this adds spice to the dance:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were taking lessons with various teachers, with very different philosophies with respect to tango, how to dance it and how to learn it. Gustavo Naveira, the great master, dissected each step carefully, explaining exactly how and why and which steps were crossed and which were open etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming then to another lesson with the quite different teachers, I asked once why I was to go with this foot, and not with the other, as I could not make any sense of this particular combination. Jorge looked at me, as if he did not understand the question. Why? Because the step is like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only later did it make any sense to me. It was actually when los Disparis showed another step. A step where the man deliberately hides which foot he has weight on. To make it less obvious which direction the turn will be.  Going in the not so logical direction. Or perhaps not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding a touch of finesse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember several years earlier, another tango teacher told us that the man should always have a little surprise for the woman, a sorpresita, to make her feel she was something special. And in the same way, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t hurt having a sorpresita for the spectators as well. At least if you are giving a show, that is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this leads to one reason I find a lot of performances unbearably boring. The dancers do a lot of things, trying to be innovative. But it shows a mile a head where they are going. No sorpresita. Lacking even the slightest hint of finesse.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clichés</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2008/07/06/clich%C3%A9s/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2008 10:31:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2008/07/06/clich%C3%A9s/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever since I started dancing, the topic of tango clichés has fascinated me. The rose in mouth, castanets, head flicks, dramatic poses are all parts of what usually pops into people&amp;rsquo;s heads when they hear the word tango. Where did they come from, and why did they stick? Going through a lot of Hollywood production at least gives a partial answer, and Rudolph Valentino is one of the people to blame, the rose in mouth appears in the film &lt;em&gt;Blood and sand&lt;/em&gt;, where he plays a bullfighter, while the film he dances the tango is _Four horsemen of the apocalypse. _The tango in &lt;em&gt;Some like it hot&lt;/em&gt; must have reinforced the image further into the public memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what lies behind the clichés, do they reveal something of interest, which we may overlook, just because the cliché is so easily dismissed? Could the tango have more important influence from the flamenco than is commonly acknowledged? The rose at least played a role in the real tango porteño in the way that the orchestra of Pugliese used a single rose on the piano during their performances to mark the maestro&amp;rsquo;s absence while he was held in prison for his political beliefs. The head flicks seem to come from the ballroom version of tango, and to my knowledge they have little relation to the &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; tango. Many of the dramatic poses, though, could have their roots in early tango moves such as cortes and quebradas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/images/pugliese_ausencia.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Osvaldo Pugliese in absentia&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, many sayings about tango, are often dismissed as being &lt;em&gt;merely clichés&lt;/em&gt;, but I have found that many of them go deeper than we first think. That tango is really about dancing for the woman is one such statement. Often heard, rarely seen outside Buenos Aires, is my experience. Even by those who say it.  I heard women talk about this for years, &lt;em&gt;X dances for himself&lt;/em&gt; etc. It took me many years before I started noticing what they were &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; talking about. But when I finally realized, it transformed my way of seeing tango, both my own and others&amp;rsquo;. It may appear superficial, a subtle adjustment, a cliché. In fact, what is needed is a fundamental change. Starting to dance for the woman, rather for one self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now read those &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/index.php/2008/06/01/gavito-dixit/&#34;&gt;Gavito quotes&lt;/a&gt; again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>