<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Metaphor on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>https://simbatango.github.io/categories/metaphor/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Metaphor on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="https://simbatango.github.io/categories/metaphor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Quality and snobs</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/09/05/quality-and-snobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2009 02:30:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/09/05/quality-and-snobs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/96dpi/1139662917/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1213/1139662917_7b4b1bab22.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Swing by 96dpi, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/96dpi/&#34;&gt; 96dpi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tangocommuter1.blogspot.com/2009/08/tango-al-fresco-was-its-usual-amiable.html&#34;&gt;Food&lt;/a&gt; (and &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/04/26/stuff-without-the-stuff/&#34;&gt;drinks&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;a href=&#34;http://mshedgehog.blogspot.com/2009/08/egg-and-chips-pugliese.html&#34;&gt;metaphor&lt;/a&gt;s for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.limericktango.com/2009/08/nigell-lawson-on-henry-james/&#34;&gt;tango&lt;/a&gt; seem to be popular lately, so here in another one: My brother and I have two very distinct wine quality stories that I find very amusing when seen together. Each involves a young woman, at the age where going to parties and flirting with alcohol is at its most exciting, somewhere just before or just after going to university.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#1: A rather simple red wine was served with the main dish at a dinner party with the entire class of that year. She tasted it, called for the waiter and asked for another bottle. &amp;ndash;This I cannot drink. Only thing was, there was nothing wrong with the wine. Except that is was cheap. And the new bottle of the same, cheap wine was no better, of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#2: At a party in the place of a friend&amp;rsquo;s parents, she opened the bottle, poured into a glass and tasted. Then she walked right over to the sink and &amp;ndash; to the astonished looks from her friends &amp;ndash; emptied the entire bottle into the sink.  &amp;ndash;This I cannot drink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How this applies to tango is left as an exercise to the reader&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eating the marshmellow</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/05/27/eating-the-marshmellow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 23:41:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/05/27/eating-the-marshmellow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/supa_muffin/2853407584/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/05/marshmellow.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;marshmellow&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/supa_muffin/&#34;&gt; Sarah Marafi  (мυƒƒιησσн™)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just read a very interesting article in the New Yorker about research on people&amp;rsquo;s ability to deter satisfaction, and how it could be a character treat determined very early. The researchers performed an experiment where children were given the choice of eating a marshmellow now, or wait fifteen minutes, waiting in front of the marshmellows, and get two marshmellows. Some kids were able to find ways of distracting themselves, earning the extra marshmellow in the end. Others just couldn&amp;rsquo;t wait and had it right there and then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This experiment was performed quite some time ago, and the researchers are now performing new experiments with the same subjects, now grown-ups, and find correlation with their success in life. Career-wise, that is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all corresponds nicely with microeconomic theory: Delay some consumption and invest, in order to get something more to consume later. The right thing to do. Rational and wise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But to some of us, waiting was never the problem. The problem is living right here and now. Seizing the day. And some of us learn about that through tango. Tango, or more precisely going to the milongas, is about eating the marshmellow. Savouring the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And some times, the right thing is to eat the marshmellow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Color -- like no other</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/02/26/color----like-no-other/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2009 21:32:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/02/26/color----like-no-other/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/eqi2vK_i3IE&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The world is not black and white, there are grays in between&amp;hellip; it is often said when some take a clear position in a debate. And they do have a point of course. But they also sometimes miss the point entirely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tango is not gray, it is full of colour! You just have to open your eyes and take them in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am thinking of the &amp;ldquo;nuevo&amp;rdquo; versus &amp;ldquo;traditional&amp;rdquo; debate, of course. I sometimes wonder if it is not rather a distinction between seeing tango as culture or tango as movement that distinguishes the &amp;ldquo;purists/traditionalists&amp;rdquo; from the &amp;ldquo;nuevo&amp;rdquo; crowd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open your eyes to the richness of tango culture, and you will see it is not a matter of black or white, but of lots of colors. Some brilliand and stark, others soft and subtle. Some murkey and others ugly and dim. And yes &amp;ndash; I do prefer some colours and combinations to others.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empty movement</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/02/04/empty-movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2009 20:43:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/02/04/empty-movement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/bass_nroll/2397838219/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2043/2397838219_d126f3b0c9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;[empty] by bass_nroll, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/bass_nroll/&#34;&gt; bass_nroll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you probably know, tango is not merely a dance. Among other things, the dance is also a language. It is not like a language, because the different movements have different meanings, which can be used for actual communication. It is not a metaphor. However, when people copy movements without realizing the underlying meaning, &lt;a href=&#34;http://lonewalker.blog.co.uk/2009/01/25/midsummer-nights-tango-part-5441668/&#34;&gt;the result is movements with no meaning&lt;/a&gt;. Empty movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or even worse, you may be saying something without knowing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is somehow like writing calligraphy for decoration only, selecting the &amp;ldquo;nice letters&amp;rdquo;, not knowing the meaning of what you are writing. How about a tattoo reading &amp;ldquo;A fool and his money are easily parted&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Prostitute&amp;rdquo; in Chinese? Don&amp;rsquo;t laugh, it recently happened that a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.independent.co.uk/arts-entertainment/tv/news/chinese-classical-poem-was-brothel-ad-1058031.html&#34;&gt;science journal used an ad for a brothel to decorate the front page&lt;/a&gt; of a special issue on China. They thought the letters &amp;ldquo;looked nice&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So be careful with your tango, remember its mythical origin&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sabor a tango</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/01/12/sabor-a-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2009 20:22:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/01/12/sabor-a-tango/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/simba_tango/3192178602/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3525/3192178602_b05990b3b2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Tango fruit by Simba tango, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/simba_tango/&#34;&gt; Simba tango&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is common to say that we taste four diffent tastes: sweet, salt, bitter and sour. Combinations of these make up all other tastes. Sounds familiar? You may be guessing what I&amp;rsquo;m getting at&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The experience of taste, or should I say the experience of a meal, which we humans make for the pure pleasure of enjoying the different tastes and combinations, consists of &lt;strong&gt;a lot more&lt;/strong&gt; than these four basic tastes (some also include umami, but that&amp;rsquo;s not the point).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the four basic tastes, the &lt;strong&gt;consistency&lt;/strong&gt; of what we eat obviously makes quite a difference, porridge and beef are quite different in this respect, spaghetti needs to be &lt;em&gt;al dente&lt;/em&gt;. Whether it is hot or cold,  hard or soft, wet or dry&amp;hellip; The list goes on and on. We also have &lt;strong&gt;pain&lt;/strong&gt; receptors in the mouth, which respond to things like chili, adding the spicy sting that the Argentines do not seem to enjoy very much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;smell&lt;/strong&gt;s are also very important. This is a point frequently made by the wine connoisseurs, much of what we consider taste, is actually smell, try to enjoy a nice vintage while your nose is blocked by a cold&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presentation&lt;/strong&gt;, or the visual aspect of food also makes quite a difference. No surprise that the finest cuisines make a lot of effort in presenting their food as delicately and elegantly as possible, balancing colour, volumes and textures for the best possible visual experience in addition to the tastes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the &lt;strong&gt;ambience&lt;/strong&gt; or context of the meal also adds a lot (or reduces, depending on the circumstances). Sitting alone in a nice restaurant does not create the same feelings for the food as sharing it with good friends in a nice environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You probably guessed already, the same goes for tango. What makes up a good dance, or a good night depends on a lot of factors, and we need to add some spice to the dance to keep it interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t dance all porridge, add some spice to your dance. And make sure to savor &lt;strong&gt;everything it has to offer&lt;/strong&gt;. Why not explore some new flavours the next time you go out dancing?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Under pressure</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2008/12/06/under-pressure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2008 19:30:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2008/12/06/under-pressure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/notinponce/1845809/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/2/1845809_017008af6b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;hombre al agua! by notinponce, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/notinponce/&#34;&gt; notinponce&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comparing tango with other dances, salsa for instance, some find the other dances so much fuller of life. Sparkling. Bubbling over of life and joy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tango is rarely bubbling over. It is more self contained. Directing the energy inwards. More like boiling under pressure.  More intensity and energy, but perhaps less visible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember so well one of my first times to a festival. As usual, people were going crazy on the dance floor, using brownian motion as the guiding principle. Except one couple.  Calm and strong,  they were wading through the chaos with confidence. Making space. Taking their time. It made a strong impression. Strong indeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later the same night, they were giving a performance, of course. Ignorant me did not know about Roberto Herrera and Natacha Poberaj. A fabulous performance, sparkling and energetic, so good that few in the world would be able to match it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the dancing in the crowd left a much stronger impression.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Secret -- Don&#39;t tell anyone</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2008/11/11/the-secret----dont-tell-anyone/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2008 16:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2008/11/11/the-secret----dont-tell-anyone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/11/salt.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/11/salt.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main character is asked to prepare an omelet in the morning for his master, a Parisian intellectual. Feeling his cooking is underappreciated, he contemplates the intellectuals&amp;rsquo; missing reflection on his artistry in the kitchen. This is clearly about tango: (From Monique Truong&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Book of Salt:)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Like children, gullible and full of wonder, they always ask, &#34;What is your secret?&#34;

Do I look like a fool? I ask myself each time. Please, Madame, do not equate my lack of speech with a lack of thought. If there is a secret, Madame, I would take it with me to my unmarked grave, hide it in my bony jaw, the place my tongue would be if it had not rotted away. (...)

They all believe in a &#34;secret&#34; ingredient, a balm for their Gallic pride, a magic elixir that anyone can employ to duplicate my success. Its very existance threatens my own. (...) If there is a &#34;secret&#34;, Madame, it is this: Repetition and routine. Servitude and subservience. Beck and call.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should read the passage in context, it is too long to fit in a blog post, it is in the beginning of chapter 15.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS: Many thanks to my lovely wife for serving me the delicious omelet and sharing the secret. (The recipy is in the same chapter :-) )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://flickr.com/photos/wlodi/252462355/&#34;&gt;Photo&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;http://flickr.com/photos/wlodi/&#34;&gt;wlodi&lt;/a&gt;@flickr, &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/deed.en&#34;&gt;CC-licensed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Death in the Afternoon</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2008/10/24/death-in-the-afternoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2008 20:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2008/10/24/death-in-the-afternoon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/images/vicente-barrera.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Vicente Barrera&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, reading on very different topics can give deep insights in tango. &lt;em&gt;Death in the Afternoon&lt;/em&gt; by Ernest Hemingway is such a book. I thought of tango often when reading his treaty on bullfighting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While not being as deadly or controvertial as the bullfighting, tango is also a culture full of rituals and things you have to know to really appreciate. And it was the parts that was guiding the novice to understand the rich culture of bullfighting and its meaning that really made me think of tango.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hemingway is an excellent writer, of course, so it is impossible to summarize this extraordinary book in a blog post, and adding value even harder, but I will try to give an idea of what made me think of tango in this book:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed the descriptions of how people are initiated into a new world, and how this entering a different world takes place. Also how some find out that it is not for them. I have never seen a bullfight, but Hemingway suggests that I would learn very early whether it is something for me. As was the case for the tango, I knew very soon that tango was for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hemingway describes how the people new to bullfighting appreciate very different things of the drama than the connoisseur, as it takes a lot of knowledge and experience to appreciate the finer points of the art of bullfighting. While the beginner is more likely to appreciate the more flashy appearance with costumes, horses etc, appearing fairly early in the process. While the expert sees right through the crowd pleasing acts and appreciates a matador (literally &amp;lsquo;killer&amp;rsquo;) that is daring, brave and performs the act of killing with precision and without cowardry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ritual of the bullfight is also something intrigueing. There is never a happy ending. The bull always dies. If the matador cannot kill the bull, is injured or killed, the bull is still killed in the end. So while a bullfight can clearly be very exciting, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound like much fun. The bullfight goes straight into the core. Life and death. And it is very very real.  The matador is always in danger of great wounds or losing his life. The bull &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; dies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this reminded me how much I appreciate the rituals of the milongas. Coming, hearing the music from afar. The &lt;em&gt;cabeceo&lt;/em&gt;, the tandas, everybody on the floor moving as one&amp;hellip;  The chit-chat in between songs. Accompanying the lady back to her table. The tango ends, and the spell is broken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was very interesting to read about how the matadors use tricks to make the bull move closer and closer, until it is so close that the bullfighter gets blood on his clothes. The bullfighter controlling every move of the bull, only twisting his wrist or turning his torso ever so slightly. How different moves were invented by this and that bullfighter, and changed the world of bullfighting. How cowards pretend to be brave, only to be disclosed by the expert eye. The real masters. The great art. The bullfight is a staged tragedy of life and death. Maybe tango is a staged romance. Both very real indeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then you have the crowd pleasing tricks versus real skill. And the responsibility of the conoisseur. This strung a chord with the never ending tango debates on styles, favourite dancers, nuevo versus traditional.  Some advice from the old man. (And this indeed applies to tango as well):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt; ...there is one thing you can do and that is know what is good and what is bad, to appreciate the new but let nothing confuse your standards. You can continue to attend bullfights even when they are bad; but never applaud what is not good. You should, as a spectator, show your appreciation of the good and valuable work that is essential but not brilliant. You should appreciate the proper working and correct killing of a bull that is impossible to be brilliant with. A bullfighter will not be better than his audience very long. If they prefer tricks to sincerity they soon get the tricks. If a really good bullfighter is to come and to remain honest, sincere, without tricks and mystifications there must be a nucleus of spectators that he can play for when he comes.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highly recommended!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Putting the baby to sleep</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2008/10/14/putting-the-baby-to-sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 20:49:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2008/10/14/putting-the-baby-to-sleep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I quite recently became a father, and the poor child is exposed to a lot of tango music, naturally. (And I get out to dance less, hence the blog writing.) Before he was born, I used to talk about how we would practice walking together, he and I. Now this is how it turned out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scene: Unpatiant 12 days old boy, waiting for his mother to get ready for breast-feeding. Father to find something to entertain the child, and preferably also himself in the meantime. Time for tango. Di Sarli&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Nido Gaucho&lt;/em&gt; on the stereo, practicing the tango walk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boy seemed to enjoy the experience, I would say. Not as big eyes as with the milonga a few days earlyer (yes - really). After one tango and a half, he became more quiet. A few other songs from the same album, then the &lt;em&gt;Porteño y bailarín&lt;/em&gt; album from the start. The boy fell asleep in my arms. And I got to practice my walk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The funny thing about this, is that having a baby in your arms, getting it to sleep is a quite common metaphor for the way the woman should be held in the embrace. Soft, yet firm and secure.  I know at least El &amp;ldquo;Negro&amp;rdquo; Capello and Javier Rodríguez have used this metaphor. The thing is, I spent quite a lot of time practicing my tango embrace, but not making babies sleep. I got the idea, of course, but now I could apply the metaphor in the reverse direction, using my tango skills to get the boy to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, I fell asleep quite happily that night myself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>