<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Walk on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/categories/walk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Walk on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2010 17:51:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/categories/walk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Experiment shows: walking heel first more efficient</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/16/experiment-shows-walking-heel-first-more-efficient/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2010 17:51:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/16/experiment-shows-walking-heel-first-more-efficient/</guid>
      <description>This will not, of course, settle the agelong debate of whether to walk toe first or heel first in tango. Still, I found it interesting that there has recently been published research on the efficiency of the human walk, specifically investigating walking heel first versus walking toe first. If you are striving for the most efficient walk, their conclusion might be worth noting:
   When human subjects walked with their heels slightly elevated in a ‘low-digitigrade’[toe first] posture, COT [cost of transport] increased by 53% above that of normal plantigrade [heel first] walking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The structure of a tango, choreography and how it might improve your dancing</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/28/the-structure-of-a-tango-choreography-and-how-it-might-improve-your-dancing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2009 01:46:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/28/the-structure-of-a-tango-choreography-and-how-it-might-improve-your-dancing/</guid>
      <description>by aperte
If you prefer your naïve, pure emotional interpretation of the tango, you might not want to read this. If, on the other hand you think that knowing a little about how tango music is organized might increase the breadth or depth of your musical appreciation, then this could be for you.
Like Tangocommuter writes in the discussion of how a tango became approximately three minutes long, a prototypical tango has the structure ABA:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking on high heels</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/04/walking-on-high-heels/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2009 02:10:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/04/walking-on-high-heels/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;599&amp;rdquo; caption=&amp;ldquo;Cinderella discovers the risk involved in dancing too wildly while wearing glass shoes&amp;rdquo;][/caption]
Sure he was great, but don&#39;t forget that Ginger Rogers did everything he did, backwards... and in high heels. I had the pleasure of dancing with a woman in Buenos Aires who really knew how to operate her feet. She worked in television in her country, and was known as &amp;rsquo;the woman that knows how to walk on high heels&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to walk</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/11/learning-to-walk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2009 13:15:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/11/learning-to-walk/</guid>
      <description>by Café du Monde
After spending a lot of time relearning how to walk, and teaching others to do the same, it is refreshing to watch a (very) young man learning to walk, in fact learning basically everything.
Following him from being unable to hold his own head, through rolling around and sitting up, getting up by means of whatever furniture or grown up legs are in his proximity is fascinating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A morir</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/19/a-morir/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2009 01:24:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/19/a-morir/</guid>
      <description>by Xanboozled
   _--When a man walks nicely, the woman dies in his embrace._   --_When a man walks badly, the woman wants to die._ HT: yy</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breathtaking</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/12/breathtaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 20:04:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/12/breathtaking/</guid>
      <description>I was so excited to see how it worked out with Stella and Javier on their tour this year. And this is just soooo beautiful! My piano teacher used to tell me when I practiced the hard parts: don&amp;rsquo;t forget breathing! This left me breathless, so dear reader, unless you can keep your breath for three minutes: don&amp;rsquo;t forget breathing!
  HT: nyctango</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marathon</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/27/marathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2009 19:14:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/27/marathon/</guid>
      <description>by darkmatter
So what&amp;rsquo;s with this marathon thing that seems to be spreading across Europe? I never found anything positive about marathons, running and sweating for hours on asphalt with no break and being totally destroyed afterwards?
Of course, people may dance as they like. Myself, I prefer a nice milonga, champagne at the table, nice and clean clothes, nice and calm. Having a ball. Walking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Under pressure</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/06/under-pressure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2008 19:30:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/06/under-pressure/</guid>
      <description>by notinponce
Comparing tango with other dances, salsa for instance, some find the other dances so much fuller of life. Sparkling. Bubbling over of life and joy.
Tango is rarely bubbling over. It is more self contained. Directing the energy inwards. More like boiling under pressure. More intensity and energy, but perhaps less visible.
I remember so well one of my first times to a festival. As usual, people were going crazy on the dance floor, using brownian motion as the guiding principle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost there</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/21/almost-there/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2008 12:03:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/21/almost-there/</guid>
      <description>by patsun They say it takes 10 years learning to walk&amp;hellip; Almost there ;-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waiting for the right moment</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/18/waiting-for-the-right-moment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2008 17:57:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/18/waiting-for-the-right-moment/</guid>
      <description>by just.Luc
   -I see a lot of men are not dancing. They can&#39;t manage to dance when the floor is so full of people.     -It may not be because of lack of ability. It may be because they enjoy the dance more when the floor is not packed and they can more around the floor in their dance. Maybe they are waiting for their favorite music.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Secret -- Don&#39;t tell anyone</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/11/the-secret-dont-tell-anyone/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2008 16:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/11/the-secret-dont-tell-anyone/</guid>
      <description>The main character is asked to prepare an omelet in the morning for his master, a Parisian intellectual. Feeling his cooking is underappreciated, he contemplates the intellectuals&amp;rsquo; missing reflection on his artistry in the kitchen. This is clearly about tango: (From Monique Truong&amp;rsquo;s The Book of Salt:)
Like children, gullible and full of wonder, they always ask, &#34;What is your secret?&#34; Do I look like a fool? I ask myself each time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salón Canning</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/06/salon-canning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2008 23:08:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/06/salon-canning/</guid>
      <description>I realize that the guys at Movement invites movement are not afraid of provocation, but I think they suffer a tiny bit from a syndrome often associated with Gringos, shooting from the waist.
In their rant abot Canning, they fail to recognize a few important reasons Canning has such an important position. Aside from being one of the very best floors in the city (maybe the very best), it attracts many excellent dancers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the eye of the beholder</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/06/in-the-eye-of-the-beholder/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2008 17:31:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/06/in-the-eye-of-the-beholder/</guid>
      <description>Isn&amp;rsquo;t it funny how we see so different things, even when watching the exact same event?

I remember seeing containers all over the place while we were renovating our appartment, a friend who is an architect and carpenter seemed to literally see through the walls in the house before we bought it. A trained art expert will instantly recognize the work of an artist, an analyst will see through the endless rows of numbers in a spreadsheet&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Masquerade</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/31/masquerade/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2008 21:07:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/31/masquerade/</guid>
      <description>Who are you when you are dancing? Are you the leader? The follower? The man? The woman? I was once confronted with my using the terminology man/woman in class. The person complaining said that she was dancing a role (she was dancing the man&amp;rsquo;s part) and that was the role of the leader.
I know this easily gets messy, but I never liked the euphemism leader/follower when what we are talking about is a man and a woman in most cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Putting the baby to sleep</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/14/putting-the-baby-to-sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 20:49:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/14/putting-the-baby-to-sleep/</guid>
      <description>I quite recently became a father, and the poor child is exposed to a lot of tango music, naturally. (And I get out to dance less, hence the blog writing.) Before he was born, I used to talk about how we would practice walking together, he and I. Now this is how it turned out:
The scene: Unpatiant 12 days old boy, waiting for his mother to get ready for breast-feeding.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>