<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Milonga on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/tags/milonga/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Milonga on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2009 19:20:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/tags/milonga/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to organize a Milonga</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/07/how-to-organize-a-milonga/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2009 19:20:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/07/how-to-organize-a-milonga/</guid>
      <description>by Chris and Sue
Starting a milonga is easy, right? You just need a place to dance, put some music on, and there you go&amp;hellip;
&amp;hellip;well not exactly. There are lots of small and not so small details that work together to create a good environment for social dancing. Based on my experience as organizer of both unsuccessful events and much more successful events and experience from various milongas and practicas over the world, I attempt to gather some advice on how to approximate the authentic milonga in your own community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The real stuff</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/10/the-real-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2009 15:12:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/10/the-real-stuff/</guid>
      <description>by oed
Ah -- you dance **real** milonga (echte Milonga). After struggling with my milonga for years, this was the ultimate sign I was finally getting somewhere. And one of my favorite compliments ever. I got a tip from the Argentine host to ask this woman to dance, he thought I should dance with someone good. So I did. And was not disappointed. Starting almost right out with a milonga, which would have terrified me only a year earlier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Entering the milonga</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/17/entering-the-milonga/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2008 15:45:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/17/entering-the-milonga/</guid>
      <description>by Untitled blue
The moment or should I say process of entering a milonga is very special for me. I think savoring the moment is something very important in tango, and for me it starts at the moment I am standing outside the milonga entrance. There is a certain amount of expectation for the night even before, of course, but this is when I really start enjoying the sensation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>