<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nuevo on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/tags/nuevo/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nuevo on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/tags/nuevo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The origins of &#39;Tango Nuevo&#39;</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/05/01/the-origins-of-tango-nuevo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 17:55:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/05/01/the-origins-of-tango-nuevo/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/SW9BNE9o7Q0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;When I heard about the Dinzel book, I thought it was sort of a curious project. Working through all possibilities of tango steps, charting them out in elaborate diagrams with circles and arrows in all directions demonstrating the vast space of choreographic possibilites. I had a look at the book at a friend&amp;rsquo;s place several years ago, but it felt somehow disconnected to how I experienced the dance. This was rather early in my days of tango though, so maybe I would get more out of it at a later point. (If anyone of you got the book, I would love to have a picture/scan for illustration purposes of this post.) [EDIT: You can see an &lt;a href=&#34;http://shytanguero.blogspot.com/2009/10/once-upon-time.html&#34;&gt;example of one diagram here&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks to Chris for providing another diagram, shown below (click on the image to see the full resolution version):]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://img534.imageshack.us/img534/2171/dinzelpasobasetangoavan.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://img534.imageshack.us/img534/2171/dinzelpasobasetangoavan.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never took lessons with the Dinzel myself, but I heard from friends that they would often do exercises to explore the different possibilities from a given position, sort of like a game. Only after a friend that was going to Gustavo Naveira&amp;rsquo;s classes with us told us she started taking lessons with his old maestro, did I make the connection. In fact Gustavo also states in  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.danceoftheheart.com/naveirainterview.htm&#34;&gt;an interview&lt;/a&gt; by Brian Dunn that he was a student of the Dinzel:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;[W]hen I was in my twenties, about 1981, I started studying with Rodolfo Dinzel. I was one of his best students within that course, and he took special notice of me and worked me very very hard.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is actually a rather interesting interview, so I encourage you to read it all. It also motivates the search for a new approach to learning tango:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

&gt; 
&gt; You know, in my study of tango, often I would encounter a &#34;tango master&#34;, and even if you approached them respectfully, they would have an attitude of, &#34;I know everything, you are sh**, don&#39;t bother me&#34;. This is a typical attitude from an earlier way of looking at tango. So it was often very difficult to learn useful things about tango from them.
&gt; 
&gt; 
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fabián Salas elaborates on this in &lt;a href=&#34;http://totango.net/salas2.html&#34;&gt;another interesting interview&lt;/a&gt; by Keith Elshaw:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

&gt; 
&gt; At one point, I remember that we were very concerned about all these dancers dying - all these milongueros, all these teachers, they were dying. One after the other, three or four in one year. It was catastrophic. So I said, &#34;Gustavo, we are on our own; there is hardly anybody any more and if there is, we can&#39;t do much about it because it&#39;s hard to talk to these people. We have to start learning from ourselves. We have to start bringing the process along and the only way to do it is getting together. Why don&#39;t we join with the people that we consider are good dancers that have something to offer with this idea of, you know, changing - exchanging things? Getting together and practice in a serious way. Analyze.&#34;
&gt; 
&gt; 
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe anybody who has been in the tango world for a while can agree that there are some great egos out there, so this is easy to believe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems clear to me that Gustavo inherited the analytical approach of the Dinzel and took it to another level with his collaboration with Fabián Salas and Mariano &amp;ldquo;Chicho&amp;rdquo; Frumboli. And watching this clip of the Dinzel couple, I think I can recognize some of the ways or habits of Gustavo Naveira, for instance the way he is turning his foot when he is waiting with no weight on it, where most (?) other dancers use a flat foot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS: Unfortunately, youtube has just disabled the sound on this video, making it a lot less interesting to watch.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Mariano &#39;Chicho&#39; Frumboli</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/11/23/interview-with-mariano-chicho-frumboli/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2009 23:14:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/11/23/interview-with-mariano-chicho-frumboli/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/pktd/2364570952/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/11/chichos-feet.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Chicho’s feet by parakulturado, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/pktd/&#34;&gt; parakulturado&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

&gt; 
&gt; [T]oday there is a new generation that learned to dance 2,3 or 5 years ago, who only know how to do the new styles, the ganchos, the colgadas, but who are not in contact with everything that came before, and I go to the milongas and I see people that know how to move but that don’t know how to dance, people don’t breathe tango like they did before.
&gt; 
&gt; 

&gt; 
&gt; --Mariano &#39;Chicho&#39; Frumboli
&gt; 
&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an interesting &lt;a href=&#34;http://atdrc.com/default.asp?TextDisplay=1&amp;amp;Display=18&#34;&gt;interview with Chicho&lt;/a&gt;, he talks about how he started working with Gustavo Naveira and Fabian Salas, his artistic development and the relationship and tension between the new things that they do and the &amp;lsquo;traditional&amp;rsquo; tango.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is very easy to agree on some of his statements, and he is certainly a dancer I respect, even if I found out that I do not really want to dance like him. I had the pleasure of dancing in front of him for an entire tanda at Niño Bien, and he was dancing very considerately in the social environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found the parts where he discusses the periods with different partners and the corresponding artistic development particularly interesting, also Chicho on his weaknesses and strengths:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

&gt; 
&gt; I believe that my best qualities have to do with my musicality, and obviously my creativity within that realm.  I began as a musician and I continue to be one.  The music is what move me on all levels, I need to feel it in order to be able to dance, and I believe that is visible in my dancing.  And I believe my weakness has to do with my inhibition, I still don’t feel that I have exploited and showed everything I have to show, almost as if I haven’t been able to give myself completely as I would like to.
&gt; 
&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, on dancing with women of different styles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

&gt; 
&gt; I don’t care with what style she dances, what interests me is that in the moment when we are dancing together, that we are having fun together in the moment, I need to feel good next to that person.
&gt; 
&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Up and down</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/03/02/up-and-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2009 15:29:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/03/02/up-and-down/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/ableman/534153791/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1125/534153791_20e37d5eec.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The Mind Eraser by Scott Ableman, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/ableman/&#34;&gt; Scott Ableman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;-Have you been practicing tango nuevo?&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guilty as charged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He knew immediately. And it was not because I used an open embrace, we were practicing milonga, using a very confined embrace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I often wonder why people get so hang up on the somewhat arbitrary distinction between open and close embrace (all teachers, both &amp;ldquo;nuevo&amp;rdquo; and others usually promote very close embrace at times, but for some figures it is not possible to maintain the closest embrace.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some say that the technique is the same. Well, it is mostly compatible, and that is what matters, but there are some differences. Which was clearly demonstrated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What gave me away was that my energy was going down. That might not be the correct way of putting it, but you get the idea. What he wanted was energy going &lt;strong&gt;up.&lt;/strong&gt; So the difference was in the energy going up or down (up-traditional, down-nuevo). While staying well grounded, of course. Stretching the spine, effectively going up and down at the same time. Talk about dissosiation&amp;hellip; And it doesn&amp;rsquo;t require less in the balance department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might argue that whatever makes it possible (or easier) to do &lt;insert favorite fancy move here&gt; is worth it. Like in skiing, sacrificing elegance for ability to go faster or jump longer. Bending down for improved balance? Feet more apart?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Myself, I never saw the point of doing as many steps as possible (volcadas/minute anone?). It&amp;rsquo;s not like it&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/03/01/competition/&#34;&gt;competition&lt;/a&gt;, remember?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More on reinvention</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/28/more-on-reinvention/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2009 21:01:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/28/more-on-reinvention/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/oschene/2588641284/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3065/2588641284_603490d6d1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Onion by oschene, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/oschene/&#34;&gt; oschene&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After discussing my short &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/01/16/reinvention/&#34;&gt;post on reinvention in the comments&lt;/a&gt;, I decided to write a new post discussing the matter. Here is the quote again:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&#34;Those who don&#39;t understand [Tango] are condemned to reinvent it, poorly.&#34;

&gt; 
&gt; – Henry Spencer (about Unix)
&gt; 
&gt; 

&gt; 
&gt; 
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First I thought of it as a warning against setting out to reinvent or improve something that you do not fully understand, as it will be futile. So do not assume, that because you know the six fundamental building blocks of tango, you are ready to reinvent tango. Chances are you will fail miserably. If you miss something in tango, it could be that the fault is not with tango&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a second level, there are clearly some very talented dancers that do things that might be considered as (re)invention. And this is where it gets interesting. Without wanting to disrespect anybody, I was hoping the quote would trigger questions like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is tango reinvented by someone?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If so, by whom?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do they understand tango?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If tango is reinvented, is it for better or worse? And in what way(s)?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you add something new, what is left out? And what is new?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do we need to reinvent tango? What would we want to achieve?  What would reinvention of tango mean?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not so easy to answer, I think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS: Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://mytangologue.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;koolricky&lt;/a&gt; for biting ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reinvention</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/16/reinvention/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2009 15:31:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/16/reinvention/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/pallotron/631554319/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1088/631554319_199a6788d3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Poetry HackLab by pallotron, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/pallotron/&#34;&gt; pallotron&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&#34;Those who don&#39;t understand [Tango] are condemned to reinvent it, poorly.&#34;

&gt; 
&gt; – Henry Spencer (about Unix)
&gt; 
&gt; 
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe Miguel Angel Zotto to have said something along the same lines, that if you do not understand tango, how can you possibly improve it? I can&amp;rsquo;t seem to find the reference, though.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>