<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nostalgia on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>https://simbatango.github.io/tags/nostalgia/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nostalgia on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="https://simbatango.github.io/tags/nostalgia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Nostalgia</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2012/04/19/nostalgia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2012 21:10:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2012/04/19/nostalgia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.newyorker.com/online/blogs/cartoonists/120423_cn-in-the-nostalgia-district_p465.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I some times muse over the multiple levels of nostalgia in tango. Today we are (at least to some degree) nostalgic about the golden age of tango, peaking in the 1940s. Tango, of course, was already nostalgic about the turn of the century during the golden age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I always thought of this as layered or maybe even recursive nostalgia, beging nostalgic about the nostalgia of the 1940s. Add the nostalgia being a long way from Buenos Aires and longing back to being nostalgic about how they were nostalgic about the fin de ciecle in the golden age, and you get the picture&amp;hellip; Even the nostalgia was better in the old days. It&amp;rsquo;s all very meta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The New Yorker provides a different perspective in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newyorker.com/talk/comment/2012/04/23/120423taco_talk_gopnik&#34;&gt;an article about 40 years nostalgia cycles&lt;/a&gt; (also don&amp;rsquo;t miss &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newyorker.com/online/blogs/cartoonists/2012/04/nostalgia-is-never-passe.html&#34;&gt;the cartoons&lt;/a&gt;), and why they occur (people with power are often in their forties). Like many others I tend to link the revival of interest in tango in the 1980s with the fall of the dictatorship in Argentina, but it fits right into the theory because it happened about 40 years after the peak of the golden age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Forty years past is the potently fascinating time just as we arrived, when our parents were youthful and in love, the Edenic period preceding the fallen state recorded in our actual memories.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course it&amp;rsquo;s not backed by solid evidence, but let&amp;rsquo;s say that the 40 years cycle applies. Should we expect a wave of nostalgia about the 80s revival of tango argentino in ten years time?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Death of the Prodigy dancer</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/03/16/death-of-the-prodigy-dancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2009 21:40:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/03/16/death-of-the-prodigy-dancer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/mickal/78653689/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/42/78653689_6318c0c586.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Prodigy Concert by Mickal, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/mickal/&#34;&gt; Mickal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tango is full of nostalgia, even sentimentality. We long for the times that were. Even sentimentality was better in the 40s. How can it be for the real milongueros, who were young in that time?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not to say it is the same, but the thought struck me the other day. I just bought &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.emusic.com/album/The-Prodigy-Invaders-Must-Die-MP3-Download/11373684.html&#34;&gt;the new Prodigy album&lt;/a&gt;, playing it loud and dancing around the kitchen. (I do this a lot, usually to tango music these days) This was the music of my youth, when we went out to party, that was the best. And when we couldn&amp;rsquo;t go out because we were not old enough or didn&amp;rsquo;t have money, we listened to it at home. Longing for the long nights of dancing in a crowd of equal minded. And meeting girls, of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like the milongueros had tango. And not much else. It was the music of that time. What you did when you went out and wanted to meet girls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thunder! It triggered me to dance! Not tango, though. &lt;strong&gt;This&lt;/strong&gt; is how electronic dance music sounds today (or rather 10-15 years ago already). Not like that anemic you-know-what.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>