<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chicho on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/tags/chicho/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chicho on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2012 15:49:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/tags/chicho/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango Libre</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2012/11/07/tango-libre/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2012 15:49:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2012/11/07/tango-libre/</guid>
      <description>There is another tango film coming up. This Belgian production is starring Chicho, and although tango films can be a mixed bag, and I have my doubts how much drama it can yield, it looks sort of interesting. Apparently it won the Warsaw Film Festival Grand Prix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Interesting Reading/Viewing Elsewhere</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/11/12/some-interesting-readingviewing-elsewhere/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2011 08:23:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/11/12/some-interesting-readingviewing-elsewhere/</guid>
      <description>by Smath.
Not much time to write at the moment, here are some interesting posts that you might enjoy that I want to keep track of for later for my own sake:
Interesting interview with Chicho Part 1, Part 2 and Part 3
Quite an interesting read. I could relate very well to his comments on why teachers don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily dance all the time at festivals. Apparently many people in my local community have difficulties understanding this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>El Tangauta interviews Chicho</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/16/el-tangauta-interviews-chicho/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2009 03:28:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/16/el-tangauta-interviews-chicho/</guid>
      <description>Another interesting interview with Chicho, and he elaborates on some of the same things as in theprevious interview.
[The] milongueros had respect, delicacy and sensibility, it was totally different. I know my role is contradictory, because I also collaborated in generating this young movement. In its moment I got tired of the strict milonguero codes that didn’t correspond with my time and to rebel I tried to make my way. Today I’m a milonguero again (laughter); I’m against the people who do not cabecear (nod), who don’t have codes or respect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Mariano &#39;Chicho&#39; Frumboli</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/11/23/interview-with-mariano-chicho-frumboli/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2009 23:14:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/11/23/interview-with-mariano-chicho-frumboli/</guid>
      <description>by parakulturado
   [T]oday there is a new generation that learned to dance 2,3 or 5 years ago, who only know how to do the new styles, the ganchos, the colgadas, but who are not in contact with everything that came before, and I go to the milongas and I see people that know how to move but that don’t know how to dance, people don’t breathe tango like they did before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boleos helados</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/15/boleos-helados/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2008 21:34:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/15/boleos-helados/</guid>
      <description>by Hettie McFarlane
Limerick&amp;rsquo;s post on boleos made me think of the concept of boleos helados, or frozen boleos. I went to a workshop with Chicho and Lucía a couple of years back, and while the frozen boleos were sort of fun, it ruins your boleo technique if you shape your boleos that way. Methinks.
The intrigueing thing about boleos is their free flowing unmanaged quality. Or as Limerick says:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confiteria La Ideal en BBC</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/23/confiteria-la-ideal-en-bbc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2008 20:49:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/23/confiteria-la-ideal-en-bbc/</guid>
      <description>Another good documentary about tango. I enjoyed it a lot. Some of the interesting scenes are available on youtube, but the documentary itself was quite hard to get hold of. As far as I could determine, it is not available for sale, not even on ebay, so you better know one of them pirates or use your imagination ;-)
I am quite impressed by how ordinary dancers are able to express what tango means to them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>