<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Transfer on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/tags/transfer/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Transfer on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/tags/transfer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>More Fast Transfers</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2013/05/07/more-fast-transfers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 08:36:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2013/05/07/more-fast-transfers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/ale_era/3681831618/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2650/3681831618_f2b4553466.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Unbelievable!!! by Aleera*, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/ale_era/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/ale_era/&#34;&gt;Aleera*&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2011/06/15/too-fast-transfers/&#34;&gt;previously discussed too fast transfers from 78s&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;http://tangodjduo.nl/di-sarli-el-ciruja/&#34;&gt;Age Akkerman has a well researched take on Di Sarli&amp;rsquo;s El ciruja&lt;/a&gt; which he found to be about 5% too fast on the Euro Records transfer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Too Fast Transfers</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/06/15/too-fast-transfers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 21:23:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/06/15/too-fast-transfers/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/raza-criolla.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/raza-criolla.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sort of promised to post a few samples of my results from slowing down some tracks that &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2011/05/07/dym-online-tango-classics/&#34;&gt;I believe are transferred at too high speed in the DyM Tango Classics collection&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I have suspected that several other transfers, most notably on the El Bandoneon label were transferred at too high speed, I never tried slowing them down myself because I knew it to be hard to find the correct speed. Maybe impossible. To know you got the right signal (as in as similar or undistorted relative to how it sounded before it entered the recording chain), you would have to know the tone played at some time during the recording, and how the instrument that played that tone was tuned. Even though there are scores for many tangos, the exact arrangements are rarely available, and even then you would have to know that the musicians did not deviate from what was written there (e.g. transposing up or down a (semi)tone). And how the instrument was tuned. Most commonly the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Concert_pitch&#34;&gt;concert pitch&lt;/a&gt; A is supposed to be 440 Hz, but it has varied from time to time and from orchestra to orchestra.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not trivial in other words as I basically had access to exactly none of the required information. I usually tried to get another and hopefully more correct transfer, leaving the problem to be sorted out by someone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now with some of these De Caro recordings, it was just too annoying, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t know of any other transfers available (which was why I got them in the first place). So I gave it a try. As I don&amp;rsquo;t have perfect pitch and didn&amp;rsquo;t have the above mentioned information, I did it by trial and error, and I paid particular attention to the timbre of the piano, attack, decay etc and generally tried to assess whether it sounded &amp;lsquo;right&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would be interested to hear your opinion, here are two examples, both by Julio De Caro, El taita/Raza criolla and Maipo. First original as transferred by DyM, then my 7 percent slowed down versions (about one semitone). EDIT: I added some samples for tracks that I believe are not so readily available: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tango.info/04024236200191-1-7&#34;&gt;Berretín&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tango.info/04024236200498-1-4&#34;&gt;Lorenzo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tracks-also-available-on-rca-100-años&#34;&gt;Tracks also available on RCA 100 Años&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/09-El-taita-Raza-criolla30s.mp3&#34;&gt;-09 El taita &amp;ndash; Raza criolla30s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/09-El-taita-Raza-criolla-7pct-slower30s.mp3&#34;&gt;-09 El taita &amp;ndash; Raza criolla-7pct-slower30s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/08-Maipo30s.mp3&#34;&gt;-08 Maipo30s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/Maipo-7pct-slower30s.mp3&#34;&gt;-Maipo-7pct-slower30s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tracks-unique-for-dym&#34;&gt;Tracks &amp;ldquo;Unique&amp;rdquo; for DyM&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/07-Berretin30s.mp3&#34;&gt;-07 Berretin30s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/07-Berretin-7pct-slower30s.mp3&#34;&gt;-07 Berretin-7pct-slower30s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/04-Lorenzo-Felix-Gutierrez30s.mp3&#34;&gt;-04 Lorenzo (Felix Gutierrez)30s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/04-Lorenzo-Felix-Gutierrez-7pct-slower30s.mp3&#34;&gt;-04 Lorenzo (Felix Gutierrez)-7pct-slower30s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DyM Online | Tango Classics</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/05/07/dym-online--tango-classics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 20:27:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/05/07/dym-online--tango-classics/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/toddbinger/3235728614/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3265/3235728614_f7835317b7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Color Spectrum CD Reflection by Todd Binger, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/toddbinger/&#34;&gt; Todd Binger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to check out the offerings of DyM a bit more closely after I noticed that some of them were available in lossless format from the French site Qobuz. I got a couple of De Caro compilations because they are hard to get by other places. These tracks are mostly from the late 20s and early 30s, so what I found out may or may not apply to other, later recordings issued in this series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;material&#34;&gt;Material&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of these tracks are not available on cd or as downloads anywhere else as far as I know, and early De Caro is very intersting for several reasons, not least because he had a great influence on the development of tango music. To state it briefly, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.todotango.com/english/creadores/jdecaro.html&#34;&gt;De Caro was a genius&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;quality&#34;&gt;Quality&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These several of these volumes are available as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.qobuz.com/label/zebralution-dym-online/telechargement-ecoute-albums&#34;&gt;lossless downloads from Qobuz&lt;/a&gt;, and now &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.danzaymovimiento.com/dymlog/id/133-Download-salsa-and-tango-music-as-FLAC&#34;&gt;also directly from DyM&lt;/a&gt;. This is a great development, and very useful for tango music, as it can often be useful to do some eq or other processing of the sound, which is the case where lossy codecs are not really a good choice. And it turned out that some editing is indeed needed for the DyM releases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quality of the transfers I got was very variable. Some tracks were fine, with little noise and pretty much ready to be listened to, others were very noisy and quite a few were noticeably sped up during transfer from shellac. I tried slowing them down 6-12% (depending on track), and by comparing to other versions of the tracks that I already had, I got it more or less right, but it is very hard if not impossible to know for sure what the exact speed should be. One has to use one&amp;rsquo;s ears, and I used the timbre of the piano as a guideline, which seems to have worked out fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is in stark contrast with the Japanese collectors editions of CTA and AMP which are consistently well transferred in my experience. The transfers of El Bandoneon were infamous for being transferred at too high speed, like many of these are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cover-and-information&#34;&gt;Cover and information&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These collections are download only, which means that there is basically no cover information such as recording date, matrix number etc. Very bare bone. I used &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tango.info/albums/?col=DYM+Online%2F+Tango+Classics&#34;&gt;tango.info&lt;/a&gt; to improve tagging of my files. The Japanese series of CTA and AMP are way ahead in providing meta information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover art is a joke. Not only is the image a disaster, the cover image also suffers from &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Compression_artifact&#34;&gt;ugly jpg artifacts&lt;/a&gt;. Not that it is really important, but I mean &amp;ndash;  come on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;price-and-availability&#34;&gt;Price and availability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I actually think download only works well for this fringe material. Not to say for all music. For me personally cds are not very interesting, I only read a cd exactly once anyway which is when I rip it to lossless files on my computer. Lossless downloads is a very nice development, and kudos for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both at Qobuz and at DyM you have to buy the entire volume to get the lossless version, though, which is irritating and somewhat offsets the advantage of downloads where you usually only pay for the tracks you need. I know I am not alone in buying cds to get just one track missing from my collection. Therefore this is unfortunate from a customer perspective, but probably makes sense from a profit maximizing vendor perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9-10 tracks for EUR 10.39 at Qobuz and ca EUR 9 + membership (EUR 29.88/year) from DyM is a bit pricey, considering the price of commercial releases from Argentina and BATC where you get roughly twice the number of tracks for the same price. It is a bit cheaper and much more readily available than the Japanese releases, but the quality of the transfers and the information provided is not at the same level either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearly material for collectors and djs only.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>