<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Carlos Copello on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>https://simbatango.github.io/tags/carlos-copello/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Carlos Copello on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="https://simbatango.github.io/tags/carlos-copello/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Putting the baby to sleep</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2008/10/14/putting-the-baby-to-sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 20:49:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2008/10/14/putting-the-baby-to-sleep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I quite recently became a father, and the poor child is exposed to a lot of tango music, naturally. (And I get out to dance less, hence the blog writing.) Before he was born, I used to talk about how we would practice walking together, he and I. Now this is how it turned out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scene: Unpatiant 12 days old boy, waiting for his mother to get ready for breast-feeding. Father to find something to entertain the child, and preferably also himself in the meantime. Time for tango. Di Sarli&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Nido Gaucho&lt;/em&gt; on the stereo, practicing the tango walk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boy seemed to enjoy the experience, I would say. Not as big eyes as with the milonga a few days earlyer (yes - really). After one tango and a half, he became more quiet. A few other songs from the same album, then the &lt;em&gt;Porteño y bailarín&lt;/em&gt; album from the start. The boy fell asleep in my arms. And I got to practice my walk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The funny thing about this, is that having a baby in your arms, getting it to sleep is a quite common metaphor for the way the woman should be held in the embrace. Soft, yet firm and secure.  I know at least El &amp;ldquo;Negro&amp;rdquo; Capello and Javier Rodríguez have used this metaphor. The thing is, I spent quite a lot of time practicing my tango embrace, but not making babies sleep. I got the idea, of course, but now I could apply the metaphor in the reverse direction, using my tango skills to get the boy to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, I fell asleep quite happily that night myself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>