<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technique on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>https://simbatango.github.io/tags/technique/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technique on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="https://simbatango.github.io/tags/technique/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution?</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2010/04/27/evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2010 20:35:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2010/04/27/evolution/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/bQb7JWpEVRo&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I hear it every so often: that tango technique, especially for women, has gone through a tremendous evolution since the resurgence in the early 1980s. Let&amp;rsquo;s just say I&amp;rsquo;m not quite convinced. Watch this clip from the 1988 movie &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0096221/&#34;&gt;Tango Bar&lt;/a&gt;, and draw your own conclusions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Necessary</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/05/14/necessary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2009 01:13:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/05/14/necessary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/openthreads/457204337/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/240/457204337_b2d45ca69a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Flamingo - Albuquerque BioPark by OpenThreads, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/openthreads/&#34;&gt; OpenThreads&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Breaking the dance of tango down to its smallest parts is a popular exercise. Why stop at forward-side-back-steps? What it really comes down to is one simple concept. If you can do it, you can tango. Or at least you need to be able to do it to dance it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standing on one leg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a week-end class, we had one student with some condition that made it impossible for her to stand on one leg. Which was sad because the communication did not work at all. I was sorry to realize that she would never be able to dance tango, even if she really wanted to. We did our best to make it work and for her to have a good time, of course,  but it was quite clear that tango was not for her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may seem all too obvious to write a blogpost about, no? Well, there is a more subtle point I wanted to make. The best dancers have a clarity and elegance, simplicity of movement that we all long for (I suppose). And to a large degree it stems from their ability to stand on exactly one leg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No less, no more&amp;hellip; ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Up and down</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/03/02/up-and-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2009 15:29:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/03/02/up-and-down/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/ableman/534153791/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1125/534153791_20e37d5eec.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The Mind Eraser by Scott Ableman, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/ableman/&#34;&gt; Scott Ableman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;-Have you been practicing tango nuevo?&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guilty as charged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He knew immediately. And it was not because I used an open embrace, we were practicing milonga, using a very confined embrace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I often wonder why people get so hang up on the somewhat arbitrary distinction between open and close embrace (all teachers, both &amp;ldquo;nuevo&amp;rdquo; and others usually promote very close embrace at times, but for some figures it is not possible to maintain the closest embrace.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some say that the technique is the same. Well, it is mostly compatible, and that is what matters, but there are some differences. Which was clearly demonstrated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What gave me away was that my energy was going down. That might not be the correct way of putting it, but you get the idea. What he wanted was energy going &lt;strong&gt;up.&lt;/strong&gt; So the difference was in the energy going up or down (up-traditional, down-nuevo). While staying well grounded, of course. Stretching the spine, effectively going up and down at the same time. Talk about dissosiation&amp;hellip; And it doesn&amp;rsquo;t require less in the balance department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might argue that whatever makes it possible (or easier) to do &lt;insert favorite fancy move here&gt; is worth it. Like in skiing, sacrificing elegance for ability to go faster or jump longer. Bending down for improved balance? Feet more apart?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Myself, I never saw the point of doing as many steps as possible (volcadas/minute anone?). It&amp;rsquo;s not like it&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/03/01/competition/&#34;&gt;competition&lt;/a&gt;, remember?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boleos helados</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2008/12/15/boleos-helados/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2008 21:34:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2008/12/15/boleos-helados/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/hettiemcfarlane/225531507/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/79/225531507_fb9f3664ee.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;icecream cow, Budapest, Hungary by Hettie McFarlane, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/hettiemcfarlane/&#34;&gt; Hettie McFarlane&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.limericktango.com/blog/&#34;&gt;Limerick&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s post on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.limericktango.com/2008/11/boleos/&#34;&gt;boleos&lt;/a&gt; made me think of the concept of boleos helados, or frozen boleos. I went to a workshop with Chicho and Lucía a couple of years back, and while the frozen boleos were sort of fun, it ruins your boleo technique if you shape your boleos that way. Methinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The intrigueing thing about boleos is their free flowing unmanaged quality. Or as Limerick says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;You don’t do boleos, boleos happen.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technique vs. Feeling</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2008/11/27/technique-vs.-feeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2008 21:42:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2008/11/27/technique-vs.-feeling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/abhijit/1399642105/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1009/1399642105_b924d9730b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Violinist from MC Rai - 2 BW by my hovercraft is full of eels, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/abhijit/&#34;&gt; my hovercraft is full of eels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which one is most important? Technique or dancing with feeling? I sometimes get the impression that tango dancers are divided in two camps, the technique camp and the feelings camp. The first emphasizes the technical matters of the dance, the latter paying solely attention to the feeling. As long as we can hug each other, all is well ;-) Both seemingly ignoring the other point of view completely. As a matter of fact, I used to get a little annoyed by people who dismissed technique and just wanted to be in the embrace, feeeeeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By what interests me nowadays, I can easily be mistaken for belonging in the feelings camp. I find the technical extravaganzas of many performances quite boring at times, as they convey no emotional content whatsoever (to me, that is). So have I moved to the other camp?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not really, I would rather say I belong in the both are necessary camp. I just  heard an interview on the radio with a conductor visiting one of the major symphony orchestras here, and he made the following statement about the two leading violinists in the orchestra (quoted as I remember it):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;They have very good technique, which allows them to express their musicality.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this is at the heart of the matter. You need good technique. You need it to express your musicality through your dance. You should work hard to improve it, but technique alone will not do. It is a necessary condition, but hardly sufficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And just as the music critics rather discuss the interpretation of an orchestra or musician, I think the artistic interpretation is more interesting to discuss than the technical points. Technique is simple, really: all you need is good teachers and a lot of practice&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>