<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Documentary on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/categories/documentary/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Documentary on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/categories/documentary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Podestá Godoy, cantores | Documentary</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2015/10/07/podesta-godoy-cantores-documentary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2015 13:28:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2015/10/07/podesta-godoy-cantores-documentary/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/-2K_RQ-SRpM&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;A new documentary on tango singers Alberto Podestá and Juan Carlos Godoy by Daniel Tonelli and Marcelo Turrisi looks interesting. Hope it gets released on dvd or video on demand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HT: Janis&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Last Tango -- Copes y Nieves</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2015/09/10/our-last-tango-copes-y-nieves/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 11:43:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2015/09/10/our-last-tango-copes-y-nieves/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now this looks like something to look forward to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;In „Our Last Tango“ Juan and María tell their story to a group of young tango dancers and choreographers from Buenos Aires, who transform the most beautiful, moving and dramatic moments of Juan and Maria’s lives into incredible tango-choreographies.  These beautifully-shot choreographies compliment the soul-searching interviews and documentary moments of the film to make this an unforgettable journey into the heart of the tango.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&#34;http://- See more at: http://widehouse.org/film/our-last-tango/&#34;&gt;more about Our Last Tango (Un tango más) here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/138545957&#34;&gt;Link to the trailer.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Felix Picherna | Tengo una pregunta para vos</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2014/09/02/felix-picherna-tengo-una-pregunta-para-vos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 19:37:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2014/09/02/felix-picherna-tengo-una-pregunta-para-vos/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/ZXlAziV8yFo&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Felix Picherna is a legend, and he was clearly the first tango dj to make a lasting impression in me. Sitting with his cassette deck, rewinding the prepared tandas, live commenting the upcoming music with the microphone. Unforgettable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy this video from the excellent &amp;ldquo;Tengo una pregunta para vos&amp;rdquo; series by Pepa Palazón, that I just recently found time to start watching. There are several gems there, and the most recent ones are subtitled in English (that includes this one).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also really enjoyed the ones with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ju2LRV3BymI&#34;&gt;Vanina Bilous&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WHajO2jYxMw&#34;&gt;Olga Besio&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Aphw2EmiQTU&#34;&gt;Guillermina Quiroga&lt;/a&gt;, and I still have quite a few to go.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango Negro, The African Roots of Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2014/04/02/tango-negro-the-african-roots-of-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 20:53:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2014/04/02/tango-negro-the-african-roots-of-tango/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/b1OCMY06u7M&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Now this looks interesting, a documentary about the African roots of tango. It&amp;rsquo;s featuring &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Juan_Carlos_C%C3%A1ceres&#34;&gt;Juan Carlos Cáceres&lt;/a&gt; (of &amp;ldquo;Tango Negro&amp;rdquo; fame), of which I&amp;rsquo;m a great fan. One of the best concerts I ever attended was with Cáceres and band and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vBvn0UAl6gQ&#34;&gt;Facundo &amp;amp; Kely Posadas&lt;/a&gt; performing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;a href=&#34;http://nyadiff.org/tango-negro-the-african-roots-of-tango-candombe/&#34;&gt;read a bit more about the documentary&lt;/a&gt; at the ADIFF film festival pages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carlos Di Sarli Documentary</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2013/03/30/carlos-di-sarli-documentary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 08:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2013/03/30/carlos-di-sarli-documentary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/DiSarli.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/DiSarli.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DiSarli&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Realidad Bonaerense, there is a new &lt;a href=&#34;http://realidadbonaerense.blogspot.no/2013/03/se-estrena-el-film-carlos-di-sarli-el.html&#34;&gt;documentary about Carlos di Sarli&lt;/a&gt; coming out, directed by Alberto Freinquel. No information about dvd or download edition, but there will be several public viewings in Buenos Aires and in Bahía Blanca, I think. The article mentions several dramatized sequences, which makes me a bit sceptical, but I guess you have to do something if there is little historical material available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EDIT: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.enterateantes.com.ar/merecida-reparacion-historica-a-carlos-di-sarli/&#34;&gt;A bit more information here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Documentary: Eyes Closed -- Ad occhi chiusi</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/11/17/upcoming-documentary-eyes-closed-ad-occhi-chiusi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2010 08:41:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/11/17/upcoming-documentary-eyes-closed-ad-occhi-chiusi/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/TtCQfGcuOk8&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I missed (at least) one on my last post on upcoming movies. This one is an Italian documentary.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adocchichiusi.com/eyesclosed.html&#34;&gt;Here is a link to the film website for more information&lt;/a&gt;, and here is a link to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=W4NnMP1H4wc&#34;&gt;Italian version of the trailer&lt;/a&gt; for those who prefer. From the website:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;This will be the story of Rossana, a young Italian artist, who rediscovers her femininity by means of the Tango, going through a real metamorphosis which is enhanced by the sparkle in her eyes when telling her story. We will meet Nicola and Pietro, that fight their disease in the steps of tango.

These intertwined stories are enriched by the voices and faces of the numerous protagonists: ordinary people who attend the “Milonga Illegal”, teachers and professional dancers, highly-rated scholars and researchers in many different fields of discipline who share an interest in the study of psychological and sociocultural behaviour behind this passion.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone knows what Italian dialect are the first few Itialians are speaking? I&amp;rsquo;ve never heard that way of speaking Italian before, I think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HT: Ilene&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>El otro camino</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/19/el-otro-camino/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2009 02:50:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/19/el-otro-camino/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/iangallagher/2078325269/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2239/2078325269_1de1aef438.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bandoneon by i_gallagher, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/iangallagher/&#34;&gt; i_gallagher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Una vez, tocando con una pequeña orquesta  en la escuela  de música popular -- eran estudiantes; yo me sentí, tocando con ellos, me sentí cómodo. Pero físicamente cómodo, como cuando  uno se siente con la ropa de entrecasa. Y dije: &#34;¿Que me pasa? Y de pronto, la orquesta estaba tocando, esa orquesta de la escuela en un concierto y salen a bailar algunas personas. Y yo ví eso y dije: &#34;esto es maravilloso&#34;. &#34;Esta gente baila y baila conmigo&#34;. Está  reinterpretando, lo mismo que yo. Yo estoy tocando ese melodía y ellos la están tocando con los pies. Y cuando comprendí que esos bailarines estaban más cerca de mí, que esa gente que me aplaude  por los acordes raros que uno puede hacer.  Dije: &#34;Hay que recuperar el baile&#34;.

&gt; 
&gt; _Rodolfo Mederos_
&gt; 
&gt; 
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally got around to watching the documentary &lt;em&gt;El otro camino&lt;/em&gt; with Rodolfo Mederos. I got tipped by a &lt;a href=&#34;http://tangocommuter1.blogspot.com/2009/04/bandoneons-for-sale.html&#34;&gt;comment over at tangocommuter&lt;/a&gt;, and ordered it &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/El-Otro-Camino-Rodolfo-Mederos/dp/B001BP150W/&#34;&gt;from Amazon&lt;/a&gt; right away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think I am exagerrating when I say that Mederos is one of the major bandoneon players of our time, and I really enjoyed watching &lt;em&gt;El otro camino&lt;/em&gt;. Rather short and simple, it has lots of musical numbers, and Mederos talking about the instrument, playing it and about tango in general in between. It is a good format. If you like tango music, and chances are that you do, as you are reading this, I think you will enjoy this little film.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The music is excellent, only the mixing is a little odd for some numbers. It could be that we watched it on a pc, but with Mederos playing with a trio, it was next to impossible to hear the other instruments. Aside from that, everything was good, and a pleasure to listen to the wisdom of one of the top bandoneon players in Buenos Aires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love how the porteños use this colorful language, which is especially evident when he talks about how it is necessary to bring tango back to life after the dark times that have passed. Interestingly, he also talks a bit about dancing, and what he has to say makes a lot of sense. I do hope that more musicians would come to the same conclusion as Mederos. Here is an attempt to translate the above quote to English:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;One day, while I was playing with a small orchestra in the school of popular music -- they were students; I found myself, playing with them, feeling very comfortable. Physically comfortable, like when you put on gym clothes. And I said: What is happening to me? And suddenly, as the orquestra was playing, this school orchestra, giving a concert, some people started dancing. And I saw this and said: This is marvellous, These people are dancing with me. They are interpreting, just like me. I am playing this melody, and they are playing with their feet. And then I understood that these dancers were closer to me than the people that applauded me for the strange chords that one can make. I said: The dance must recovered.

One day, I was playing with a little student orchestra in the college of popular music — I was playing with them, and I felt very comfortable. I mean, physically comfortable, like wearing pyjamas. And I said to myself, What is this? And then suddenly, the orchestra was playing, this college orchestra giving a concert, and some people got up and danced. And I saw this and I went, “this is brilliant”. “These people are dancing with me”. They were interpreting the music, just like me. I am playing the music, and they’re playing it with their feet. And I realised that these dancers were more with me than an audience who applaud me for the intricate harmonies I can play. I said: “We need to revive the dance”.

&gt; 
&gt; _Rodolfo Mederos_
&gt; 
&gt; 
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_Suggestions for improvements of my translation are welcome. Edit: New translation heavily influenced by suggestions from &lt;a href=&#34;http://mshedgehog.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Ms Hedgehog&lt;/a&gt;_&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silencio</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/04/25/silencio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2009 13:19:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/04/25/silencio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/entropik/295420031/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/117/295420031_1182d0d95d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Silencio (1) by entropiK, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/entropik/&#34;&gt; entropiK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;El que hace bien el silencio, hace bien el tango

(Who plays the silence well, plays the tango well)

&gt; 
&gt; Osvaldo Requena
&gt; 
&gt; 

&gt; 
&gt; 
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorite quote from the outstanding &lt;em&gt;Café de los Maestros&lt;/em&gt; documentary. I just wanted to watch it all over again as soon as it was finished. ¡Que sentimiento! ¡Que pasión!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 Tangos -- Adios Buenos Aires</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/19/12-tangos-adios-buenos-aires/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2008 17:06:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/19/12-tangos-adios-buenos-aires/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/11/12-tangos.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/11/12-tangos.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The documentary &lt;a href=&#34;http://12tangos.com&#34;&gt;12 tangos&lt;/a&gt; was just released in international version on DVD. It is a documentary, and the Adios Buenos Aires part of the title is somehow more accurate with regards to the content of the film. If you are looking for the Buena Vista Social Club of tango, you will be disappointed. There are no interviews with musicians, and only a few of the oldtimers participate in the orchestra. So Café de los maestros should be a better bet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;12 tangos is mainly a film about the hard times in Argentina after the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Argentine_economic_crisis_(1999-2002)&#34;&gt;crisis in &lt;sup&gt;2001&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2002&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/a&gt; when many lost everything they had, and quite a lot of people were forced to move to Europe to get work. That is, in the opposite direction of their anscestors, who went from Europe to Argentine for the same purpose. The film tells the stories of a young dancer (Marcela Maiola) going to Paris, her partner, the retired professional dancer (&lt;a href=&#34;http://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=ji6R1K_oAUo&#34;&gt;Roberto Tonet&lt;/a&gt;) who is afraid of losing his apartment in order to survive and  a mother (Yolanda Zubieta) leaving her children to go to Spain (she has no apparent connection with tango).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mixed in between these are musical numbers from a concert at La Catedral, a milonga in Buenos Aires. This is where the 12 tangos come in, and they are supposed to work like a framwork for the storytelling, and are marked as chapters on the dvd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though it did not take me with storm, I quite enjoyed the film. The photography was excellent at times. I particularly enjoyed the scene that is shown on the cover, where some partly hidden dancers are part of the live show at La Catedral. It works much better in motion than on the cover. The dancing was ok, not stunning, but nice. I did not like the slow motion sequence, though, as the connection with the music is completely lost, but maybe it works better for non-dancers. I admit my preferences in this respect have changed considerably after taking up dancing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Las muñecas dressed as vampires were hilarious, even if they were even better in _&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0380741/&#34;&gt;Tango, un giro extraño&lt;/a&gt;__. _And Roberto was quite a character :-) But I also found something amiss, like it did not all fit together that well. Maybe the relation between the 12 tangos and the rest of the film was not clear enough.  There were also some peculiarities, like having school-children explain the economic crisis that I found a bit strange. Some glitches in the text, where the English text was suddenly in German.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some more about the musicians would have been nice, and the presence of José Libertella was perhaps a bit oversold, as he is only featured in one of the last musical numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall a nice film. And on a completely subjective note, it is so good to see footage from mi Buenos Aires querido, el colectivo, hearing people chit chat, people walking in the streets, the skyline&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both the film and the soundtrack are available from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://12tangos.com/&#34;&gt;film&amp;rsquo;s website&lt;/a&gt;. It took about a week from I order until I had the discs in my hand. For immediate listening, I just discovered that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.emusic.com/album/Luis-Borda-12-Tangos-Adios-Buenos-Aires-MP3-Download/11320075.html&#34;&gt;the sountrack is available on emusic&lt;/a&gt; as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 tangos</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/01/12-tangos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 11:24:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/01/12-tangos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just &lt;a href=&#34;http://12tangos.com/&#34;&gt;ordered the new documentary 12 tangos&lt;/a&gt;. Will be very interesting to see, it also claims to be a Buena Vista Tango Club, so a shootout between 12 tangos and Cafe de los maestros. 12 tangos has a great advantage in being actually available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will get back to it later, in the meantime, the trailer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[youtube]&lt;a href=&#34;http://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=mrFklWP6dQY&amp;amp;feature=related[/youtube&#34;&gt;http://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=mrFklWP6dQY&amp;amp;feature=related[/youtube&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lágrima Ríos &amp; Candombe</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/28/lagrima-rios-candombe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2008 22:13:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/28/lagrima-rios-candombe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; the name! Lágrima Ríos is a wonderful artistic name, Rivers of tears..  Re tango, no?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.emusic.com/music/images/album/288/111/746/11174699/300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;La Perla Negra del Tango&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My attention was brought to some of her recordings by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.milonga.co.uk/blog/?p=130&#34;&gt;Michael&amp;rsquo;s music&lt;/a&gt; blog, discussing some available recordings of hers. Luckily, I was able to find them &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.emusic.com/artist/Lágrima-Ríos-MP3-Download/11952621.html&#34;&gt;both at emusic&lt;/a&gt; for instant satisfaction :-) She is featured in the film Café de los maestros, which I have not yet been able to get hold of (but will eventually!), but there was something familiar, I thought. And yes there was:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She is also featured in the documentary &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0375637/&#34;&gt;Candombe&lt;/a&gt;. If Café de maestros is the Buena Vista Social Club of tango, then this must be the one for the Candombe. As you will know if you have been in San Telmo on a Sunday evening, the candombe culture is alive in Buenos Aires today. You hear the drums far away, and in the winter darkness it can be a bit scary for the newcomer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film is based on the candombe culture of Montevideo in Uruguay, and we meet people from different parts of the culture, drum makers, singers, drummers etc. It is very charming, and even if I have never been to Montevideo, it all felt very familiar, giving away the close relationship between the two cities. I got it on DVD at Zival&amp;rsquo;s I believe, and it comes with a CD! Recommended to fill in on the black origins/parts of tango culture.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Café de los maestros</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/13/cafe-de-los-maestros/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2008 13:33:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/13/cafe-de-los-maestros/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Always looking out for new films about tango, both dance and music, I must say I am really looking forward to this one: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1185589/&#34;&gt;Café de los maestros&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. It has been described as the tango equivalent to the _&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0186508/&#34;&gt;Buena Vista Social Club&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;I already got the soundtrack, so I know the music is excellent. Can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see it.&lt;/em&gt; _&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When oh when will it become available on DVD? It will never be shown on the silver screen where I live I&amp;rsquo;m afraid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, here is the trailer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;httpvh://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=bi8C7m8TVxU&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confiteria La Ideal en BBC</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/23/confiteria-la-ideal-en-bbc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2008 20:49:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/23/confiteria-la-ideal-en-bbc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another good documentary about tango. I enjoyed it a lot. Some of the interesting scenes are available on youtube, but the documentary itself was quite hard to get hold of. As far as I could determine, it is not available for sale, not even on ebay, so you better know one of them pirates or use your imagination ;-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am quite impressed by how ordinary dancers are able to express what tango means to them. I always find it hard to describe what in tango I love so much or why I came to be obsessed with tango.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it made me long for Buenos Aires. A lot. And that hurt. But it was still a good experience, a tango experience I suppose.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/1TufSIR3onU&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;



&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/7r1mPWczWPk&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;



&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/y5CmBLdEY9A&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;



&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/T5_RnRny8kI&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>O Ultimo Bandoneón</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/08/21/o-ultimo-bandoneon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2008 18:39:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/08/21/o-ultimo-bandoneon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is actually possible to get hold of &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/index.php/2008/07/22/la-ultima-bandoneon/&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;, but I had to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.travessa.com.br/O_ULTIMO_BANDONEON/artigo/e1ae6378-bb14-471e-8a38-29d92cccc084&#34;&gt;order it from Brazil&lt;/a&gt;, so it was with portuguese subtitles, which was - challenging, but a very nice film it was. Recommended.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>El último bandoneón</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/22/la-ultima-bandoneon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2008 10:15:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/22/la-ultima-bandoneon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;httpvh://youtube.com/watch?v=eGerxiMniBQ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maravillosa!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now where can I get the entire &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0414712/&#34;&gt;film&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trailer here:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/wIgEb_nxPdk&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>