<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Documentary on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/categories/documentary/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Documentary on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2015 13:28:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/categories/documentary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Podestá Godoy, cantores | Documentary</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2015/10/07/podesta-godoy-cantores-documentary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2015 13:28:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2015/10/07/podesta-godoy-cantores-documentary/</guid>
      <description>A new documentary on tango singers Alberto Podestá and Juan Carlos Godoy by Daniel Tonelli and Marcelo Turrisi looks interesting. Hope it gets released on dvd or video on demand.
HT: Janis</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Last Tango -- Copes y Nieves</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2015/09/10/our-last-tango-copes-y-nieves/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 11:43:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2015/09/10/our-last-tango-copes-y-nieves/</guid>
      <description>Now this looks like something to look forward to:
In „Our Last Tango“ Juan and María tell their story to a group of young tango dancers and choreographers from Buenos Aires, who transform the most beautiful, moving and dramatic moments of Juan and Maria’s lives into incredible tango-choreographies. These beautifully-shot choreographies compliment the soul-searching interviews and documentary moments of the film to make this an unforgettable journey into the heart of the tango.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Felix Picherna | Tengo una pregunta para vos</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2014/09/02/felix-picherna-tengo-una-pregunta-para-vos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 19:37:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2014/09/02/felix-picherna-tengo-una-pregunta-para-vos/</guid>
      <description>Felix Picherna is a legend, and he was clearly the first tango dj to make a lasting impression in me. Sitting with his cassette deck, rewinding the prepared tandas, live commenting the upcoming music with the microphone. Unforgettable.
Enjoy this video from the excellent &amp;ldquo;Tengo una pregunta para vos&amp;rdquo; series by Pepa Palazón, that I just recently found time to start watching. There are several gems there, and the most recent ones are subtitled in English (that includes this one).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango Negro, The African Roots of Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2014/04/02/tango-negro-the-african-roots-of-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 20:53:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2014/04/02/tango-negro-the-african-roots-of-tango/</guid>
      <description>Now this looks interesting, a documentary about the African roots of tango. It&amp;rsquo;s featuring Juan Carlos Cáceres (of &amp;ldquo;Tango Negro&amp;rdquo; fame), of which I&amp;rsquo;m a great fan. One of the best concerts I ever attended was with Cáceres and band and Facundo &amp;amp; Kely Posadas performing.
You can read a bit more about the documentary at the ADIFF film festival pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carlos Di Sarli Documentary</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2013/03/30/carlos-di-sarli-documentary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 08:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2013/03/30/carlos-di-sarli-documentary/</guid>
      <description>According to Realidad Bonaerense, there is a new documentary about Carlos di Sarli coming out, directed by Alberto Freinquel. No information about dvd or download edition, but there will be several public viewings in Buenos Aires and in Bahía Blanca, I think. The article mentions several dramatized sequences, which makes me a bit sceptical, but I guess you have to do something if there is little historical material available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Documentary: Eyes Closed -- Ad occhi chiusi</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/11/17/upcoming-documentary-eyes-closed-ad-occhi-chiusi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2010 08:41:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/11/17/upcoming-documentary-eyes-closed-ad-occhi-chiusi/</guid>
      <description>I missed (at least) one on my last post on upcoming movies. This one is an Italian documentary. Here is a link to the film website for more information, and here is a link to the Italian version of the trailer for those who prefer. From the website:
This will be the story of Rossana, a young Italian artist, who rediscovers her femininity by means of the Tango, going through a real metamorphosis which is enhanced by the sparkle in her eyes when telling her story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>El otro camino</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/19/el-otro-camino/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2009 02:50:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/19/el-otro-camino/</guid>
      <description>by i_gallagher
Una vez, tocando con una pequeña orquesta en la escuela de música popular -- eran estudiantes; yo me sentí, tocando con ellos, me sentí cómodo. Pero físicamente cómodo, como cuando uno se siente con la ropa de entrecasa. Y dije: &#34;¿Que me pasa? Y de pronto, la orquesta estaba tocando, esa orquesta de la escuela en un concierto y salen a bailar algunas personas. Y yo ví eso y dije: &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silencio</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/04/25/silencio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2009 13:19:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/04/25/silencio/</guid>
      <description>by entropiK
El que hace bien el silencio, hace bien el tango (Who plays the silence well, plays the tango well)   Osvaldo Requena      My favorite quote from the outstanding Café de los Maestros documentary. I just wanted to watch it all over again as soon as it was finished. ¡Que sentimiento! ¡Que pasión!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 Tangos -- Adios Buenos Aires</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/19/12-tangos-adios-buenos-aires/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2008 17:06:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/19/12-tangos-adios-buenos-aires/</guid>
      <description>The documentary 12 tangos was just released in international version on DVD. It is a documentary, and the Adios Buenos Aires part of the title is somehow more accurate with regards to the content of the film. If you are looking for the Buena Vista Social Club of tango, you will be disappointed. There are no interviews with musicians, and only a few of the oldtimers participate in the orchestra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 tangos</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/01/12-tangos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 11:24:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/01/12-tangos/</guid>
      <description>Just ordered the new documentary 12 tangos. Will be very interesting to see, it also claims to be a Buena Vista Tango Club, so a shootout between 12 tangos and Cafe de los maestros. 12 tangos has a great advantage in being actually available.
I will get back to it later, in the meantime, the trailer:
[youtube]http://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=mrFklWP6dQY&amp;amp;feature=related[/youtube]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lágrima Ríos &amp; Candombe</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/28/lagrima-rios-candombe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2008 22:13:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/28/lagrima-rios-candombe/</guid>
      <description>I just love the name! Lágrima Ríos is a wonderful artistic name, Rivers of tears.. Re tango, no?
My attention was brought to some of her recordings by Michael&amp;rsquo;s music blog, discussing some available recordings of hers. Luckily, I was able to find them both at emusic for instant satisfaction :-) She is featured in the film Café de los maestros, which I have not yet been able to get hold of (but will eventually!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Café de los maestros</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/13/cafe-de-los-maestros/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2008 13:33:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/13/cafe-de-los-maestros/</guid>
      <description>Always looking out for new films about tango, both dance and music, I must say I am really looking forward to this one: Café de los maestros. It has been described as the tango equivalent to the _Buena Vista Social Club. I already got the soundtrack, so I know the music is excellent. Can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see it. _
When oh when will it become available on DVD? It will never be shown on the silver screen where I live I&amp;rsquo;m afraid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confiteria La Ideal en BBC</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/23/confiteria-la-ideal-en-bbc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2008 20:49:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/23/confiteria-la-ideal-en-bbc/</guid>
      <description>Another good documentary about tango. I enjoyed it a lot. Some of the interesting scenes are available on youtube, but the documentary itself was quite hard to get hold of. As far as I could determine, it is not available for sale, not even on ebay, so you better know one of them pirates or use your imagination ;-)
I am quite impressed by how ordinary dancers are able to express what tango means to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>O Ultimo Bandoneón</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/08/21/o-ultimo-bandoneon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2008 18:39:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/08/21/o-ultimo-bandoneon/</guid>
      <description>It is actually possible to get hold of this, but I had to order it from Brazil, so it was with portuguese subtitles, which was - challenging, but a very nice film it was. Recommended.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>El último bandoneón</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/22/la-ultima-bandoneon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2008 10:15:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/22/la-ultima-bandoneon/</guid>
      <description>httpvh://youtube.com/watch?v=eGerxiMniBQ
Maravillosa!
Now where can I get the entire film?
Trailer here:
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>