<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Musicality on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/categories/musicality/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Musicality on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 20:08:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/categories/musicality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Los Estilos Fundamentales del Tango 2 | Fresedo</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2016/09/01/los-estilos-fundamentales-del-tango-2-fresedo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 20:08:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2016/09/01/los-estilos-fundamentales-del-tango-2-fresedo/</guid>
      <description>The video from the Fresedo seminar is up!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Los Estilos Fundamentales del Tango 2 | Julio De Caro</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2016/06/19/los-estilos-fundamentales-del-tango-2-julio-de-caro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2016 20:23:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2016/06/19/los-estilos-fundamentales-del-tango-2-julio-de-caro/</guid>
      <description>The video from the seminar last week on Julio De Caro is up. Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Los estilos fundamentales del tango por Ignacio Varchausky | Alfredo Gobbi</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2015/10/26/los-estilos-fundamentales-del-tango-por-ignacio-varchausky-alfredo-gobbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 19:43:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2015/10/26/los-estilos-fundamentales-del-tango-por-ignacio-varchausky-alfredo-gobbi/</guid>
      <description>The Gobbi seminar video is up!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Los estilos fundamentales del tango por Ignacio Varchausky | Horacio Salgán</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2015/09/19/los-estilos-fundamentales-del-tango-por-ignacio-varchausky-horacio-salgan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2015 15:40:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2015/09/19/los-estilos-fundamentales-del-tango-por-ignacio-varchausky-horacio-salgan/</guid>
      <description>This time with video. Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Los estilos fundamentales del tango por Ignacio Varchausky</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2015/08/23/los-estilos-fundamentales-del-tango-por-ignacio-varchausky/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2015 19:01:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2015/08/23/los-estilos-fundamentales-del-tango-por-ignacio-varchausky/</guid>
      <description>Ignacio Varchausky is doing a series of very interesting seminars on the style of different tango orchestras. Audio recordings of the seminars have been released with links in the facebook comments, and that means an opportunity to listen to them even when very lejos de Buenos Aires. They are in Spanish though, so you need to follow spoken Spanish reasonably well to make any use of it.
Apparently, they build on a seminar similar to the one that inspired this post on how to listen to tango, so you might want to check out that first, if you haven&amp;rsquo;t already.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mickey Mousing</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/06/02/mickey-mousing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2010 19:47:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/06/02/mickey-mousing/</guid>
      <description>It seems to be spreading, a new way of interpreting music in tango. Every so often I hear people rave about some couple&amp;rsquo;s outstanding musicality and more often than not it translates to their mimicking every little plink and plonk in the music with a corresponding movement. Naturally, it requires good knowledge of the song to do this, but does it really demonstrate such great musicality?
I once heard this way of dancing called Mickey Mousing, as it was like this music was often used in animations, many from the 1930s and the 1940s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What does it mean to dance with &#39;good musicality&#39;?</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/01/22/what-does-it-mean-to-dance-with-good-musicality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2010 19:41:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/01/22/what-does-it-mean-to-dance-with-good-musicality/</guid>
      <description>by mhowry
Tango dancers often discuss the importance of dancing to the music, having &amp;lsquo;good musicality&amp;rsquo; etc. But what exactly does it mean to dance musically? I tried noting some possibilities, and since some are very basic, while other are more advanced (and should be used sparingly).
I tried to classify them within the usual trichotomy of beginner/intermediate/advanced, thinking that you have to know the very basics, and you should master basically everything in the intermediate before venturing out into the advanced concepts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cadencia</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/23/cadencia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2009 01:01:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/23/cadencia/</guid>
      <description>by Kanaka&amp;rsquo;s Paradise Life in Hawaii
If you have to ask, you will never know.   _Luis Armstrong when asked &#39;what is jazz?&#39;_    &amp;ndash;You see, that is not the way to make it &amp;lsquo;swing&amp;rsquo; in tango. I was looking out onto the group of people standing around us with question marks painted all over their faces. &amp;ndash;Well, I don&amp;rsquo;t know the right word, but the corresponding to swing in tango.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Death of the Prodigy dancer</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/03/16/death-of-the-prodigy-dancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2009 21:40:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/03/16/death-of-the-prodigy-dancer/</guid>
      <description>by Mickal
Tango is full of nostalgia, even sentimentality. We long for the times that were. Even sentimentality was better in the 40s. How can it be for the real milongueros, who were young in that time?
Not to say it is the same, but the thought struck me the other day. I just bought the new Prodigy album, playing it loud and dancing around the kitchen. (I do this a lot, usually to tango music these days) This was the music of my youth, when we went out to party, that was the best.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The real stuff</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/10/the-real-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2009 15:12:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/10/the-real-stuff/</guid>
      <description>by oed
Ah -- you dance **real** milonga (echte Milonga). After struggling with my milonga for years, this was the ultimate sign I was finally getting somewhere. And one of my favorite compliments ever. I got a tip from the Argentine host to ask this woman to dance, he thought I should dance with someone good. So I did. And was not disappointed. Starting almost right out with a milonga, which would have terrified me only a year earlier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Showing off</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/10/showing-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2008 22:12:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/10/showing-off/</guid>
      <description>by - mika -
Who hasn&amp;rsquo;t been tempted&amp;hellip;
&amp;hellip; to do some flashy moves when someone sitting next to the dance floor watches.
&amp;hellip; to show all the tricks of the trade when getting to dance with a really good dancer
&amp;hellip; to play some obscure gem from the record collection when djing
&amp;hellip; to play some music to be innovative
The problem is, it does not impress anyone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why we never tire of tango music</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/29/why-we-never-tire-of-tango-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2008 22:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/29/why-we-never-tire-of-tango-music/</guid>
      <description>by nadworks
Tango music for the non-argentine 21st century tango lover is often something of an acquired taste. At least for tango dancers. The recordings are old, the music sounds strange, we don&amp;rsquo;t understand the lyrics &amp;ndash; but we love the dance&amp;hellip;
After some time, we get more into the music, it all changes, and we become total fanáticos de tango, we can never get enough of the classics of tango music.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technique vs. Feeling</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/27/technique-vs-feeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2008 21:42:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/27/technique-vs-feeling/</guid>
      <description>by my hovercraft is full of eels
Which one is most important? Technique or dancing with feeling? I sometimes get the impression that tango dancers are divided in two camps, the technique camp and the feelings camp. The first emphasizes the technical matters of the dance, the latter paying solely attention to the feeling. As long as we can hug each other, all is well ;-) Both seemingly ignoring the other point of view completely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the eye of the beholder</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/06/in-the-eye-of-the-beholder/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2008 17:31:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/06/in-the-eye-of-the-beholder/</guid>
      <description>Isn&amp;rsquo;t it funny how we see so different things, even when watching the exact same event?

I remember seeing containers all over the place while we were renovating our appartment, a friend who is an architect and carpenter seemed to literally see through the walls in the house before we bought it. A trained art expert will instantly recognize the work of an artist, an analyst will see through the endless rows of numbers in a spreadsheet&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confiteria La Ideal en BBC</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/23/confiteria-la-ideal-en-bbc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2008 20:49:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/23/confiteria-la-ideal-en-bbc/</guid>
      <description>Another good documentary about tango. I enjoyed it a lot. Some of the interesting scenes are available on youtube, but the documentary itself was quite hard to get hold of. As far as I could determine, it is not available for sale, not even on ebay, so you better know one of them pirates or use your imagination ;-)
I am quite impressed by how ordinary dancers are able to express what tango means to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listening to the music</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/21/listening-to-the-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2008 20:48:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/21/listening-to-the-music/</guid>
      <description>What is good musicality?
Countless workshops are offered, people discuss who is dancing more musical or who doesn&amp;rsquo;t get it. But not easy to define. So without trying to get to the bottom of it, some reflexions are in place.
I heard quite often after dancing for a few years that I was dancing musically, which of course made me happy. Who wouldn&amp;rsquo;t like to dance musically? Of course it could be just to be polite and not mentioning my other more obvious shortcomings, but I think that even if my musicality was not very good or mature, at least I was:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>