<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Interview on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/tags/interview/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Interview on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/tags/interview/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Essence of Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/16/the-essence-of-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2010 19:30:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/16/the-essence-of-tango/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.eltangauta.com/images/ediciones/184_Tapahome.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;When we watched the milongueros dancing years ago, we could perceive the mystery behind what they did, no matter if it was easy or difficult. Therefore, technique has to be understood first, then it can be copied, but the goal is to get to its essence. If you use the word &#34;technique&#34; less in class, and instead use words like &#34;essence&#34; and &#34;sensation&#34;, students can perform the movement with a more natural attitude and will learn faster than if you speak about numbers, diagonals or muscles.

&gt; 
&gt; Javier Rodríguez
&gt; 
&gt; 
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good advice from the maestros. They also talk about the decline of the European tango scene and our fear of the embrace. Read the &lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/9cYFra&#34;&gt;entire interview at El tangauta&lt;/a&gt; (#184 Feb 2010). [EDIT: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eltangauta.com/nota.asp?id=1438&amp;amp;idedicion=0#nota-mas&#34;&gt;Direct link here&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>El Tangauta interviews Chicho</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/16/el-tangauta-interviews-chicho/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2009 03:28:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/12/16/el-tangauta-interviews-chicho/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/12/ElTangauta182-Chicho.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/12/ElTangauta182-Chicho.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ElTangauta182-Chicho&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Another &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eltangauta.com/nota.asp?id=1412&amp;amp;idedicion=0#nota-i&#34;&gt;interesting interview with Chicho&lt;/a&gt;, and he elaborates on some of the same things as in the&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/11/23/interview-with-mariano-chicho-frumboli/&#34;&gt; previous interview&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;[The] milongueros had respect, delicacy and sensibility, it was totally different. I know my role is contradictory, because I also collaborated in generating this young movement. In its moment I got tired of the strict milonguero codes that didn’t correspond with my time and to rebel I tried to make my way. Today I’m a milonguero again (laughter); I’m against the people who do not cabecear (nod), who don’t have codes or respect. The value of tango has been diluted. That is why I say that many dancers are lost, they barely hold on to each other to dance and for two hours like zombies, it is very sad.

&gt; 
&gt; _Mariano &#39;Chicho&#39; Frumboli_
&gt; 
&gt; 
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read the entire interview at &lt;a href=&#34;http://eltangauta.com&#34;&gt;El Tangauta&lt;/a&gt;, you need to register to download the pdf (issue 182). [Edit: It is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eltangauta.com/nota.asp?id=1412&amp;amp;idedicion=0#nota-i&#34;&gt;now online here&lt;/a&gt; (direct link to the english translation)]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Mariano &#39;Chicho&#39; Frumboli</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/11/23/interview-with-mariano-chicho-frumboli/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2009 23:14:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/11/23/interview-with-mariano-chicho-frumboli/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/pktd/2364570952/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/11/chichos-feet.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Chicho’s feet by parakulturado, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/pktd/&#34;&gt; parakulturado&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

&gt; 
&gt; [T]oday there is a new generation that learned to dance 2,3 or 5 years ago, who only know how to do the new styles, the ganchos, the colgadas, but who are not in contact with everything that came before, and I go to the milongas and I see people that know how to move but that don’t know how to dance, people don’t breathe tango like they did before.
&gt; 
&gt; 

&gt; 
&gt; --Mariano &#39;Chicho&#39; Frumboli
&gt; 
&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an interesting &lt;a href=&#34;http://atdrc.com/default.asp?TextDisplay=1&amp;amp;Display=18&#34;&gt;interview with Chicho&lt;/a&gt;, he talks about how he started working with Gustavo Naveira and Fabian Salas, his artistic development and the relationship and tension between the new things that they do and the &amp;lsquo;traditional&amp;rsquo; tango.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is very easy to agree on some of his statements, and he is certainly a dancer I respect, even if I found out that I do not really want to dance like him. I had the pleasure of dancing in front of him for an entire tanda at Niño Bien, and he was dancing very considerately in the social environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found the parts where he discusses the periods with different partners and the corresponding artistic development particularly interesting, also Chicho on his weaknesses and strengths:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

&gt; 
&gt; I believe that my best qualities have to do with my musicality, and obviously my creativity within that realm.  I began as a musician and I continue to be one.  The music is what move me on all levels, I need to feel it in order to be able to dance, and I believe that is visible in my dancing.  And I believe my weakness has to do with my inhibition, I still don’t feel that I have exploited and showed everything I have to show, almost as if I haven’t been able to give myself completely as I would like to.
&gt; 
&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, on dancing with women of different styles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

&gt; 
&gt; I don’t care with what style she dances, what interests me is that in the moment when we are dancing together, that we are having fun together in the moment, I need to feel good next to that person.
&gt; 
&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>