<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Documentary on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/tags/documentary/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Documentary on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 11:43:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/tags/documentary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Last Tango -- Copes y Nieves</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2015/09/10/our-last-tango-copes-y-nieves/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 11:43:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2015/09/10/our-last-tango-copes-y-nieves/</guid>
      <description>Now this looks like something to look forward to:
In „Our Last Tango“ Juan and María tell their story to a group of young tango dancers and choreographers from Buenos Aires, who transform the most beautiful, moving and dramatic moments of Juan and Maria’s lives into incredible tango-choreographies. These beautifully-shot choreographies compliment the soul-searching interviews and documentary moments of the film to make this an unforgettable journey into the heart of the tango.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango Negro, The African Roots of Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2014/04/02/tango-negro-the-african-roots-of-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 20:53:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2014/04/02/tango-negro-the-african-roots-of-tango/</guid>
      <description>Now this looks interesting, a documentary about the African roots of tango. It&amp;rsquo;s featuring Juan Carlos Cáceres (of &amp;ldquo;Tango Negro&amp;rdquo; fame), of which I&amp;rsquo;m a great fan. One of the best concerts I ever attended was with Cáceres and band and Facundo &amp;amp; Kely Posadas performing.
You can read a bit more about the documentary at the ADIFF film festival pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango Film Club</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/04/19/tango-film-club/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2009 15:26:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/04/19/tango-film-club/</guid>
      <description>by atomicjeep
I was planning to write a separate post for each of those, but I never seem to find the time&amp;hellip; The recent posts by tangocommuter prompted me to write up this list of my favorite tango films. I never was all that interestesd in instructional videos, but films about the culture I find fascinating. In our small community we arranged public showings in an informal tango film club to make these gems available to the rest of the community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 Tangos -- Adios Buenos Aires</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/19/12-tangos-adios-buenos-aires/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2008 17:06:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/19/12-tangos-adios-buenos-aires/</guid>
      <description>The documentary 12 tangos was just released in international version on DVD. It is a documentary, and the Adios Buenos Aires part of the title is somehow more accurate with regards to the content of the film. If you are looking for the Buena Vista Social Club of tango, you will be disappointed. There are no interviews with musicians, and only a few of the oldtimers participate in the orchestra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>El último bandoneón</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/22/la-ultima-bandoneon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2008 10:15:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/22/la-ultima-bandoneon/</guid>
      <description>httpvh://youtube.com/watch?v=eGerxiMniBQ
Maravillosa!
Now where can I get the entire film?
Trailer here:
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>