<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Julio Amp Corina on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/tags/julio-amp-corina/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Julio Amp Corina on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/tags/julio-amp-corina/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Body parts</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/22/body-parts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2009 20:02:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/22/body-parts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/balakov/763594852/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1072/763594852_838e7d276f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Stacked Focus Cogs by Balakov, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/balakov/&#34;&gt; Balakov&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Privates can be tough. Very useful, but tough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our first trip to Buenos Aires, my wife and I took privates with Julio &amp;amp; Corina, and we worked on the basics. Of course. We learnt a lot, but it was so much to think about. So much we did wrong. So much to fix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my own sake, it felt like they deconstructed my whole body, just to leave the parts on the floor. For me to pick up and bring back for the next lesson. I felt like I could not dance at all for about a week. (Which was maybe not so far from the truth, as I had not really been dancing for that long.) Even at the prácticas, I felt out of place, unable to relax and enjoy the dance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took some time to reassemble, but it was definitely worth the effort. In reaching the next level, one&amp;rsquo;s awareness of the things that need to be fixed, can give some headache, but when you finally get there, it really improves your dancing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The general feeling has been repeated with various other teachers over the years, but with more experience it takes less effort to put myself together after groundbraking changes. Well &amp;ndash; maybe not less effort. But it breaks me down for a shorter time. And I am better prepared in advance. Maybe the errors I have to fix are not as grave as they used to be. I like to think of it that way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>