<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cliche on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/tags/cliche/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cliche on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2009 01:47:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/tags/cliche/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango in music videos</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/29/tango-in-music-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2009 01:47:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/29/tango-in-music-videos/</guid>
      <description>Old but good: tango (the dance) is used to sell musical forms that may have little in common with tango. These examples show that cliches can be treated elegantly and with humour. Not to say that the dancing is necessarily very elegant&amp;hellip;
My favorite: the Van Damage. The gotan one is quite cool, too.
          </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nice film tangos</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/20/nice-film-tangos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2009 20:44:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/20/nice-film-tangos/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;600&amp;rdquo; caption=&amp;ldquo;From Happy Together&amp;rdquo;][/caption]
Fortunately, tango is not always portrayed as completely kitsch in films. So I found that a handful of very nice films, with equally nice tango mandated a post of its own. These are all highly recommended, tango or not.
First Happy together by Wong Kar-Wai. He is actually one of my favourite directors, and uses tango as one way to tell us about the relationship and love between two people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why the Chileans love tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/16/why-the-chileans-love-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 23:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/16/why-the-chileans-love-tango/</guid>
      <description>by f _ d a y
--Do you know why the Chileans love tango? I have made a couple of Chilean friends lately, and that means opportunities to practice my castellano. In all countries, the residents make jokes about their neighbours, and one of my new friends told me this one.
Another invited us to his asado (or bbq as they say here), and kept insisting on me saying** **tu, not vos like in Argentina.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clichés</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/06/cliches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2008 10:31:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/06/cliches/</guid>
      <description>Ever since I started dancing, the topic of tango clichés has fascinated me. The rose in mouth, castanets, head flicks, dramatic poses are all parts of what usually pops into people&amp;rsquo;s heads when they hear the word tango. Where did they come from, and why did they stick? Going through a lot of Hollywood production at least gives a partial answer, and Rudolph Valentino is one of the people to blame, the rose in mouth appears in the film Blood and sand, where he plays a bullfighter, while the film he dances the tango is _Four horsemen of the apocalypse.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>