<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cliche on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/tags/cliche/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cliche on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/tags/cliche/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango in music videos</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/29/tango-in-music-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2009 01:47:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/29/tango-in-music-videos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Old but good: tango (the dance) is used to sell  musical forms that may have little in common with tango. These examples  show that cliches can be treated elegantly and with humour. Not to say that the dancing is necessarily very elegant&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorite: the Van Damage. The gotan one is quite cool, too.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/7aPwOC7cZCo&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;



&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/cEYtdfDKLvc&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;



&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/HyY2MP-1Va4&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;



&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/3zD9W9SZj9w&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;



&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/fIG2cjckxj8&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nice film tangos</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/20/nice-film-tangos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2009 20:44:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/20/nice-film-tangos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;ldquo;&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;600&amp;rdquo; caption=&amp;ldquo;From Happy Together&amp;rdquo;]&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.timezone.fr/uploaded_images/happy_together_tony_leslie_8_d302bfe6a3de421aa6c37d9b4627eca7-798476.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;From Happy Together&#34; /&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, tango is not always portrayed as completely kitsch in films. So I found that a handful of very nice films, with equally nice tango mandated a post of its own. These are all highly recommended, tango or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0118845/&#34;&gt;Happy together&lt;/a&gt; by Wong Kar-Wai. He is actually one of my favourite directors, and uses tango as one way to tell us about the relationship and love between two people. One of whom work for some time in a tango bar in Buenos Aires. Not in a cliched fashion, which is quite a feat, given &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/05/24/tango-in-popular-culture/&#34;&gt;what is out there&lt;/a&gt;. Come to think of it, I probably should see this film again sometime soon myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the eccentric characters in the Almodóvaresque &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0310001/&#34;&gt;Piedras&lt;/a&gt; by Spanish director Ramón Salazar, actually go to a milongas. The man, who is an Argentine brings a women, and he talks to her about the Argentine saying &amp;lsquo;Sacando viruta al piso&amp;rsquo;.  As far as I can remember, the dancing in the Madrid milonga was quite &amp;lsquo;authentic&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0436445/&#34;&gt;No suis là pour être aimé&lt;/a&gt; (Not here to be loved) almost made it to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/04/19/tango-film-club/&#34;&gt;film club post&lt;/a&gt;, as the main characters in this movie actually take tango lessons. And the lessons have a profound impact on the characters&amp;rsquo; lives. In addition, they watch a show by Geraldine and Javier. So plenty of tango, and a nice film. How she came to fall for him is still a mystery, though. Never underestimate the power of tango, I guess&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it is indeed possible. There must be more that I am unaware of or have forgotten. What are your favourites?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why the Chileans love tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/16/why-the-chileans-love-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 23:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/16/why-the-chileans-love-tango/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/f_day/241328208/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/89/241328208_273ac0db29.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Tricolor. / by f _ d a y, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/f_day/&#34;&gt; f _ d a y&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;--Do you know why the Chileans love tango?&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have made a couple of Chilean friends lately, and that means opportunities to practice my castellano. In all countries, the residents make jokes about their neighbours, and one of my new friends told me this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another invited us to his asado (or bbq as they say here), and kept insisting on me saying** **&lt;strong&gt;tu&lt;/strong&gt;, not &lt;strong&gt;vos&lt;/strong&gt; like in Argentina. I, on the other hand, was always dreaming of speaking Spanish with an Argentine accent, so I kept my vos, thankyouverymuch. Even if he admitted the meat they used was Argentinian, he also claimed the Chileans made much better asados than the Argentines. In lack of any Argentines there, he was constantly picking on me. It was like that all night, quite amusing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;--Because in every tango, at least one Argentine suffers or dies.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clichés</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/06/clich%C3%A9s/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2008 10:31:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/06/clich%C3%A9s/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever since I started dancing, the topic of tango clichés has fascinated me. The rose in mouth, castanets, head flicks, dramatic poses are all parts of what usually pops into people&amp;rsquo;s heads when they hear the word tango. Where did they come from, and why did they stick? Going through a lot of Hollywood production at least gives a partial answer, and Rudolph Valentino is one of the people to blame, the rose in mouth appears in the film &lt;em&gt;Blood and sand&lt;/em&gt;, where he plays a bullfighter, while the film he dances the tango is _Four horsemen of the apocalypse. _The tango in &lt;em&gt;Some like it hot&lt;/em&gt; must have reinforced the image further into the public memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what lies behind the clichés, do they reveal something of interest, which we may overlook, just because the cliché is so easily dismissed? Could the tango have more important influence from the flamenco than is commonly acknowledged? The rose at least played a role in the real tango porteño in the way that the orchestra of Pugliese used a single rose on the piano during their performances to mark the maestro&amp;rsquo;s absence while he was held in prison for his political beliefs. The head flicks seem to come from the ballroom version of tango, and to my knowledge they have little relation to the &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; tango. Many of the dramatic poses, though, could have their roots in early tango moves such as cortes and quebradas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/images/pugliese_ausencia.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Osvaldo Pugliese in absentia&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, many sayings about tango, are often dismissed as being &lt;em&gt;merely clichés&lt;/em&gt;, but I have found that many of them go deeper than we first think. That tango is really about dancing for the woman is one such statement. Often heard, rarely seen outside Buenos Aires, is my experience. Even by those who say it.  I heard women talk about this for years, &lt;em&gt;X dances for himself&lt;/em&gt; etc. It took me many years before I started noticing what they were &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; talking about. But when I finally realized, it transformed my way of seeing tango, both my own and others&amp;rsquo;. It may appear superficial, a subtle adjustment, a cliché. In fact, what is needed is a fundamental change. Starting to dance for the woman, rather for one self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now read those &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/index.php/2008/06/01/gavito-dixit/&#34;&gt;Gavito quotes&lt;/a&gt; again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>