<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cliche on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/categories/cliche/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cliche on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 19:02:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/categories/cliche/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dancing to the music of time</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2016/01/29/dancing-to-the-music-of-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 19:02:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2016/01/29/dancing-to-the-music-of-time/</guid>
      <description>But among so many lessons, with so many teachers, I find contradictions and clichés. My feet are shovels; my feet are paintbrushes. My feet must caress the floor, intensely; my feet are too firm against the floorboards. My embrace must be close, like the embrace of a lover; my embrace must leave space for the tension between us. I am a cat, I am a lion, I am a horse-rider. Carina tells me I need to work on my ochos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valentino</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/09/16/valentino/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2011 20:49:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/09/16/valentino/</guid>
      <description>I have this weird interest in the popular culture image of tango, for a large part constituted by various more or less successful renditions of the tango on the silver screen.
As a matter of fact I have been looking for this particular rendition since I saw still photos in the tango book by Collier et al. And thanks to Tangocommuter, I realized Valentino (1977) by Ken Russell was released on DVD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Panther Tango (1967)</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/28/the-panther-tango-1967/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2009 02:26:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/28/the-panther-tango-1967/</guid>
      <description>Now someone is having a ball, evidently&amp;hellip; (From an ad for rum in LIFE - Nov 3, 1967)
Anyone knows what the Panther Tango at the Plaza in 1928 refers to? It sure can&amp;rsquo;t be Pantera tanguera by Cuarteto Almagro (on the album Hemisferios)&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rose in mouth</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/13/rose-in-mouth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2009 22:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/13/rose-in-mouth/</guid>
      <description>by alyssathiele
The tango cliché of dancing with a rose in the mouth is quite fascinating. It is everywhere, and everybody doing argentine tango wants absolutely nothing to do with it. But where does it come from?
I have often seen it associated with the silent movie star Rudolph Valentino, and suggested that it first appeared in the movie Four Horsemen of the Apocalypse (1921). So being curious, I had to check this out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the eye of the beholder</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/06/in-the-eye-of-the-beholder/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2008 17:31:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/06/in-the-eye-of-the-beholder/</guid>
      <description>Isn&amp;rsquo;t it funny how we see so different things, even when watching the exact same event?

I remember seeing containers all over the place while we were renovating our appartment, a friend who is an architect and carpenter seemed to literally see through the walls in the house before we bought it. A trained art expert will instantly recognize the work of an artist, an analyst will see through the endless rows of numbers in a spreadsheet&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>