<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cliche on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>https://simbatango.github.io/categories/cliche/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cliche on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="https://simbatango.github.io/categories/cliche/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Dancing to the music of time</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2016/01/29/dancing-to-the-music-of-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 19:02:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2016/01/29/dancing-to-the-music-of-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.intelligentlifemagazine.com/sites/default/files/0116IL_PL_WIN_04-web.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;But among so many lessons, with so many teachers, I find contradictions and clichés. My feet are shovels; my feet are paintbrushes. My feet must caress the floor, intensely; my feet are too firm against the floorboards. My embrace must be close, like the embrace of a lover; my embrace must leave space for the tension between us. I am a cat, I am a lion, I am a horse-rider. Carina tells me I need to work on my ochos. “There is no such thing as an ocho,” says Oscar Casas, at our next lesson. There is only a change in direction, that’s all.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.intelligentlifemagazine.com/places/dancing-to-the-music-of-time&#34;&gt;refreshingly unclichéd take on dancing tango in Buenos Aires&lt;/a&gt;. (In Argentina, tango is a way of life, as Tara Isabella Burton discovered when she went to Buenos Aires, following in her grandmother’s footsteps, from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.intelligentlifemagazine.com/places/dancing-to-the-music-of-time&#34;&gt;Intelligent Life Magazine&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valentino</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2011/09/16/valentino/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2011 20:49:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2011/09/16/valentino/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/M1fourAkSJU&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I have this weird interest in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/05/24/tango-in-popular-culture/&#34;&gt;popular culture image of tango&lt;/a&gt;, for a large part constituted by various more or less successful renditions of the tango on the silver screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a matter of fact I have been looking for this particular rendition since I saw still photos in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Tango-Dance-Story-Simon-Collier/dp/0500279799/&#34;&gt;tango book by Collier et al&lt;/a&gt;. And &lt;a href=&#34;http://tangocommuter1.blogspot.com/2011/08/for-change.html&#34;&gt;thanks to Tangocommuter&lt;/a&gt;, I realized &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0076868/&#34;&gt;Valentino&lt;/a&gt; (1977) by Ken Russell was released on DVD. Well, sort of, like many of Valentino&amp;rsquo;s silents, it was actually a print on demand edition, no extras, no subtitles etc, just the movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Valentino early catched my attention as the iconic Hollywood tango hero, and he was a fascinating character &amp;ndash; but we&amp;rsquo;ll stick to the tango for now.  One thing that puzzled me in&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/02/14/rose-in-mouth/&#34;&gt; tracing back the origins of some of the tango cliches&lt;/a&gt;, was that people were talking dismissively of the tango of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rodolfo_Valentino&#34;&gt;Rodolpho Valentino&lt;/a&gt;, but his dancing wasn&amp;rsquo;t at all that bad. Bear in mind that there are some really awful tango scenes in the history of film, and that the tango of the turn of the century must have been rather different from the tango of the forties and fifties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, I remember the milongueros talk about the ridiculous tango of Valentino in&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0094106/&#34;&gt; Tango: Bayle Nuestro&lt;/a&gt;, which was released in 1988. After watching Nureyev&amp;rsquo;s Valentino, some additional pieces found their place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tangocommuter actually warned me about not having too high expectations. Now, where I live, renting is not really an option, all out of the mainstream has to be ordered on the internet. I can live with that, although it means I end up having a rather eccentric dvd collection. Russell apparently wasn&amp;rsquo;t too happy with the result himself, calling it &lt;a href=&#34;http://entertainment.timesonline.co.uk/tol/arts_and_entertainment/film/article2870480.ece&#34;&gt;his biggest mistake&lt;/a&gt;. I have to confess I haven&amp;rsquo;t really watched many of his films, but if you ask me, he comes off as something of a prick that regrets not picking the script that won several Oscars and his supposedly introspective  list of mistakes includes gems such as &amp;ldquo; Never give an unreliable member of the crew a second chance&amp;rdquo;. Maybe I just don&amp;rsquo;t get the British sense of humour, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how it applies to himself. I would choose Valentino every time, and other people have successfully made&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0045152/&#34;&gt; a classic&lt;/a&gt; out of related material. (Apparently they both quote/parody one particular love scene of Valentino&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0015145/&#34;&gt;Monsieur Beaucaire&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, Russell&amp;rsquo;s work hasn&amp;rsquo;t really aged well, it&amp;rsquo;s a typical 70s flick, and not in a good way. It&amp;rsquo;s not really historically correct either, which is ok I guess, but I would think Valentino&amp;rsquo;s life had enough drama as it were. And Nureyev isn&amp;rsquo;t really an outstanding actor. Ballet dancer: yes. Tango dancer: not really.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which brings me to the missing piece of the puzzle. Or at least it will serve as my working theory for now. Isn&amp;rsquo;t it much more likely that the milongueros of the eighties had Russell&amp;rsquo;s/Nureyev&amp;rsquo;s Valentino in mind when they spoke of Valentino, considering it ran only a few years earlier, while &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0012190/&#34;&gt;the silent movie was from 1921&lt;/a&gt;. I somehow doubt &amp;lsquo;The four horsemen&amp;rsquo; was shown regularly in Argentina after the sound movie arrived around 1930.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Possibly, the image of Hollywood tango is actually Russell&amp;rsquo;s image of Hollywood&amp;rsquo;s image of the tango. Now how is that for distorted tango?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Panther Tango (1967)</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/09/28/the-panther-tango-1967/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2009 02:26:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/09/28/the-panther-tango-1967/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/09/panthertango.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/09/panthertango.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;panthertango&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now someone is having a ball, evidently&amp;hellip;  (From an ad for rum in &lt;a href=&#34;http://books.google.com/books?id=VUkEAAAAMBAJ&amp;amp;pg=PA12-IA1&amp;amp;dq=tango&amp;amp;as_pt=MAGAZINES#v=twopage&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;f=false&#34;&gt;LIFE - Nov 3, 1967&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone knows what the Panther Tango at the Plaza in 1928 refers to? It sure can&amp;rsquo;t be Pantera tanguera by Cuarteto Almagro (on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tangostore.com/cds_detalle.php?idx=2284&#34;&gt;the album Hemisferios&lt;/a&gt;)&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rose in mouth</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/02/13/rose-in-mouth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2009 22:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/02/13/rose-in-mouth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alyssathiele/272762443/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/95/272762443_db45eead93.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mouth Rose by alyssathiele, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/alyssathiele/&#34;&gt; alyssathiele&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tango cliché of dancing with a rose in the mouth is quite fascinating. It is everywhere, and everybody doing argentine tango wants &lt;em&gt;absolutely nothing to do with it&lt;/em&gt;. But where does it come from?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have often seen it associated with the silent movie star Rudolph Valentino, and suggested that it first appeared in the movie &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0012190/&#34;&gt;Four Horsemen of the Apocalypse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; (1921). So being curious, I had to check this out. Which was not so easy, as the Four Horsemen was not easily obtainable on DVD. Until I one day found out it was published as a bonus disc on the Valentino documentary &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Rudolph-Valentino-Great-Lover-Documentary/dp/B000EGDCGO/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=dvd&amp;amp;qid=1230081144&amp;amp;sr=8-2&#34;&gt;The Great Lover&lt;/a&gt; (The documentary turned out to be quite interesting as well, leading to more Valentino movies for me).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most famous scene from The Four Horsemen is when the young hero in the film dances tango in a bar in La Boca. This scene is quite interesting, and while not exactly correct, the tango in this scene is much better than what people usually associate with Hollywood tango in general and with Valentino&amp;rsquo;s tango in particular. Just don&amp;rsquo;t try those sacadas with spores on&amp;hellip;   But no rose in mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also a scene from Paris, where our hero dances tango in a much more sober fashion. And a scene involving a rose, but nobody ever puts it into anyone&amp;rsquo;s mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/02/vlcsnap-503547.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/02/vlcsnap-503547.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So where does the rose and the Hollywood cliché then come from? It is certainly established in the Hollywood comedy _&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0053291/&#34;&gt;Some Like it Hot&lt;/a&gt;__ (1959)_&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; and Tom Lehrer sings about it in his song _Masochism Tango. _Both of these also suffer from a severe mix-up with flamenco, featuring castanets, which to my knowledge has never been used in Argentine tango. Possibly the flamenco &lt;em&gt;tangos&lt;/em&gt; have something to do with the mix up, or perhaps the rule that Argentines had to perform in gaucho costumes in Paris in the early 20th century.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/02/vlcsnap-505672.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/02/vlcsnap-505672.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter another Valentino movie. Featuring flamenco, a whip, a bullfighter, and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;a rose in the mouth&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;_. _The movie is &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0012952/&#34;&gt;Blood And Sand&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; (1924), and Valentino plays the matador, the bullfighter. It features a scene where a woman puts a rose in her mouth after doing a flamenco. So this cliché probably stems from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who first mixed the two together I have no idea, but I can&amp;rsquo;t say I think it is fair to blame it all on Valentino.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the eye of the beholder</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2008/11/06/in-the-eye-of-the-beholder/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2008 17:31:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2008/11/06/in-the-eye-of-the-beholder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Isn&amp;rsquo;t it funny how we see so different things, even when watching the exact same event?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://flickr.com/photos/rykerstribe/2589081910/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/11/eye-of-the-beholder.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;In the eye of the beholder&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember seeing containers all over the place while we were renovating our appartment, a friend who is an architect and carpenter seemed to literally see through the walls in the house before we bought it. A trained art expert will instantly recognize the work of an artist, an analyst will see through the endless rows of numbers in a spreadsheet&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we see people dancing, we notice different things. Where one sees excellent and clear lead, the other sees excessive adornos. Where one sees innovative moves, another sees boring repetition, where one sees old clichés, another sees elegance, musicality and smootheness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe we in many regards see what we are looking for, and what we find familiar. In other words, when we are working on some element in our own dance, we are more likely to see who masters this particular element in other dancers. And easily fail to see other qualities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, being able to notice excellence in others, requires a certain skill level. To be able to judge musicality, you need to know what is musical. To determine who has the better walk, you need to know how the walk &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be. And so on. It has taken years and months for me to be able to determine by sight whether someone is a good dancer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, on occations I have been able to spot a good dancer before she even changed her shoes. I would not say I am able to say exactly what it is that gives a good dancer away, but the way they walk is something I always pay attention to. High heels can be faked. the way you walk in them can&amp;rsquo;t. Only the good dancers got it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question is, do we see the same walk?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://flickr.com/photos/rykerstribe/2589081910/&#34;&gt;Photo&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;http://flickr.com/photos/rykerstribe/&#34;&gt;rykerstribe&lt;/a&gt;@flickr, &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/deed.en&#34;&gt;CC-licensed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>