<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Three Partners on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/tags/three-partners/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Three Partners on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/tags/three-partners/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Fundamentals of Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/04/14/three-fundamentals-of-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2010 21:13:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/04/14/three-fundamentals-of-tango/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/pforret/4489579181/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4001/4489579181_e399aebb7b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Brussels Tango Festival - Saturday -Exhi by Peter Forret, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/pforret/&#34;&gt; Peter Forret&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever I hear the postulate that everything in tango is either a step forward, a step backwards or a side step, I get a little irritated. I know what they mean, and it&amp;rsquo;s not that it is entirely wrong, it&amp;rsquo;s rather that it is incomplete, and it tends to send people off in a very step oriented direction. But &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2008/11/09/nuevo-tools-nuevo-problems/&#34;&gt;I have written about that before&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me instead remind you of three quite different fundamentals in the tango, or maybe rather governing principles. It is a very important insight.  Simple, yet profound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dancing the tango, you have three partners. And tango is about embrace, embrace and embrace. In order to dance well, you need to embrace them all:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;embrace-your-partner&#34;&gt;Embrace your partner&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is all about the woman.  No partner, no dancing. Respect your partner, take care of her and protect her, make it a pleasant experience for her. Listen to her, feel her presence, wishes and desires&amp;hellip; In return, she will make you both beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;embrace-the-music&#34;&gt;Embrace the music&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The movement has to come from the music. Without music we would just stand there, hugging each other. That can be nice, too, of course, but it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be dancing. Listen to what the music tells you and find your inspiration there. Then embrace the music and dance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;embrace-the-dance-floor&#34;&gt;Embrace the dance floor&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are not alone on the floor. We are dancing with the other couples on the floor as well. Respect their space, keep moving at a reasonable pace and avoid dangerous movements. (The &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/KISS_principle&#34;&gt;KISS principle&lt;/a&gt; is apt here.)  In return you will feel the energy of the floor. Sometimes people complain about dancers not socializing enough, but as I see it, sharing the floor is also socializing. Embrace your fellow dancers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Naveira-Salas model may help you to learn steps. Which can be useful. &lt;em&gt;To learn to dance, you need to learn how to embrace your three partners.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS: I am talking about social dancing here. For performance/stage dancing, I guess you could substitute dance floor with audience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>