<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tango Theory on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/categories/tango-theory/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tango Theory on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/categories/tango-theory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Los Estilos Fundamentales del Tango Series 2 | Elementos Básicos</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2016/05/22/los-estilos-fundamentales-del-tango-series-2--elementos-b%C3%A1sicos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2016 09:07:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2016/05/22/los-estilos-fundamentales-del-tango-series-2--elementos-b%C3%A1sicos/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/5cF6SvvYXLU&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Ignacio Varchausky is at it again with a new series of his excellent &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/groups/451570588378843/&#34;&gt;Los Estilos Fundamentales del Tango&lt;/a&gt;. Go there if you&amp;rsquo;re in Bs As, or listen/watch after the fact like the rest of us otherwise. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Impossibility  of Re-Creating the Tango of Times Gone By</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2014/03/27/the-impossibility--of-re-creating-the-tango-of-times-gone-by/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2014 21:29:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2014/03/27/the-impossibility--of-re-creating-the-tango-of-times-gone-by/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/oldonliner/179768787/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/67/179768787_c2cf90edc0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;First Impressionism by OldOnliner, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/oldonliner/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/oldonliner/&#34;&gt;OldOnliner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a paradox concerning my relationship with tango, and maybe with tango itself. On one hand, I want to learn from the sources, learn the &amp;lsquo;true&amp;rsquo; tango.  If that even exists. On the other hand, I want to see progress, to move on, and to find or invent &amp;lsquo;my own&amp;rsquo; tango. Which may not exist, either. This tension between a certain nostalgia and  the Sisyphean quest for the authentic, and the longing for progress, a rational approach, the tension between being controlled by the tango and taking control over the tango is at once frustrating and tantalizing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are, inescapably, products of our time. The way we dress, the way we talk and the way we move has changed in numerous ways over the years, not to mention growing up on a different continent. How the times we live in manifest themselves in people was beautifully captured by this interesting &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newyorker.com/online/blogs/movies/2014/03/why-its-impossible-to-recreate-a-film-shot-by-shot.html&#34;&gt;reflection upon the remake of the classic movie &amp;lsquo;Psycho&amp;rsquo;  in an article in The NewYorker&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;The way that people carry themselves—their posture, their gestures, and even the micro-gestures, the sense of sharpness or tremulousness, the brusqueness or smoothness of movements, the pointedness or curves of joints, the decisive rapidity or easy offhandedness with which they move, and the precision or meander of speech—conveys more about their personality and their times than the overt signifiers of fashion or vocabulary.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/11/06/tailored-for-tango/‎&#34;&gt;mentioned once before&lt;/a&gt; how I was fascinated by the refined, elegant movements  of&amp;rsquo;El Flaco&amp;rsquo; Dany when he lit a cigarette. This fascination is despite me generally finding the the habit of smoking despicable. Still there was something about about his way, the micro-gestures, the way he carried himself that stays with me. I would never be able to make his way of lighting a cigarette my own, even if I tried. Even if I worked hard, the best I could hope to achieve would be a superficial resemblance, a bleak copy. A fraud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We may learn from the best, the ones that lived during the golden age of tango, or at least from those few who remain.  We may keep trying, but we will never dance their tango. We are left to find our own.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The origins of &#39;Tango Nuevo&#39;</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/05/01/the-origins-of-tango-nuevo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 17:55:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/05/01/the-origins-of-tango-nuevo/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/SW9BNE9o7Q0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;When I heard about the Dinzel book, I thought it was sort of a curious project. Working through all possibilities of tango steps, charting them out in elaborate diagrams with circles and arrows in all directions demonstrating the vast space of choreographic possibilites. I had a look at the book at a friend&amp;rsquo;s place several years ago, but it felt somehow disconnected to how I experienced the dance. This was rather early in my days of tango though, so maybe I would get more out of it at a later point. (If anyone of you got the book, I would love to have a picture/scan for illustration purposes of this post.) [EDIT: You can see an &lt;a href=&#34;http://shytanguero.blogspot.com/2009/10/once-upon-time.html&#34;&gt;example of one diagram here&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks to Chris for providing another diagram, shown below (click on the image to see the full resolution version):]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://img534.imageshack.us/img534/2171/dinzelpasobasetangoavan.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://img534.imageshack.us/img534/2171/dinzelpasobasetangoavan.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never took lessons with the Dinzel myself, but I heard from friends that they would often do exercises to explore the different possibilities from a given position, sort of like a game. Only after a friend that was going to Gustavo Naveira&amp;rsquo;s classes with us told us she started taking lessons with his old maestro, did I make the connection. In fact Gustavo also states in  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.danceoftheheart.com/naveirainterview.htm&#34;&gt;an interview&lt;/a&gt; by Brian Dunn that he was a student of the Dinzel:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;[W]hen I was in my twenties, about 1981, I started studying with Rodolfo Dinzel. I was one of his best students within that course, and he took special notice of me and worked me very very hard.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is actually a rather interesting interview, so I encourage you to read it all. It also motivates the search for a new approach to learning tango:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

&gt; 
&gt; You know, in my study of tango, often I would encounter a &#34;tango master&#34;, and even if you approached them respectfully, they would have an attitude of, &#34;I know everything, you are sh**, don&#39;t bother me&#34;. This is a typical attitude from an earlier way of looking at tango. So it was often very difficult to learn useful things about tango from them.
&gt; 
&gt; 
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fabián Salas elaborates on this in &lt;a href=&#34;http://totango.net/salas2.html&#34;&gt;another interesting interview&lt;/a&gt; by Keith Elshaw:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

&gt; 
&gt; At one point, I remember that we were very concerned about all these dancers dying - all these milongueros, all these teachers, they were dying. One after the other, three or four in one year. It was catastrophic. So I said, &#34;Gustavo, we are on our own; there is hardly anybody any more and if there is, we can&#39;t do much about it because it&#39;s hard to talk to these people. We have to start learning from ourselves. We have to start bringing the process along and the only way to do it is getting together. Why don&#39;t we join with the people that we consider are good dancers that have something to offer with this idea of, you know, changing - exchanging things? Getting together and practice in a serious way. Analyze.&#34;
&gt; 
&gt; 
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe anybody who has been in the tango world for a while can agree that there are some great egos out there, so this is easy to believe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems clear to me that Gustavo inherited the analytical approach of the Dinzel and took it to another level with his collaboration with Fabián Salas and Mariano &amp;ldquo;Chicho&amp;rdquo; Frumboli. And watching this clip of the Dinzel couple, I think I can recognize some of the ways or habits of Gustavo Naveira, for instance the way he is turning his foot when he is waiting with no weight on it, where most (?) other dancers use a flat foot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS: Unfortunately, youtube has just disabled the sound on this video, making it a lot less interesting to watch.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The structure of a tango, choreography and how it might improve your dancing</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/28/the-structure-of-a-tango-choreography-and-how-it-might-improve-your-dancing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2009 01:46:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/28/the-structure-of-a-tango-choreography-and-how-it-might-improve-your-dancing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/aperte/489430756/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/230/489430756_1e20e6391a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Meditation Labyrinth by aperte, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/aperte/&#34;&gt; aperte&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you prefer your naïve, pure emotional interpretation of the tango, you might not want to read this. If, on the other hand you think that knowing a little about how tango music is organized might increase the breadth or depth of your musical appreciation, then this could be for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like &lt;a href=&#34;http://tangocommuter1.blogspot.com/2009/08/three-minute-question.html&#34;&gt;Tangocommuter writes&lt;/a&gt; in the discussion of how a tango became approximately three minutes long, a prototypical tango has the structure ABA:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Most tangos, and most songs generally, are A-B-A in structure. It&#39;s a structure people seem to like, it works well musically and in a song. 16-bar blues follow much the same pattern. In practice, we get three segments of around 16 bars each. 16 bars to a minute, mas o menos, 48 bars start to finish. 48 bars of four beats each, that&#39;s 192 beats in three minutes, which is... 64 beats a minute. A familiar number. 192 heart beats to a tango.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best example to look for in my knowledge is the orchestra of Carlos Di Sarli, which adhered fairly strictly to a regular scheme for all his tangos.  A musician I met in Buenos Aires told me that Di Sarli was known as the master of something I think he called the quadratic form or something similar. The 16 bars (or measures as they are often called) can again be divided into four phrases of 4 bars of two strong and two weak beats each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, what is more interesting than this little arithmetic is that these 4 sections of 4 bars form a structure of theme and variations inside the main structure of the tango. Gustavo Naveira called this &amp;lsquo;call&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;response&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;question&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;answer&amp;rsquo;, I don&amp;rsquo;t recall exactly. My musician friend objected to this and called them variations.  Whatever you want to call it, it is there, and you can hear it and use it in your dancing if you like. With the second being a response to the first and the fourth being a response to the third, there is also some sort of nested structure of dialogue between the first two phrases and the two last. Very neat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, creating a choreography is an art in itself, and sadly there are very few that master this art &amp;lsquo;a full&amp;rsquo;, as they would say in Buenos Aires. Taking this structural knowledge into the choreography would be a good framework to build a choreography around, one would imagine. In my own attempts to do semi choreography dances, matching the main turning points of the music was always a major concern, and that is why I find it so surprising (and disappointing) that so many performances seem to pay no attention at all to the general structure of the song they are performing to. Not even the main structure of main theme (A or AA), the contrasting theme (B) and the final variation (A again). I mean, not even reflecting the development from beginning to end. Just unmotivated throwing out of crowd pleasing steps in all directions from the start. I don&amp;rsquo;t get it. It is soooo boring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this seems to be a disease which is prominent with the followers of the maestro that first taught me about this in a dance context. I find it somewhat ironic that the dancers most concerned with the &amp;lsquo;structure of tango&amp;rsquo; (the dance) seem to overlook completely the structure of tango (the music). Maybe it will come later in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/01/16/reinvention/&#34;&gt;reinvention&lt;/a&gt; project?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we are not doing choreography, you may protest. True, but still you have to listen to the music, and knowing just a little about what to listen for, might improve your listening (and thus dancing) experience. One gringo that was also taking the same seminar with Naveira found that part of the class utterly uninteresting  &amp;ndash; clearly you can already hear this, he said. Which is sort of true for many dancers, on the other hand, watching many people dance, one has to wonder&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I do not suggest that you start counting over and over again while you are out at the milongas dancing with your friends and strangers in the night, far from it. However, it can be useful to listen carefully for the specific developments of the music during one tango and try dancing to it. It should come as no surprise that a large number of step combinations taught are actually matching exactly one phrase in tango (8 strong beats or four measures/bars). Try it with the normal basic step if you still remember it&amp;hellip; Also it can be useful to try combining walking exercises (which you still do regularly, no?) with phrasing exercises. For example doing one kind of adornos for one full phrase. No less and no longer. Exactly one phrase. I suggest you try with Di Sarli, pick any song basically, as he conforms fairly closely to this scheme. We have good experience with walking our student through these exercises, even without much explanation, as moving with the phrases gives an intuitive understanding of the music, which you will eventually bring to the dance floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Jorge Dispari talked about how people &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/05/10/on-circulation/&#34;&gt;used to interpret the music in a more similar fashion&lt;/a&gt; in the golden age of tango, I suspect this might be part of what he was talking about (the A(A)BA structure). I everyone is saving their giros and extra stuff for the final variation, then everybody stops progressing at the same time, and nobody gets hurt.. Unfortunately I never had the opportunity to take his music seminar, so this remains my theory or speculations if you prefer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, comments and corrections from more knowledgeable readers are most welcome&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On circulation</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/11/on-circulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2009 00:57:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/11/on-circulation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/pdcawley/2220859/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/1/2220859_55540cbb1f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mallory Bugatti by pdcawley, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/pdcawley/&#34;&gt; pdcawley&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ms Hedgehog is researching the dynamics of flow in the ronda, comparing with traffic and pondering about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://mshedgehog.blogspot.com/2009/05/floorcraft-and-length-of-tangos.html&#34;&gt;importance of song length&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While song length can probably have some influence, I believe other factors are much more significant. And it is kind of hard to perform real experiments, even though she deserves credit for the attempt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Jorge Dispari, the flow on the dance floors of Buenos Aires used to be much better than today. At Canning, for instance, during the peak hours, the circulation almost stops completely. While it is still possible to dance, it is not as enjoyable as when there is good circulation. And if he is to be believed, there was more people on the floor at that time as well, so floors being more crowded is not the reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He explained it by two factors:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dancers today don&amp;rsquo;t have the necessary skills&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dancers interpreted the music more in the same fashion earlier&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it is impossible for me to compare earlier times in Buenos Aires today, my experience from milongas all over the world largely supports the main idea that navigation skills and interpreting the music in a similar fashion improves the flow on the dancefloor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is why: I know from teaching and observations on practicas and milongas support that &amp;lsquo;too few&amp;rsquo; have the ability to dance a) in a straight line b) on the spot c) change between  these when necessary. Dancers also observe the need to keep moving and not moving counter to the line of dance. Which I attribute to a lack of skill. If they know how, but choose not to, I attribute it more to musical interpretation. If dancers cannot keep within their own space, they are likely to cause a congestion or at least interrupt the other dancers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If dancers are generally in agreement that they need to move at  certain speed around the dance floor, congestion is less likely. Anyone stopping while the others keep moving easily clogs the entire floor in less than a minute,  which is easy to show by experiment (yes I have done this on several occations). When dancers are generally in agreement of which parts in the music are for moving around/walking, and which are for more stationary repertoire like giros (the final variation for instance), the flow improves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hmm &amp;ndash; a little more work, and we might have the proof here :-). Assume we have enough dancers to achieve a crowded dance floor. (Too much space, and everybody can move wherever they like, and no significant interaction occurs.) Lack of skills imply congestion. Heterogenous musical interpretation implies congestion. Skills and homogenous musical interpretation are necessary, but not sufficient conditions for good flow of the ronda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course,  you could show experimentally that the three minute theory is true, at best you could show that it is a necessary condition given sufficiently crowded floor. I do believe it occurs, but I believe it mainly covers the corner case where both conditions above are satisfied, but the floor is extremely crowded and good dance music with songs significantly longer than three minutes being played.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Say we have all three confirmed by experiment, how do we establish their relative importance? One could do a large survey of milongas, estimating the skills of dancers etc and do a regression, I suppose. For me, it is enough to know that the tree minute song limit is pretty much satisfied for all golden age tango music, so it is hard to imagine when it would be significant. I.e actually affecting the flow of the ronda. (If you play other music with longer songs, I belive other factors than song length destroys the ronda flow.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As to how to improve the skills and musical interpretation, I don&amp;rsquo;t have the answer. Not allowing unskilled dancers is not exactly how to achieve a milonga with good attendance these days, I&amp;rsquo;m afraid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If only it were possible to create a milonga ouside Bs As where you could feel that the entire dance floor was dancing and breathing together, making the old adage true: You have three dance partners in tango: 1) Your partner 2) The music 3) The dance floor.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The dual nature of tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/04/the-dual-nature-of-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2009 02:49:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/04/the-dual-nature-of-tango/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/airpark/491171868/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/204/491171868_17541f8e50.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Angel &amp;amp; Devil by airpark, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/airpark/&#34;&gt; airpark&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I often wonder why tango is so attractive, why I (and others with me) got so obsessed with it. Why we never tire of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In part, I think it has to do with the infinite depth that can be found within it, and part of the source of this I believe is the dual nature of tango, or its apparent paradoxes. Making it difficult to explain or describe what tango is and isn&amp;rsquo;t. Conflicting forces that are present simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Sorrow and happiness.
Confidence and humbleness.
Quiet and loud.

Calmness and violence.
Domination and submission.
Understatement and exagerration.

Elegance and crudeness.
Simplicity and complexity.
Playfulness and sincerity.

Modernity and tradition.
Decency and frivolity.
Proximity and distance.

Suspense and release.
Old and new.
Life and death.

Me -- and you.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/12/evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2009 08:51:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/12/evolution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kaptainkobold/215227655/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/74/215227655_e7fce47abc.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Darwin Studying Barnacles by Kaptain Kobold, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/kaptainkobold/&#34;&gt; Kaptain Kobold&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the year of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charles_Darwin&#34;&gt;Darwin&lt;/a&gt; this year. In a radio show, different scientists were discussing Darwin&amp;rsquo;s impact on their fields. The art historian made a point out of the fact that after Darwin, people no longer expected the evolution to be linear, or directed towards a specific goal. Always improving. It became clear that modern art would change, take different forms. The direction of change would be an other matter entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why we never tire of tango music</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/29/why-we-never-tire-of-tango-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2008 22:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/29/why-we-never-tire-of-tango-music/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/nadworks/219864640/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/63/219864640_5bb97d5c4a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;MY FAVOURITE MUSIC... by nadworks, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/nadworks/&#34;&gt; nadworks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tango music for the non-argentine 21st century tango lover is often something of an acquired taste. At least for tango dancers. The recordings are old, the music sounds strange, we don&amp;rsquo;t understand the lyrics &amp;ndash; but we love the dance&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some time, we get more into the music, it all changes, and we become total fanáticos de tango, we can never get enough of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://tejastango.com/classic_tangos.html&#34;&gt;classics of tango music&lt;/a&gt;. Why do we never get tired of listening to these old recordings, often transferred from old, scratchy 78s, since &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.totango.net/rca.html&#34;&gt;the masters were burnt&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will often hear tango lovers rave about the &lt;em&gt;complexity&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;richness&lt;/em&gt; of tango music. So let us investigate a bit further what is the source of this richness. The title of the first record by the orchestra Escuela de tango, &lt;em&gt;De contrapunto&lt;/em&gt; gives us the first clue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One way to categorize music is by the musical textures, and the three main categories are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Monopohonic&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Homophonic&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Polyphonic&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monophony&#34;&gt;Monophonic&lt;/a&gt; music consists of a single melody line, and is the simplest form of musical texture. Perhaps the best known example in western music is the Gregorian chant. The monophonic music is also the easiest to understand or interpret.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Homophony&#34;&gt;Homophonic&lt;/a&gt; music is slightly more complex, as it consists of a principal melody line accompanied by a chordal accompaniment. Perhaps a bit surprisingly, it is the most recent &amp;ldquo;invention&amp;rdquo;, as it basically did not occur in music created earlier than the end of the 16th century. It was used in a lot of romantic music for increased clarity and thus emotional impact, in contrast with the most complex form, polyphony.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polyphony&#34;&gt;Polyphonic&lt;/a&gt; music is the kind that is the most demanding of the listener. Several melodic lines, or &amp;ldquo;voices&amp;rdquo;, are present at the same time, forming harmonies as they go. To appreciate this, you may have to disregard some parts of the music, and the melodic line (horizontal) will become apparent. This gives a different listening experience than &amp;ldquo;just listening&amp;rdquo; to all the sounds present at the same time (vertical). Depending on which lines you choose, the same piece may be experienced somewhat differently each time. And this is what is actually meant when dancers talk about dancing to different instruments. All voices need not be present at the same time, of course, and some melodic lines will move from instrument to instrument, so dancing different voices would be a more precise definition of what you are actually doing. (The clue from de contrapunto is that &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Counterpoint&#34;&gt;counterpoint&lt;/a&gt; is one special case of polyphonic music)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To quote Aaron Copland in the book &lt;em&gt;What to listen for in music&lt;/em&gt; (on which this post leans heavily),  &amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;repeated hearings keep up your interest better than music of homophonic texture. Even supposing that you do not hear all the separate voices equally well, there is every likelihood that when you return to it again, there will be something different for you to listen to. You can always hear it from a different angle.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pop music springs out from the homophonic tradition from the romantic music. While being popular music, tango from the golden age has a certain quality that you will not generally find in today&amp;rsquo;s popular music, the polyphony. And that also explains why it is much less interesting to dance to pop music than the real stuff. It is simply not enough to throw in some bandoneón samples or having more or less the right rhythm. More on that in a later post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The polyphonic nature of most tango music means there are a lot of ways to listen to the same tune, you can discover something new time after time. And it makes the music sound fresh every time. And thus the dance stays fresh as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nuevo tools, nuevo problems</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/09/nuevo-tools-nuevo-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2008 21:07:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/09/nuevo-tools-nuevo-problems/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/11/hammer.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/11/hammer.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Models can be very useful. By making a simplified version of the world that we are able to grasp, we may learn something about the world outside the model as well. This approach has proven very successful in a lot of areas, and is also applied to tango.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a danger associated with model building, as everyone working with them should know, and that is to mistake the model for reality. To forget that you had to do some simplifications to make comprehendable model out of the apparenly chaotic world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also tends to shape the way we think about the world we modeled. Which can be fine, as that is part of the purpose. However, it assumes we got all important aspects covered by the model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two sayings that illustrate the danger of using a hammer as your model:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If your only tool is a hammer, everything looks like a nail.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you can&amp;rsquo;t solve it with force, use a larger hammer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-nuevo-theory&#34;&gt;The nuevo theory&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tango nuevo methodology, or rather theory, was developed be Naveira and Salas, and is quite influenced by the Dinzels, of which Naveira I think was a student. It is quite interesting, as it breaks everything down to small pieces, and explain very complex sequences as sequences of these basic building blocks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can be very useful when you want to explain a sequence, but I always wonder when a teacher says something like &amp;ldquo;There only exist six steps in tango&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; If they really mean it, or just use it as a simplification.  What would be more precise would be something convoluted like &amp;ldquo;According to the Naveira-Salas model (or tango nuevo), all (or rather a large number of) steps can be broken down to six basic movements&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; So I understand why people do not say that teaching. But I am afraid many people actually believe that you can get to the bottom of tango by understanding these principles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can use it to analyze and describe an astonishingly large number of tango sequences, but you also miss some.  Mistaking the model for reality, you never realize what your model does not cover. When you look the model inventors dancing, and the same with their students, there are some obvious omissions in their vocabulary, which I leave as an exercise for the reader ;-) I don&amp;rsquo;t assume that the guys that figuered out this neat theory to believe it to be a theory of everything, but I am afraid quite a few of their students do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ironically, since this theory is so concerned with breaking up old steps/patterns, and exploring &amp;lsquo;new&amp;rsquo; ones, the users of the theory all seem to be very occupied with &amp;ndash; steps. And there is a lot more to tango than steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another problem withe the dance created by using this model, is that everything is equally good, it seems. Since it is all about exploring &amp;lsquo;new&amp;rsquo; possibilities, these possibilities should not be ruled out. But in the evolution of the dance, quite a lot of possible steps and sequences have already been tried out and thrown in the garbage, either because was not nice, or if it didn&amp;rsquo;t feel good. Remaining is an enormous set of steps/sequences that allow for a uniquely complex dance. The tango student should learn not only which are the possibilities, but also which work well and which don&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To sum up, the nuevo theory can be very helpful in learning sequences, but it is dangerous if you don&amp;rsquo;t know its limitations. As with all powerful tools: handle with care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://flickr.com/photos/ppdigital/2054989998/&#34;&gt;Photo&lt;/a&gt; : &lt;a href=&#34;http://flickr.com/photos/ppdigital/&#34;&gt;Darren Hester&lt;/a&gt;@flickr, &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.0/deed.en&#34;&gt;CC-licensed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>