<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tango Culture on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/tags/tango-culture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tango Culture on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2009 15:26:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/tags/tango-culture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango Film Club</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/04/19/tango-film-club/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2009 15:26:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/04/19/tango-film-club/</guid>
      <description>by atomicjeep
I was planning to write a separate post for each of those, but I never seem to find the time&amp;hellip; The recent posts by tangocommuter prompted me to write up this list of my favorite tango films. I never was all that interestesd in instructional videos, but films about the culture I find fascinating. In our small community we arranged public showings in an informal tango film club to make these gems available to the rest of the community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Urban dance</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/24/urban-dance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2009 20:09:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/24/urban-dance/</guid>
      <description>by lrargerich
Tango is and always was a very urban culture. The dance even more so. Sometimes visitors to Buenos Aires that are tango dancers somehow expect everybody they meet to be a dancer, and taxi drivers to know all the milongas by name.
Not so.
Even in Buenos Aires, tango dancing is very much a niche activity, and the world of the milongas is very small even in the great city with millions of inhabitants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empty movement</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/04/empty-movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2009 20:43:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/04/empty-movement/</guid>
      <description>by bass_nroll
As you probably know, tango is not merely a dance. Among other things, the dance is also a language. It is not like a language, because the different movements have different meanings, which can be used for actual communication. It is not a metaphor. However, when people copy movements without realizing the underlying meaning, the result is movements with no meaning. Empty movement.
Or even worse, you may be saying something without knowing it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Un beso...</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/26/un-beso/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2009 17:33:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/01/26/un-beso/</guid>
      <description>by Kevin Steele
Buenos Aires is not like home. And when in Rome, drive like the Romans&amp;hellip;
And the Argentines kiss when they meet. Better get used to it.
(...) would lean over, ready to commit the act that, I thought, was reserved only for girlfriends and, on occasion, family. This guy used a few months it seems, but has written a really entertaining account of the argentinian kissing habits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yes honey, but is it tango?</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/04/yes-honey-but-is-it-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2008 15:58:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/12/04/yes-honey-but-is-it-tango/</guid>
      <description>Roy Lichtenstein: Girl with Ribbon (1965)
There is always a lot of fuzz in the tango communities of the world about what is the right tango. And rightly so. There is good and there is bad tango.
But in the middle of these heated arguments, we need to remind ourselves of one thing. Tango culture is rich. There is a lot of diversity in tango. Tango is not only dance. It is also music for listening.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>