<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quality on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>https://simbatango.github.io/tags/quality/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Quality on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="https://simbatango.github.io/tags/quality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Quality and snobs</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/09/05/quality-and-snobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2009 02:30:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/09/05/quality-and-snobs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/96dpi/1139662917/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1213/1139662917_7b4b1bab22.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Swing by 96dpi, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/96dpi/&#34;&gt; 96dpi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tangocommuter1.blogspot.com/2009/08/tango-al-fresco-was-its-usual-amiable.html&#34;&gt;Food&lt;/a&gt; (and &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/04/26/stuff-without-the-stuff/&#34;&gt;drinks&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;a href=&#34;http://mshedgehog.blogspot.com/2009/08/egg-and-chips-pugliese.html&#34;&gt;metaphor&lt;/a&gt;s for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.limericktango.com/2009/08/nigell-lawson-on-henry-james/&#34;&gt;tango&lt;/a&gt; seem to be popular lately, so here in another one: My brother and I have two very distinct wine quality stories that I find very amusing when seen together. Each involves a young woman, at the age where going to parties and flirting with alcohol is at its most exciting, somewhere just before or just after going to university.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#1: A rather simple red wine was served with the main dish at a dinner party with the entire class of that year. She tasted it, called for the waiter and asked for another bottle. &amp;ndash;This I cannot drink. Only thing was, there was nothing wrong with the wine. Except that is was cheap. And the new bottle of the same, cheap wine was no better, of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#2: At a party in the place of a friend&amp;rsquo;s parents, she opened the bottle, poured into a glass and tasted. Then she walked right over to the sink and &amp;ndash; to the astonished looks from her friends &amp;ndash; emptied the entire bottle into the sink.  &amp;ndash;This I cannot drink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How this applies to tango is left as an exercise to the reader&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the eye of the beholder</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2008/11/06/in-the-eye-of-the-beholder/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2008 17:31:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2008/11/06/in-the-eye-of-the-beholder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Isn&amp;rsquo;t it funny how we see so different things, even when watching the exact same event?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://flickr.com/photos/rykerstribe/2589081910/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/11/eye-of-the-beholder.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;In the eye of the beholder&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember seeing containers all over the place while we were renovating our appartment, a friend who is an architect and carpenter seemed to literally see through the walls in the house before we bought it. A trained art expert will instantly recognize the work of an artist, an analyst will see through the endless rows of numbers in a spreadsheet&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we see people dancing, we notice different things. Where one sees excellent and clear lead, the other sees excessive adornos. Where one sees innovative moves, another sees boring repetition, where one sees old clichés, another sees elegance, musicality and smootheness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe we in many regards see what we are looking for, and what we find familiar. In other words, when we are working on some element in our own dance, we are more likely to see who masters this particular element in other dancers. And easily fail to see other qualities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, being able to notice excellence in others, requires a certain skill level. To be able to judge musicality, you need to know what is musical. To determine who has the better walk, you need to know how the walk &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be. And so on. It has taken years and months for me to be able to determine by sight whether someone is a good dancer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, on occations I have been able to spot a good dancer before she even changed her shoes. I would not say I am able to say exactly what it is that gives a good dancer away, but the way they walk is something I always pay attention to. High heels can be faked. the way you walk in them can&amp;rsquo;t. Only the good dancers got it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question is, do we see the same walk?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://flickr.com/photos/rykerstribe/2589081910/&#34;&gt;Photo&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;http://flickr.com/photos/rykerstribe/&#34;&gt;rykerstribe&lt;/a&gt;@flickr, &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/deed.en&#34;&gt;CC-licensed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>