<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tango Fanatics on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/categories/tango-fanatics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tango Fanatics on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2009 22:26:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/categories/tango-fanatics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Zapatillas de tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/02/zapatillas-de-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2009 22:26:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/02/zapatillas-de-tango/</guid>
      <description>Guess what was in the mailbox for our little son the other day? A nice pair of &amp;lsquo;shoes&amp;rsquo; made by a friend back home. She has specialized in this kind of baby footwear perfect for developing small feet and new walking skills.
All hand made, she makes an effort in always finding a new twist, theming them with butterflies, elephants or monsters. Or creating the very first tango shoes for a tangobaby.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The dual nature of tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/04/the-dual-nature-of-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2009 02:49:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/04/the-dual-nature-of-tango/</guid>
      <description>by airpark
I often wonder why tango is so attractive, why I (and others with me) got so obsessed with it. Why we never tire of it.
In part, I think it has to do with the infinite depth that can be found within it, and part of the source of this I believe is the dual nature of tango, or its apparent paradoxes. Making it difficult to explain or describe what tango is and isn&amp;rsquo;t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gingerbread milonga</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/10/gingerbread-milonga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2008 16:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/10/gingerbread-milonga/</guid>
      <description>Some friends (also tango maniacs, of course) made this just before Christmas a couple of years ago. A really tasty milonga it was! Welcome to Club Grizelle!



I released the photos under a Creative Commons license, so feel free to use them for whatever non-commercial purpose you like :-) I appreciate a link and a comment if you find use for it.
Maybe they can be useful for invitations to your Christmas milonga?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>