<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cabeceo on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/tags/cabeceo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cabeceo on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2011 18:54:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/tags/cabeceo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of the Cabeceo Part III: When in Rome...</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/10/20/the-art-of-the-cabeceo-part-iii-when-in-rome/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2011 18:54:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/10/20/the-art-of-the-cabeceo-part-iii-when-in-rome/</guid>
      <description>by Bsivad
As the music of the cortina fades out, she glances over the tables on the opposite side of the dance floor. Refreshes her memory of where the different dancers she watched on the floor are seated. Preparing to try and catch the eye of one of her favorite partners as the music starts for the next tanda.
Her eyes move along the tables, she is nodding to her self, yes, yes, maybe&amp;hellip; her eyes reach the corner of the dance floor, and she quickly moves on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of the Cabeceo Part II: Failing Gracefully</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/07/18/the-art-of-the-cabeceo-part-ii-failing-gracefully/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2011 20:17:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/07/18/the-art-of-the-cabeceo-part-ii-failing-gracefully/</guid>
      <description>There she was, the girl with the blue dress. I noticed here before, but I never managed to catch her eye. Her seat was all the way over at the other corner, so I started walking between the tables. As I approached slowly, I tried to establish eye contact. She changed her position. A slight turn of the head. I got closer. She looked down. Opened her purse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of the Cabeceo Part I: Are You Flirting With Me?</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/10/23/the-art-of-the-cabeceo-part-i-are-you-flirting-with-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2010 13:45:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/10/23/the-art-of-the-cabeceo-part-i-are-you-flirting-with-me/</guid>
      <description>by pedrosimoes7
&amp;ndash;Nobody asks me to dance, complained our Canadian classmate. We were sitting at our table in the Buenos Aires Golf Club, overlooking the dark course and the city skyline. We started chatting about the cabeceo, surely she knew the habit of the Porteño dancer to ask by catching a potential partner&amp;rsquo;s eye and confirming with a slight nod towards the pista?
Of course she didn&amp;rsquo;t. On the contrary, she brought her habit of avoiding to meet the eye of men she did not know, avoiding unwanted attention and flirts from strangers, as she did back home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your most underrated skill set</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/11/03/your-most-underrated-skill-set/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2009 16:28:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/11/03/your-most-underrated-skill-set/</guid>
      <description>Eye contact. According to American Airlines. Funny coincidence I saw this ad just a couple of days before we left for Buenos Aires, as we were flying AA. The photo is taken in San Telmo if I am not mistaken.
Does this mean AA know the cabeceo?
They canceled our flight, by the way, and the car seat did not fit in the seat, and they put us in the very back, so I can&amp;rsquo;t say we were very happy with them, hence no temptation to think it was destiny or anything&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bright side</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/11/bright-side/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2009 02:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/11/bright-side/</guid>
      <description>by renatela
It occured to me, that the topic of whom we dance with stirs up a lot of negative feelings. Or rather, with whom we do not dance. We are all concerned about being rejected, having someone not ask us to dance, or saying no when we ask (using the cabeceo, of course!).
A milonga is a place to enjoy ourselves, and everybody should dance with whoever they want to dance with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Competition</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/03/01/competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 09:04:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/03/01/competition/</guid>
      <description>by Alaz-
For some reason, people often assume I dance competitions when they hear I&amp;rsquo;m a tango dancer. Not so, I tell them. The only competition is to get to dance with the best dancers.
And while I still believe that to be true to some extent, a friend (who is an excellent dancer himself), put me on a better track. Why is it so important to dance with the &amp;ldquo;best&amp;rdquo;, he asked.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>