<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cabeceo on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>https://simbatango.github.io/tags/cabeceo/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cabeceo on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="https://simbatango.github.io/tags/cabeceo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of the Cabeceo Part III: When in Rome...</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2011/10/20/the-art-of-the-cabeceo-part-iii-when-in-rome.../</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2011 18:54:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2011/10/20/the-art-of-the-cabeceo-part-iii-when-in-rome.../</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/brettdavis/3506498664/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3656/3506498664_7dc0959756.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Romulus and Remus by Bsivad, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/brettdavis/&#34;&gt; Bsivad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the music of the cortina fades out, she glances over the tables on the opposite side of the dance floor. Refreshes her memory of where the different dancers she watched on the floor are seated. Preparing to try and catch the eye of one of her favorite partners as the music starts for the next tanda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her eyes move along the tables,  she is nodding to her self, yes, yes, maybe&amp;hellip; her eyes reach the corner of the dance floor, and she quickly moves on. Not him. She saw him on the dance floor, and with that embrace, if that is even the right word, no. Not a chance. She looks down to make it clear. She has to be careful about that part of the room, it seems. Better not cause any misunderstanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subtlety is not his force, apparently. She can see his gesturing in her peripheral view, doing her best to ignore him. But it&amp;rsquo;s too late. He is coming closer. She picks up her purse. She knows exactly where she got every single item, nevertheless she starts moving methodically between them, checking that each is in its designated place. Travel-sickness pills, mints, magnifier, spare stockings, paper towels, hand disinfectant&amp;hellip;.  He stops in front of her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;He:&lt;/strong&gt; Listen, here in Buenos Aires, he says with a  broad grin, we ask a woman to dance using our eyes&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**She: **I know&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;He:&lt;/strong&gt; So we don&amp;rsquo;t have to come up to the table to ask&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**She: **I know&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;He:&lt;/strong&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s called the cabeceo&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He tilts his head to one side and smiles again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;She:&lt;/strong&gt; I know&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She speaks without moving an inch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;He:&lt;/strong&gt; If you want to dance with me, you have to look at me and smile, you know&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He grins again and stretches out his hand for hers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;She:&lt;/strong&gt; I know. &lt;em&gt;No. Gracias.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She forces herself to make a brief smile and returns to her inventory listing. Now, where did I put that bottle of insect repellent?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of the Cabeceo Part II: Failing Gracefully</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2011/07/18/the-art-of-the-cabeceo-part-ii-failing-gracefully/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2011 20:17:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2011/07/18/the-art-of-the-cabeceo-part-ii-failing-gracefully/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/8o5IWOKl2gA&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;There she was, the girl with the blue dress. I noticed here before, but I never managed to catch her eye. Her seat was all the way over at the other corner, so I started walking between the tables. As I approached slowly, I tried to establish eye contact. She changed her position. A slight turn of the head. I got closer. She looked down. Opened her purse. I walked on until I passed her and continued to the Men&amp;rsquo;s room. Refused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some days later, I was back in the same milonga. There she was. This time closer to my table, sitting with her girlfriend, whom I had also noticed before. Fortunately, her friend accepted my invitation. I met her at the corner of  the wonderful parquet dance floor as the place started to get really packed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked her back to the table with the frozen blue dress and returned to my own. From the corner of my eye, I watched the two of them discussing vividly, glancing over in my direction. The moment of truth. Too bad I would not hear the verdict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Di Sarli intrumental. I scanned the crowd for a suitable partner. Two eyes met mine. With a subtle nod, the contract was written and I walked towards the table. The blue dress got up and we headed for the dance floor. Hora Pica &amp;ndash; peak hour &amp;ndash; and no other option than keeping it simple. Walking in an embrace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Random meetings with strangers in the night. Most are quickly forgotten. Others stay with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several years later, on a different continent. There is something familiar with that girl. I walk over to her table to say hello. She remembers. She goes dancing with some other guy while I chat with a mutual friend.  Then she returns. Di Sarli Instrumental.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our eyes meet again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HT illustration video: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.limericktango.com/2011/07/ode-au-tango/&#34;&gt;Limerick tango&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of the Cabeceo Part I: Are You Flirting With Me?</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2010/10/23/the-art-of-the-cabeceo-part-i-are-you-flirting-with-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2010 13:45:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2010/10/23/the-art-of-the-cabeceo-part-i-are-you-flirting-with-me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/pedrosimoes7/60010574/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/32/60010574_149e48d8af.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rita N by pedrosimoes7, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/pedrosimoes7/&#34;&gt; pedrosimoes7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;Nobody asks me to dance, complained our Canadian classmate. We were sitting at our table in the Buenos Aires Golf Club, overlooking the dark course and the city skyline. We started chatting about the cabeceo, surely she knew the habit of the Porteño dancer to ask by catching a potential partner&amp;rsquo;s eye and confirming with a slight nod towards the pista?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course she didn&amp;rsquo;t. On the contrary, she brought her habit of avoiding to meet the eye of men she did not know, avoiding unwanted attention and flirts from strangers, as she did back home. That is effectively the same as wearing a sign saying you&amp;rsquo;re not interested in dancing, and that habit had be brought to an end in the milongas. Instead, watching attentively and gently transmit the intent of watching out for dancers, is the way to go. If dancing is what you&amp;rsquo;re after, of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the golf club, the women wore furs, black dresses and pearls, and mostly went with their suit-clad husbands, who were in turn occupied with taking care of their women or occasionally a close friend in their company. Yet there also were also people interested in dancing with people outside their own table&amp;hellip; Our classmate headed over towards the bar, where she kept her eyes open for dancing opportunities. It didn&amp;rsquo;t take long before she was out on the floor. And on the floor she remained for the rest of the night, dancing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your most underrated skill set</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/11/03/your-most-underrated-skill-set/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2009 16:28:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/11/03/your-most-underrated-skill-set/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/11/eye-contact.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/11/eye-contact.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;eye-contact&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Eye contact. According to American Airlines. Funny coincidence I saw this ad just a couple of days before we left for Buenos Aires, as we were flying AA. The photo is taken in San Telmo if I am not mistaken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does this mean AA know the cabeceo?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They canceled our flight, by the way, and the car seat did not fit in the seat, and they put us in the very back, so I can&amp;rsquo;t say we were very happy with them, hence no temptation to think it was destiny or anything&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bright side</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/05/11/bright-side/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2009 02:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/05/11/bright-side/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/renatela/265244280/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/81/265244280_c0a856c744.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;half full or half empty? by renatela, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/renatela/&#34;&gt; renatela&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It occured to me, that the topic of whom we dance with stirs up a lot of negative feelings. Or rather, with whom we do not dance. We are all concerned about being rejected, having someone not ask us to dance, or saying no when we ask (using the cabeceo, of course!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A milonga is a place to enjoy ourselves, and everybody should dance with whoever they want to dance with. Why on earth would you want do dance with someone that would prefer not dancing with you, anyway?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always try to remember that dancing with someone is not a right, it is a privilege.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the next time someone accepts your invitation or asks you to dance. -Hurray! With me! How lucky I am to get to dance with you. Skip one heart beat,  then dance!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS: It happened to me yesterday, even if it was only on the living room floor&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Competition</title>
      <link>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/03/01/competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 09:04:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>https://simbatango.github.io/2009/03/01/competition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/azarov/755359154/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1302/755359154_19898fe183.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;4944 by Alaz-, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/azarov/&#34;&gt; Alaz-&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some reason, people often assume I dance competitions when they hear I&amp;rsquo;m a tango dancer. Not so, I tell them. The only competition is to get to dance with the best dancers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while I still believe that to be true to some extent, a friend (who is an excellent dancer himself), put me on a better track. Why is it so important to dance with the &amp;ldquo;best&amp;rdquo;, he asked. Is not the point to dance with someone you may give a nice experience? And he was absolutely right, of course. So it is better to think of compatibility rather than ability. We have different strengths and weaknesses, and value different qualities in our partners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that is one reason I find the cabeceo so wonderful. It enables you to make sure you only dance with people that would actually like to dance with &lt;strong&gt;you&lt;/strong&gt;. Having a tango star accept a dance out of mercy and feeling her bored disconnectedness through an entire tanda would be unbearable for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for convenience, I still use the catch phrase for my non-tango friends. And in a sense it is still valid. It is a competition between me and the other guys: who will be the most likely to give the lady a good dance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>