<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2009 14:18:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful foobar2000 formatting strings</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/useful-foobar2000-formatting-strings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2009 14:18:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/useful-foobar2000-formatting-strings/</guid>
      <description>Formatting for djing TINT $num(%barcode%,14)-$num($max(1.%disc%),2)-$num(%track%,2)  Date To display dates from tango.info properly (only confirmed dates with correct formatting)
$if2($greater($strstr(%date%,&#39;--&#39;),0),$date($left(%date%,10)))  Album To get album names including catalognumber and artist, e.g. &amp;lsquo;CTA261 Adolfo Carabelli Vol.1 (1931-1933)&amp;lsquo; I use this formatting string with the %album_pubcode% and %album_name% and %artist% from tango.info:
$replace($replace(%catalognumber%,&#39; &#39;,),&#39;-&#39;,) %artist% %album%  Use the above with the automatically fill values tool from the properties dialogue. Choose source &amp;lsquo;Other&amp;rsquo; and set the above as source.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tagging with MusicBrainz Picard</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/tagging-with-musicbrainz-picard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2008 22:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/tagging-with-musicbrainz-picard/</guid>
      <description>As your tango collection grows, the need to get more accurate and consistant meta information increases. To tag your music from an online database greatly reduces your effort.
I prefer using MusicBrainz Picard, as it provides data for my non-tango music as well. The tango.info database provides a wealth of information and a guide for masstagging.
To combine MusicBrainz Picard with genre and recording dates from tango.info, you can use these plugins for MusicBrainz Picard:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ripping CDs for the tangoDJ</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/ripping-cds-for-the-tangodj/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2008 21:48:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/ripping-cds-for-the-tangodj/</guid>
      <description>Windows For Windows, I would recommend dbPoweramp, foobar2000 or EAC. Both support AccurateRip, which makes sure your rip is good (provided it already exists in the database). A new and interesting project is CUETools which also supports error correction if the disc is in their database (unfortunately not so likely with most tango cds at this time).
Both CUETools and foobar2000 support checking previously ripped tracks against the AccurateRip database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TangoDJ</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/tangodj/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2008 20:58:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/tangodj/</guid>
      <description>Useful online resources for the tangoDJ:
Discussion list TangoDJ mailing list
About tango music Stephen Brown&amp;rsquo;s pages about tango music
Michael Lavocha&amp;rsquo;s guide to tango music
About audio formats Hydrogenadio
Where to buy tango music Tango store (Zival&amp;rsquo;s)
Tango music at emusic</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foobar2000 for the TangoDJ</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/foobar2000-for-the-tangodj/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2008 20:57:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/foobar2000-for-the-tangodj/</guid>
      <description>About Foobar2000 Foobar2000 is a lightweight audio player that is excellent for the tangodj on Windows. Free as in beer and quite usable out of the box, the possibilities for customizations are endless.
Prelistening For prelistening, install two instances of the player, and configure one for each sound device. If the sound from the internal sound card is good (which is often the case with recent laptops), you can use a usb headset, which is cheaper than buying an extra soundcard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/about-simba/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2008 17:15:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/about-simba/</guid>
      <description>A tango dancer since 1998&amp;frasl;1999, I have been consumed by learning, dancing, teaching and djing as well as community building in my small tango community.
Always thinking a lot about the tango and why it means so much to me, but not always time to write or discuss with the equally tango crazy, I have had the intention to blog for some time, but after I became a father quite recently, there is much less time for dancing, but some time for blogging in between.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>