<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tango In Film on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/categories/tango-in-film/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tango In Film on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/categories/tango-in-film/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Last Tango -- Copes y Nieves</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2015/09/10/our-last-tango----copes-y-nieves/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 11:43:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2015/09/10/our-last-tango----copes-y-nieves/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now this looks like something to look forward to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;In „Our Last Tango“ Juan and María tell their story to a group of young tango dancers and choreographers from Buenos Aires, who transform the most beautiful, moving and dramatic moments of Juan and Maria’s lives into incredible tango-choreographies.  These beautifully-shot choreographies compliment the soul-searching interviews and documentary moments of the film to make this an unforgettable journey into the heart of the tango.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&#34;http://- See more at: http://widehouse.org/film/our-last-tango/&#34;&gt;more about Our Last Tango (Un tango más) here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/138545957&#34;&gt;Link to the trailer.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fermin, Glorias del Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2014/10/06/fermin-glorias-del-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2014 20:44:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2014/10/06/fermin-glorias-del-tango/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/ondemand/fermin&#34;&gt;http://vimeo.com/ondemand/fermin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/ondemand/fermin&#34;&gt;Fermin, Glorias del Tango is now available for rental at Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;. Looks nice, I think. I haven&amp;rsquo;t had time to watch it, and I sort of wait for the download that was supposed to come with my Kickstarter support. Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EDIT: I worked it out with Oliver Kolker. Apparently I missed an email that was sent to all backers. Oliver promptly gave me access to the film and I experienced no further problems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glorias del Tango -- New Tango Feature Film</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2013/08/07/glorias-del-tango----new-tango-feature-film/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2013 20:58:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2013/08/07/glorias-del-tango----new-tango-feature-film/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s3.amazonaws.com/ksr/assets/000/748/554/5cd5f02c2d97cf5712aaa1fbabe8e5c4_large.jpg?1373918116&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gloriasdeltango.com/&#34;&gt;This new project&lt;/a&gt; looks interesting, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/70415751/be-a-part-of-tango-history-make-this-movie-happen&#34;&gt;you can support it on kickstarter&lt;/a&gt;. Not sure I believe the story, but the flashbacks look promising. On the other hand, it sounds much more believeable than &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0283897/&#34;&gt;Assasination Tango&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&#34;Glorias del Tango&#34; is an ambitious and exciting feature film that will end the decade-long silence of tango on the silver screen.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to it. Time to revive the &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/04/19/tango-film-club/&#34;&gt;tango film club&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carlos Di Sarli Documentary</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2013/03/30/carlos-di-sarli-documentary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 08:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2013/03/30/carlos-di-sarli-documentary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/DiSarli.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/DiSarli.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DiSarli&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Realidad Bonaerense, there is a new &lt;a href=&#34;http://realidadbonaerense.blogspot.no/2013/03/se-estrena-el-film-carlos-di-sarli-el.html&#34;&gt;documentary about Carlos di Sarli&lt;/a&gt; coming out, directed by Alberto Freinquel. No information about dvd or download edition, but there will be several public viewings in Buenos Aires and in Bahía Blanca, I think. The article mentions several dramatized sequences, which makes me a bit sceptical, but I guess you have to do something if there is little historical material available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EDIT: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.enterateantes.com.ar/merecida-reparacion-historica-a-carlos-di-sarli/&#34;&gt;A bit more information here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango Libre</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2012/11/07/tango-libre/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2012 15:49:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2012/11/07/tango-libre/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/J1WbRbxBqmk&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;There is another tango film coming up. This &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.artemisproductions.com/index.php?c=c4ca4238a0b923820dcc509a6f75849b&amp;amp;v=da4fb5c6e93e74d3df8527599fa62642&#34;&gt;Belgian production&lt;/a&gt; is starring Chicho, and although tango films can be a mixed bag, and I have my doubts how much drama it can yield, it looks sort of interesting. Apparently &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.filmneweurope.com/news/poland/104057-tango-libre-wins-warsaw-grand-prix/menu-id-158&#34;&gt;it won the Warsaw Film Festival Grand Prix&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Milonga&#34; -- tango short</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2012/02/20/milonga----tango-short/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2012 09:53:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2012/02/20/milonga----tango-short/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/P6JYeEcxnUU&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Well done, methinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HT &lt;a href=&#34;http://alextangofuego.blogspot.com/2012/02/cortometraggio-milonga-di-marco-calvise.html&#34;&gt;Alex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valentino</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/09/16/valentino/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2011 20:49:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/09/16/valentino/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/M1fourAkSJU&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I have this weird interest in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/05/24/tango-in-popular-culture/&#34;&gt;popular culture image of tango&lt;/a&gt;, for a large part constituted by various more or less successful renditions of the tango on the silver screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a matter of fact I have been looking for this particular rendition since I saw still photos in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Tango-Dance-Story-Simon-Collier/dp/0500279799/&#34;&gt;tango book by Collier et al&lt;/a&gt;. And &lt;a href=&#34;http://tangocommuter1.blogspot.com/2011/08/for-change.html&#34;&gt;thanks to Tangocommuter&lt;/a&gt;, I realized &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0076868/&#34;&gt;Valentino&lt;/a&gt; (1977) by Ken Russell was released on DVD. Well, sort of, like many of Valentino&amp;rsquo;s silents, it was actually a print on demand edition, no extras, no subtitles etc, just the movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Valentino early catched my attention as the iconic Hollywood tango hero, and he was a fascinating character &amp;ndash; but we&amp;rsquo;ll stick to the tango for now.  One thing that puzzled me in&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/02/14/rose-in-mouth/&#34;&gt; tracing back the origins of some of the tango cliches&lt;/a&gt;, was that people were talking dismissively of the tango of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rodolfo_Valentino&#34;&gt;Rodolpho Valentino&lt;/a&gt;, but his dancing wasn&amp;rsquo;t at all that bad. Bear in mind that there are some really awful tango scenes in the history of film, and that the tango of the turn of the century must have been rather different from the tango of the forties and fifties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, I remember the milongueros talk about the ridiculous tango of Valentino in&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0094106/&#34;&gt; Tango: Bayle Nuestro&lt;/a&gt;, which was released in 1988. After watching Nureyev&amp;rsquo;s Valentino, some additional pieces found their place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tangocommuter actually warned me about not having too high expectations. Now, where I live, renting is not really an option, all out of the mainstream has to be ordered on the internet. I can live with that, although it means I end up having a rather eccentric dvd collection. Russell apparently wasn&amp;rsquo;t too happy with the result himself, calling it &lt;a href=&#34;http://entertainment.timesonline.co.uk/tol/arts_and_entertainment/film/article2870480.ece&#34;&gt;his biggest mistake&lt;/a&gt;. I have to confess I haven&amp;rsquo;t really watched many of his films, but if you ask me, he comes off as something of a prick that regrets not picking the script that won several Oscars and his supposedly introspective  list of mistakes includes gems such as &amp;ldquo; Never give an unreliable member of the crew a second chance&amp;rdquo;. Maybe I just don&amp;rsquo;t get the British sense of humour, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how it applies to himself. I would choose Valentino every time, and other people have successfully made&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0045152/&#34;&gt; a classic&lt;/a&gt; out of related material. (Apparently they both quote/parody one particular love scene of Valentino&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0015145/&#34;&gt;Monsieur Beaucaire&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, Russell&amp;rsquo;s work hasn&amp;rsquo;t really aged well, it&amp;rsquo;s a typical 70s flick, and not in a good way. It&amp;rsquo;s not really historically correct either, which is ok I guess, but I would think Valentino&amp;rsquo;s life had enough drama as it were. And Nureyev isn&amp;rsquo;t really an outstanding actor. Ballet dancer: yes. Tango dancer: not really.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which brings me to the missing piece of the puzzle. Or at least it will serve as my working theory for now. Isn&amp;rsquo;t it much more likely that the milongueros of the eighties had Russell&amp;rsquo;s/Nureyev&amp;rsquo;s Valentino in mind when they spoke of Valentino, considering it ran only a few years earlier, while &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0012190/&#34;&gt;the silent movie was from 1921&lt;/a&gt;. I somehow doubt &amp;lsquo;The four horsemen&amp;rsquo; was shown regularly in Argentina after the sound movie arrived around 1930.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Possibly, the image of Hollywood tango is actually Russell&amp;rsquo;s image of Hollywood&amp;rsquo;s image of the tango. Now how is that for distorted tango?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Documentary: Eyes Closed -- Ad occhi chiusi</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/11/17/upcoming-documentary-eyes-closed----ad-occhi-chiusi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2010 08:41:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/11/17/upcoming-documentary-eyes-closed----ad-occhi-chiusi/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/TtCQfGcuOk8&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I missed (at least) one on my last post on upcoming movies. This one is an Italian documentary.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adocchichiusi.com/eyesclosed.html&#34;&gt;Here is a link to the film website for more information&lt;/a&gt;, and here is a link to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=W4NnMP1H4wc&#34;&gt;Italian version of the trailer&lt;/a&gt; for those who prefer. From the website:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;This will be the story of Rossana, a young Italian artist, who rediscovers her femininity by means of the Tango, going through a real metamorphosis which is enhanced by the sparkle in her eyes when telling her story. We will meet Nicola and Pietro, that fight their disease in the steps of tango.

These intertwined stories are enriched by the voices and faces of the numerous protagonists: ordinary people who attend the “Milonga Illegal”, teachers and professional dancers, highly-rated scholars and researchers in many different fields of discipline who share an interest in the study of psychological and sociocultural behaviour behind this passion.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone knows what Italian dialect are the first few Itialians are speaking? I&amp;rsquo;ve never heard that way of speaking Italian before, I think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HT: Ilene&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Tango Movies: &#34;Tanguero&#34; and &#34;La cantante de tango&#34;</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/11/12/upcoming-tango-movies-tanguero-and-la-cantante-de-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2010 17:16:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/11/12/upcoming-tango-movies-tanguero-and-la-cantante-de-tango/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;A short update on a couple of upcoming tango movies. I find it somewhat promising that none of them seem to be about a middle aged dancer or hit man coming to Buenos Aires and there discovering tango and through it, themselves. Still, they may include other clichés such as lost love and finding oneself through tango:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tanguero&#34;&gt;Tanguero&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Omar, a Tango instructor, is forced to return to Buenos Aires because of an important phone call. He discovers an unrecognizable city, meets relatives, old friends and meets Veronica, his childhood friend. They remember the time they had spent together years before and decide to take on a difficult challenge. That’s how Omar rediscovers himself in Tango.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tangueromovie.com/&#34;&gt;Tanguero&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;la-cantante-de-tango&#34;&gt;La cantante de tango&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/_VIzIi-ii7U&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;Helena, una talentosa cantante de tango, se encuentra profundamente enamorada. Cuando consigue presentarse en un prestigioso teatro de Buenos Aires, su carrera parece despegar. Pero justo en ese momento la alcanza la tragedia: el hombre que ella ama ya no está enamorado de ella. Obsesionada y torturada por su pérdida, no puede recuperarse de su ruptura y lentamente se convierte en una sombra de la mujer que solía ser. Pero ¿Y si dejara atrás la pena y se atreviera a una nueva vida en un país distinto? Quizás así Helena podría también dejar atrás el dolor y,  lentamente, aprender a vivir y amar de nuevo.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://lacantantedetango.com.ar/&#34;&gt;La cantante de tango&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HT: &lt;a href=&#34;http://tinatangos.com/blog/&#34;&gt;Tina&lt;/a&gt; (Tanguero) and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.2xtango.com/?p=7720&#34;&gt;2XTango&lt;/a&gt; (La cantante de tango)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tango Hustle</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/05/14/the-tango-hustle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2010 18:39:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/05/14/the-tango-hustle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2010/04/tango-hustle.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2010/04/tango-hustle.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;So&amp;hellip; what are &lt;strong&gt;these guys up to?&lt;/strong&gt; There I was, attending my very first tango festival. I did not know very much about tango, but I did know enough to notice this couple. They were dancing, but they were doing something quite different&amp;hellip; Different indeed. Yet there was something tangoish over it. Not quite ballroom tango, not quite Argentine tango, still a hint of tango.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only watching Saturday Night Fever probably years later, did I realize: What they had been doing was the &lt;strong&gt;tango hustle&lt;/strong&gt;. According to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hustle_(dance)&#34;&gt;Wikipedia Hustle entry&lt;/a&gt;, the tango hustle was in fact invented by the crew for this scene. You can watch a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tcm.com/mediaroom/index.jsp?cid=294904&#34;&gt;clip from Saturday Night Fever with the tango hustle&lt;/a&gt; here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, the opening walk of John Travolta in the very same movie is a must see if you need an illustration of how much can be in &amp;ldquo;just walking&amp;rdquo;. But you don&amp;rsquo;t need that, do you?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homero Manzi, un poeta en la tormenta</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/23/homero-manzi-un-poeta-en-la-tormenta/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 23:35:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/23/homero-manzi-un-poeta-en-la-tormenta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/09/23/homero-manzi-un-poeta-en-la-tormenta/manzi/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/09/manzi.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;manzi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.manzilapelicula.com.ar/&#34;&gt;new film&lt;/a&gt; about the tango poet &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.todotango.com/english/creadores/manzi.html&#34;&gt;Homero Manzi&lt;/a&gt; was just released in Argentina. Manzi is the author of famous tangos like &lt;em&gt;Malena&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Sur&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Barrio de tango&lt;/em&gt;. He worked with Troilo for several years, and in cooperation with Sebastián Piana, he revitalized the milonga genre with &lt;em&gt;Milonga sentimental&lt;/em&gt; in 1931.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film is apparently a combination of archive material and reconstruction of scenes from his life. It will be interesting to watch, I will probably wait until it is available on dvd, hopefully it won&amp;rsquo;t take that long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.10tango.com/notas/135391-homero-manzi-biopic&#34;&gt;more about the film here&lt;/a&gt; or watch the trailer here:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/Ljh5eGAiChU&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;HT: &lt;a href=&#34;http://jantango.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;Janis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mickey Mouse -- The Gallopin&#39; Gaucho (1928)</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/10/mickey-mouse----the-gallopin-gaucho-1928/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2009 03:02:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/10/mickey-mouse----the-gallopin-gaucho-1928/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/dUgoYfl5h94&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;HT: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ShelleyDelayne/status/3215344512&#34;&gt;ShelleyDelaine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valentina&#39;s Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/25/valentinas-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2009 03:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/25/valentinas-tango/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://simbatango.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/valentinas-tango.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;valentinas-tango&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got a tip about this film that I never heard about, starring rightly famous tango dancer Guillermina Quiroga, arguably one of the best female show dancers of our time. Browsing the reviews online, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really sure this was something for me, but as it was available on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.netflix.com/&#34;&gt;Netflix&lt;/a&gt;, I decided to give Guillermina a chance. This is what Netflix writes about the film:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Teetering on the edge of madness, striking dancer Valentina (Guillermina Quiriga) keeps the obsessive love she has for her husband, Eduardo (Jordi Caballero), in check by dancing the tango with him. But as time goes on, she slowly drifts into insanity. As Valentina&#39;s family tries to rescue her, they instead find themselves drawn into her nightmarish world. George Perez and Dianna Miranda co-star in this passionate drama peppered with dark comedy.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watched this movie right after reading this, and I had to re-read it just after finishing it, as I couldn&amp;rsquo;t really make it fit. It is all written in codes, you see. Let me translate that for you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tango dancer Valentina (Guillermina Quiroga) has an &amp;ndash; uhm &amp;ndash; unusal apetite for her husband Eduardo (Jordi Caballero). Performing with him is essential to keeping her satisfied. When he gets hurt so he can&amp;rsquo;t dance, she starts drinking and dreaming. While Eduardo cannot run his club, the couple&amp;rsquo;s grown up sons create an awful mess. George Perez and Dianna  Miranda co-star in this meant to be erotic drama with occational black humour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A rather embarrasing affair, to be honest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not even the dancing is up to par, it takes two to tango, and Guillermina&amp;rsquo;s partners aren&amp;rsquo;t really up to the task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt; While occationally funny, it is clearly going to the &amp;lsquo;stay away from&amp;rsquo;-list together with Tango fatal. What is it with tango and film&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Funny observation:&lt;/strong&gt; It struck me that the male dancer in the animated short &lt;em&gt;En tus brazos&lt;/em&gt; that &lt;a href=&#34;simbatango.com/2009/06/24/great-tango-shorts/&#34;&gt;I mentioned&lt;/a&gt; a while ago might well be modeled after the Eduardo character in Valentina&amp;rsquo;s Tango, wheelchair and all.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great tango shorts</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/25/great-tango-shorts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2009 00:58:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/25/great-tango-shorts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;None of these are exactly new, but Tanghi Argentini just became available on youtube about a week ago, thanks a lot to Janis for &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/06/20/nice-film-tangos/#comment-128&#34;&gt;the tip&lt;/a&gt;! Nominated for the Academy Awards 2008 for best live action short:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/isDtYDmANkI&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;And this animated one is not so light hearted, but no less romantic:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/3PU5Tsx36E0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nice film tangos</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/20/nice-film-tangos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2009 20:44:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/20/nice-film-tangos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;ldquo;&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;600&amp;rdquo; caption=&amp;ldquo;From Happy Together&amp;rdquo;]&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.timezone.fr/uploaded_images/happy_together_tony_leslie_8_d302bfe6a3de421aa6c37d9b4627eca7-798476.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;From Happy Together&#34; /&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, tango is not always portrayed as completely kitsch in films. So I found that a handful of very nice films, with equally nice tango mandated a post of its own. These are all highly recommended, tango or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0118845/&#34;&gt;Happy together&lt;/a&gt; by Wong Kar-Wai. He is actually one of my favourite directors, and uses tango as one way to tell us about the relationship and love between two people. One of whom work for some time in a tango bar in Buenos Aires. Not in a cliched fashion, which is quite a feat, given &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/05/24/tango-in-popular-culture/&#34;&gt;what is out there&lt;/a&gt;. Come to think of it, I probably should see this film again sometime soon myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the eccentric characters in the Almodóvaresque &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0310001/&#34;&gt;Piedras&lt;/a&gt; by Spanish director Ramón Salazar, actually go to a milongas. The man, who is an Argentine brings a women, and he talks to her about the Argentine saying &amp;lsquo;Sacando viruta al piso&amp;rsquo;.  As far as I can remember, the dancing in the Madrid milonga was quite &amp;lsquo;authentic&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0436445/&#34;&gt;No suis là pour être aimé&lt;/a&gt; (Not here to be loved) almost made it to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/04/19/tango-film-club/&#34;&gt;film club post&lt;/a&gt;, as the main characters in this movie actually take tango lessons. And the lessons have a profound impact on the characters&amp;rsquo; lives. In addition, they watch a show by Geraldine and Javier. So plenty of tango, and a nice film. How she came to fall for him is still a mystery, though. Never underestimate the power of tango, I guess&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it is indeed possible. There must be more that I am unaware of or have forgotten. What are your favourites?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>