<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tango in Film on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/categories/tango-in-film/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tango in Film on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 11:43:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/categories/tango-in-film/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Last Tango -- Copes y Nieves</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2015/09/10/our-last-tango-copes-y-nieves/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 11:43:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2015/09/10/our-last-tango-copes-y-nieves/</guid>
      <description>Now this looks like something to look forward to:
In „Our Last Tango“ Juan and María tell their story to a group of young tango dancers and choreographers from Buenos Aires, who transform the most beautiful, moving and dramatic moments of Juan and Maria’s lives into incredible tango-choreographies. These beautifully-shot choreographies compliment the soul-searching interviews and documentary moments of the film to make this an unforgettable journey into the heart of the tango.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fermin, Glorias del Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2014/10/06/fermin-glorias-del-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2014 20:44:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2014/10/06/fermin-glorias-del-tango/</guid>
      <description>http://vimeo.com/ondemand/fermin
Fermin, Glorias del Tango is now available for rental at Vimeo. Looks nice, I think. I haven&amp;rsquo;t had time to watch it, and I sort of wait for the download that was supposed to come with my Kickstarter support. Oh well.
EDIT: I worked it out with Oliver Kolker. Apparently I missed an email that was sent to all backers. Oliver promptly gave me access to the film and I experienced no further problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glorias del Tango -- New Tango Feature Film</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2013/08/07/glorias-del-tango-new-tango-feature-film/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2013 20:58:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2013/08/07/glorias-del-tango-new-tango-feature-film/</guid>
      <description>This new project looks interesting, you can support it on kickstarter. Not sure I believe the story, but the flashbacks look promising. On the other hand, it sounds much more believeable than Assasination Tango.
&#34;Glorias del Tango&#34; is an ambitious and exciting feature film that will end the decade-long silence of tango on the silver screen. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to it. Time to revive the tango film club?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carlos Di Sarli Documentary</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2013/03/30/carlos-di-sarli-documentary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 08:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2013/03/30/carlos-di-sarli-documentary/</guid>
      <description>According to Realidad Bonaerense, there is a new documentary about Carlos di Sarli coming out, directed by Alberto Freinquel. No information about dvd or download edition, but there will be several public viewings in Buenos Aires and in Bahía Blanca, I think. The article mentions several dramatized sequences, which makes me a bit sceptical, but I guess you have to do something if there is little historical material available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango Libre</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2012/11/07/tango-libre/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2012 15:49:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2012/11/07/tango-libre/</guid>
      <description>There is another tango film coming up. This Belgian production is starring Chicho, and although tango films can be a mixed bag, and I have my doubts how much drama it can yield, it looks sort of interesting. Apparently it won the Warsaw Film Festival Grand Prix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Milonga&#34; -- tango short</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2012/02/20/milonga-tango-short/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2012 09:53:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2012/02/20/milonga-tango-short/</guid>
      <description>Well done, methinks.
HT Alex</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valentino</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2011/09/16/valentino/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2011 20:49:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2011/09/16/valentino/</guid>
      <description>I have this weird interest in the popular culture image of tango, for a large part constituted by various more or less successful renditions of the tango on the silver screen.
As a matter of fact I have been looking for this particular rendition since I saw still photos in the tango book by Collier et al. And thanks to Tangocommuter, I realized Valentino (1977) by Ken Russell was released on DVD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Documentary: Eyes Closed -- Ad occhi chiusi</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/11/17/upcoming-documentary-eyes-closed-ad-occhi-chiusi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2010 08:41:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/11/17/upcoming-documentary-eyes-closed-ad-occhi-chiusi/</guid>
      <description>I missed (at least) one on my last post on upcoming movies. This one is an Italian documentary. Here is a link to the film website for more information, and here is a link to the Italian version of the trailer for those who prefer. From the website:
This will be the story of Rossana, a young Italian artist, who rediscovers her femininity by means of the Tango, going through a real metamorphosis which is enhanced by the sparkle in her eyes when telling her story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Tango Movies: &#34;Tanguero&#34; and &#34;La cantante de tango&#34;</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/11/12/upcoming-tango-movies-tanguero-and-la-cantante-de-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2010 17:16:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/11/12/upcoming-tango-movies-tanguero-and-la-cantante-de-tango/</guid>
      <description>A short update on a couple of upcoming tango movies. I find it somewhat promising that none of them seem to be about a middle aged dancer or hit man coming to Buenos Aires and there discovering tango and through it, themselves. Still, they may include other clichés such as lost love and finding oneself through tango:
Tanguero Omar, a Tango instructor, is forced to return to Buenos Aires because of an important phone call.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tango Hustle</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/05/14/the-tango-hustle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2010 18:39:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/05/14/the-tango-hustle/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ndash;So&amp;hellip; what are these guys up to? There I was, attending my very first tango festival. I did not know very much about tango, but I did know enough to notice this couple. They were dancing, but they were doing something quite different&amp;hellip; Different indeed. Yet there was something tangoish over it. Not quite ballroom tango, not quite Argentine tango, still a hint of tango.
Only watching Saturday Night Fever probably years later, did I realize: What they had been doing was the tango hustle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homero Manzi, un poeta en la tormenta</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/23/homero-manzi-un-poeta-en-la-tormenta/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 23:35:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/09/23/homero-manzi-un-poeta-en-la-tormenta/</guid>
      <description>A new film about the tango poet Homero Manzi was just released in Argentina. Manzi is the author of famous tangos like Malena, Sur and Barrio de tango. He worked with Troilo for several years, and in cooperation with Sebastián Piana, he revitalized the milonga genre with Milonga sentimental in 1931.
The film is apparently a combination of archive material and reconstruction of scenes from his life. It will be interesting to watch, I will probably wait until it is available on dvd, hopefully it won&amp;rsquo;t take that long.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mickey Mouse -- The Gallopin&#39; Gaucho (1928)</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/10/mickey-mouse-the-gallopin-gaucho-1928/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2009 03:02:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/08/10/mickey-mouse-the-gallopin-gaucho-1928/</guid>
      <description>HT: ShelleyDelaine</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valentina&#39;s Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/25/valentinas-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2009 03:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/07/25/valentinas-tango/</guid>
      <description>I got a tip about this film that I never heard about, starring rightly famous tango dancer Guillermina Quiroga, arguably one of the best female show dancers of our time. Browsing the reviews online, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really sure this was something for me, but as it was available on Netflix, I decided to give Guillermina a chance. This is what Netflix writes about the film:
Teetering on the edge of madness, striking dancer Valentina (Guillermina Quiriga) keeps the obsessive love she has for her husband, Eduardo (Jordi Caballero), in check by dancing the tango with him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great tango shorts</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/25/great-tango-shorts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2009 00:58:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/25/great-tango-shorts/</guid>
      <description>None of these are exactly new, but Tanghi Argentini just became available on youtube about a week ago, thanks a lot to Janis for the tip! Nominated for the Academy Awards 2008 for best live action short:
  And this animated one is not so light hearted, but no less romantic:
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nice film tangos</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/20/nice-film-tangos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2009 20:44:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/20/nice-film-tangos/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;600&amp;rdquo; caption=&amp;ldquo;From Happy Together&amp;rdquo;][/caption]
Fortunately, tango is not always portrayed as completely kitsch in films. So I found that a handful of very nice films, with equally nice tango mandated a post of its own. These are all highly recommended, tango or not.
First Happy together by Wong Kar-Wai. He is actually one of my favourite directors, and uses tango as one way to tell us about the relationship and love between two people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>El otro camino</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/19/el-otro-camino/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2009 02:50:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/19/el-otro-camino/</guid>
      <description>by i_gallagher
Una vez, tocando con una pequeña orquesta en la escuela de música popular -- eran estudiantes; yo me sentí, tocando con ellos, me sentí cómodo. Pero físicamente cómodo, como cuando uno se siente con la ropa de entrecasa. Y dije: &#34;¿Que me pasa? Y de pronto, la orquesta estaba tocando, esa orquesta de la escuela en un concierto y salen a bailar algunas personas. Y yo ví eso y dije: &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango in popular culture</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/24/tango-in-popular-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2009 20:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/24/tango-in-popular-culture/</guid>
      <description>There is something about the word tango that seems to have a power in itself. Everybody seems to share the idea that tango is something special. Tango&amp;rsquo;s strong image in the public conscience is not quite the same as we tango addicts have, as we actually know the authentic tango culture and (I suppose) think of it when we hear the word.
To a large degree, the image the general public has of tango is imposed from the depiction of tango in popular culture, and movies in particular.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Film search</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/03/film-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2009 17:34:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/03/film-search/</guid>
      <description>by?Auntie P
Even after gathering quite a collection of tango movies, there are always some missing. Some are not available commercially, and that makes it hard. If anyone knows how to get any of these, I would be happy to know!
 Naked tango
 Flop (featuring Miguel Angel Zotto &amp;amp; Milena Plebs)
 Sur
 Tangos, exilio de Gardel
  Thanks to tango commuter for making me aware of the last two.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Luna de Avellaneda</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/03/luna-de-avellaneda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2009 13:05:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/03/luna-de-avellaneda/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;460&amp;rdquo; caption=&amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;Castillo&amp;rdquo; singing at club &amp;ldquo;Luna de Avellaneda&amp;rdquo;&amp;ldquo;][/caption]
Speaking of tango films, there are several films where tango is not a main theme, but with some interesting tango scenes. The film Luna de Avellaneda is quite nice, and stands out in that respect. For tango lovers, the opening scene is not to be missed, as it reconstructs the grand party of a community milonga in the golden age of tango.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango Film Club</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/04/19/tango-film-club/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2009 15:26:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/04/19/tango-film-club/</guid>
      <description>by atomicjeep
I was planning to write a separate post for each of those, but I never seem to find the time&amp;hellip; The recent posts by tangocommuter prompted me to write up this list of my favorite tango films. I never was all that interestesd in instructional videos, but films about the culture I find fascinating. In our small community we arranged public showings in an informal tango film club to make these gems available to the rest of the community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rose in mouth</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/13/rose-in-mouth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2009 22:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/02/13/rose-in-mouth/</guid>
      <description>by alyssathiele
The tango cliché of dancing with a rose in the mouth is quite fascinating. It is everywhere, and everybody doing argentine tango wants absolutely nothing to do with it. But where does it come from?
I have often seen it associated with the silent movie star Rudolph Valentino, and suggested that it first appeared in the movie Four Horsemen of the Apocalypse (1921). So being curious, I had to check this out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 tangos</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/01/12-tangos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 11:24:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/01/12-tangos/</guid>
      <description>Just ordered the new documentary 12 tangos. Will be very interesting to see, it also claims to be a Buena Vista Tango Club, so a shootout between 12 tangos and Cafe de los maestros. 12 tangos has a great advantage in being actually available.
I will get back to it later, in the meantime, the trailer:
[youtube]http://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=mrFklWP6dQY&amp;amp;feature=related[/youtube]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lágrima Ríos &amp; Candombe</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/28/lagrima-rios-candombe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2008 22:13:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/28/lagrima-rios-candombe/</guid>
      <description>I just love the name! Lágrima Ríos is a wonderful artistic name, Rivers of tears.. Re tango, no?
My attention was brought to some of her recordings by Michael&amp;rsquo;s music blog, discussing some available recordings of hers. Luckily, I was able to find them both at emusic for instant satisfaction :-) She is featured in the film Café de los maestros, which I have not yet been able to get hold of (but will eventually!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Putting the baby to sleep</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/14/putting-the-baby-to-sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 20:49:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/14/putting-the-baby-to-sleep/</guid>
      <description>I quite recently became a father, and the poor child is exposed to a lot of tango music, naturally. (And I get out to dance less, hence the blog writing.) Before he was born, I used to talk about how we would practice walking together, he and I. Now this is how it turned out:
The scene: Unpatiant 12 days old boy, waiting for his mother to get ready for breast-feeding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Café de los maestros</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/13/cafe-de-los-maestros/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2008 13:33:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/13/cafe-de-los-maestros/</guid>
      <description>Always looking out for new films about tango, both dance and music, I must say I am really looking forward to this one: Café de los maestros. It has been described as the tango equivalent to the _Buena Vista Social Club. I already got the soundtrack, so I know the music is excellent. Can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see it. _
When oh when will it become available on DVD? It will never be shown on the silver screen where I live I&amp;rsquo;m afraid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ideal</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/23/the-ideal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2008 21:08:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/23/the-ideal/</guid>
      <description>The previous post about Confiteria Ideal reminded me of the first visit to Buenos Aires back in 2001. This was before YouTube, remember, and there was lots of rumors about everything, and not so much tango information available on the web.
Being interested in architecture as well as in tango, trying to find the location for a scene in the film Tango by Carlos Saura, we were told by someone that we should go to one of the oldest milongas in Buenos Aires, yes our source believed it would be the same milonga that was pictured in the movie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>O Ultimo Bandoneón</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/08/21/o-ultimo-bandoneon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2008 18:39:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/08/21/o-ultimo-bandoneon/</guid>
      <description>It is actually possible to get hold of this, but I had to order it from Brazil, so it was with portuguese subtitles, which was - challenging, but a very nice film it was. Recommended.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>El último bandoneón</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/22/la-ultima-bandoneon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2008 10:15:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/22/la-ultima-bandoneon/</guid>
      <description>httpvh://youtube.com/watch?v=eGerxiMniBQ
Maravillosa!
Now where can I get the entire film?
Trailer here:
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clichés</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/06/cliches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2008 10:31:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/07/06/cliches/</guid>
      <description>Ever since I started dancing, the topic of tango clichés has fascinated me. The rose in mouth, castanets, head flicks, dramatic poses are all parts of what usually pops into people&amp;rsquo;s heads when they hear the word tango. Where did they come from, and why did they stick? Going through a lot of Hollywood production at least gives a partial answer, and Rudolph Valentino is one of the people to blame, the rose in mouth appears in the film Blood and sand, where he plays a bullfighter, while the film he dances the tango is _Four horsemen of the apocalypse.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>