<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Javier Rodriguez on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/tags/javier-rodriguez/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Javier Rodriguez on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/tags/javier-rodriguez/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Years Anniversary</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/09/07/10-years-anniversary/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2010 13:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/09/07/10-years-anniversary/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/1dUQ7xrEwlU&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;It is exactly 10 years since I first put a hesitating foot on a festival dance floor today. So I thought it would be fun to refresh my memories and reflect a bit on where I was then, and what I still keep from that time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were just entering the local tango scene, and didn&amp;rsquo;t really know anything about tango at all. We had seen Carlos Saura&amp;rsquo;s Tango, maybe Sally Potter&amp;rsquo;s Tango Lesson, but probably not yet at that time. Nobody in our community at that time had ever been to Buenos Aires. There was no youtube. Most, if not all of the visiting teachers were regional teachers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a lot of buzz, we just had to go to this festival.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to a few regional teachers, the festival featured Gustavo Naveira &amp;amp; Giselle Anne, Antonio Cervila Junior &amp;amp; Vanina Bilous, Julio Balmaceda &amp;amp; Corina de la Rosa and Javier Rodriguez &amp;amp; Geraldine Rojas. None of these names meant anything to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The workshops were spread out on several venues, so we had to run around to find the next workshop, and in the few moments in passing by the few people we knew from before, they were making comments on the dance floor quality (whether it was slippery, coarse, hard, soft etc) which puzzled us, as that was not issues in our thinking about dancing. It was a strange world, this tango scene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The single workshop I remember most clearly was with a couple that should well known to anyone that has been in tango for more than a few months (this is the presentation on the festival website, 2000):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;**Javier Rodriguez** &amp; **Geraldine Rojas** (Argentina)
Geraldine is only 18 years old, but she surprises everybody with her capacity as a tango dancer. The couple is one of the &#34;hottest&#34; at the moment. They expose a youthful enthusiasm and joy that the public loves.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure we signed up for workshops at the lowest level with visiting instructors, Beginner II (Just above absolute beginners):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Beginner II:
Approximately from 3 months to 1 year of classes and practice of dancing. Should know: Walking forward and backward, the two basic salidas, forward and backward ochos and placing of the body in all the cases.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a warm up exercise, J&amp;amp;G did forward ochos, the woman doing overturned ochos and the man doing forward ochos as sacadas. It was a disaster. Not one single couple in the class were able to do it. J&amp;amp;G must have been terribly disappointed with the level of the class. They were mumbling &amp;lsquo;catastrophe&amp;rsquo; among themselves as we tried in vain to stay on our feet with a minimal degree of dignity and control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless they made a lasting impression. Despite several detours over the years, this was the tango we eventually came back to. Calm, controlled, elegantly walking and with a great heart. I think watching this amazing couple at an early stage was very important in creating a vision of what tango was really like in my mind. Even if I didn&amp;rsquo;t know it myself at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both &lt;a href=&#34;http://simbatango.com/2009/02/22/body-parts/&#34;&gt;Julio and Corina&lt;/a&gt; and Gustavo and Giselle were teachers that we would take many lessons with over the following years. Unfortunate circumstances prevented us from taking lessons with Javier and Geraldine again, even if we did try. And when we finally managed to take lessons with Javier again, he and Geraldine already split up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two years later, Natacha Poberaj, then touring with Roberto Herrera, asked in a workshop whether I was taking lessons with Javier and Geraldine, which was hard to answer since we did not take many lessons with them, but we liked their dancing a lot. So yes and no&amp;hellip;  She asked because something about Simba reminded her of Javier. I still have no idea what that could have been, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It could be that I put too much weight on this, but from my own experience first impressions matter. Which is one reason I think it is so important to bring first class dancers to my community. Not some mediocre regional couple. Some of the best. The real deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we can expect people to find their own tango, they have to see the real tango. Smell the real tango. Touch the real tango. Listen to the real tango. And feel the real tango.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is what happened to me ten years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Essence of Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/16/tango-essence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2010 19:30:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/16/tango-essence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.eltangauta.com/images/ediciones/184_Tapahome.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;When we watched the milongueros dancing years ago, we could perceive the mystery behind what they did, no matter if it was easy or difficult. Therefore, technique has to be understood first, then it can be copied, but the goal is to get to its essence. If you use the word &#34;technique&#34; less in class, and instead use words like &#34;essence&#34; and &#34;sensation&#34;, students can perform the movement with a more natural attitude and will learn faster than if you speak about numbers, diagonals or muscles.

&gt; 
&gt; Javier Rodríguez
&gt; 
&gt; 
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good advice from the maestros. They also talk about the decline of the European tango scene and our fear of the embrace. Read the &lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/9cYFra&#34;&gt;entire interview at El tangauta&lt;/a&gt; (#184 Feb 2010). [EDIT: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eltangauta.com/nota.asp?id=1438&amp;amp;idedicion=0#nota-mas&#34;&gt;Direct link here&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A morir</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/19/a-morir/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2009 01:24:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/19/a-morir/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/xanboozled/1234201847/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1008/1234201847_ff1e1561e3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;More fun with Mantis by Xanboozled, on Flickr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/2.0/80x15.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.0 Generic License&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/xanboozled/&#34;&gt; Xanboozled&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagecodr.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

&gt; 
&gt; 

_--When a man walks nicely, the woman dies in his embrace._
&gt; 
&gt; 
--_When a man walks badly, the woman wants to die._&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HT: &lt;a href=&#34;http://tango.yyquest.net/techniques/2009/more-on-walking/&#34;&gt;yy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breathtaking</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/12/breathtaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 20:04:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/12/breathtaking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was so excited to see how it worked out with Stella and Javier on their tour this year. And this is just soooo beautiful! My piano teacher used to tell me when I practiced the hard parts: don&amp;rsquo;t forget breathing! This left me breathless, so dear reader, unless you can keep your breath for three minutes: don&amp;rsquo;t forget breathing!&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/Q0TooGHwzhA&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;HT: &lt;a href=&#34;http://nyctango.blogspot.com/2009/05/superb-musicality.html&#34;&gt;nyctango&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Putting the baby to sleep</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/14/putting-the-baby-to-sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 20:49:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/14/putting-the-baby-to-sleep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I quite recently became a father, and the poor child is exposed to a lot of tango music, naturally. (And I get out to dance less, hence the blog writing.) Before he was born, I used to talk about how we would practice walking together, he and I. Now this is how it turned out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scene: Unpatiant 12 days old boy, waiting for his mother to get ready for breast-feeding. Father to find something to entertain the child, and preferably also himself in the meantime. Time for tango. Di Sarli&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Nido Gaucho&lt;/em&gt; on the stereo, practicing the tango walk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boy seemed to enjoy the experience, I would say. Not as big eyes as with the milonga a few days earlyer (yes - really). After one tango and a half, he became more quiet. A few other songs from the same album, then the &lt;em&gt;Porteño y bailarín&lt;/em&gt; album from the start. The boy fell asleep in my arms. And I got to practice my walk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The funny thing about this, is that having a baby in your arms, getting it to sleep is a quite common metaphor for the way the woman should be held in the embrace. Soft, yet firm and secure.  I know at least El &amp;ldquo;Negro&amp;rdquo; Capello and Javier Rodríguez have used this metaphor. The thing is, I spent quite a lot of time practicing my tango embrace, but not making babies sleep. I got the idea, of course, but now I could apply the metaphor in the reverse direction, using my tango skills to get the boy to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, I fell asleep quite happily that night myself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confiteria La Ideal en BBC</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/23/confiteria-la-ideal-en-bbc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2008 20:49:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/23/confiteria-la-ideal-en-bbc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another good documentary about tango. I enjoyed it a lot. Some of the interesting scenes are available on youtube, but the documentary itself was quite hard to get hold of. As far as I could determine, it is not available for sale, not even on ebay, so you better know one of them pirates or use your imagination ;-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am quite impressed by how ordinary dancers are able to express what tango means to them. I always find it hard to describe what in tango I love so much or why I came to be obsessed with tango.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it made me long for Buenos Aires. A lot. And that hurt. But it was still a good experience, a tango experience I suppose.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/1TufSIR3onU&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;



&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/7r1mPWczWPk&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;



&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/y5CmBLdEY9A&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;



&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/T5_RnRny8kI&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>