<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Javier Rodriguez on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/tags/javier-rodriguez/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Javier Rodriguez on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2010 13:07:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/tags/javier-rodriguez/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Years Anniversary</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/09/07/10-years-anniversary/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2010 13:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/09/07/10-years-anniversary/</guid>
      <description>It is exactly 10 years since I first put a hesitating foot on a festival dance floor today. So I thought it would be fun to refresh my memories and reflect a bit on where I was then, and what I still keep from that time.
We were just entering the local tango scene, and didn&amp;rsquo;t really know anything about tango at all. We had seen Carlos Saura&amp;rsquo;s Tango, maybe Sally Potter&amp;rsquo;s Tango Lesson, but probably not yet at that time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Essence of Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/16/tango-essence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2010 19:30:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/02/16/tango-essence/</guid>
      <description>When we watched the milongueros dancing years ago, we could perceive the mystery behind what they did, no matter if it was easy or difficult. Therefore, technique has to be understood first, then it can be copied, but the goal is to get to its essence. If you use the word &#34;technique&#34; less in class, and instead use words like &#34;essence&#34; and &#34;sensation&#34;, students can perform the movement with a more natural attitude and will learn faster than if you speak about numbers, diagonals or muscles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A morir</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/19/a-morir/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2009 01:24:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/19/a-morir/</guid>
      <description>by Xanboozled
   _--When a man walks nicely, the woman dies in his embrace._   --_When a man walks badly, the woman wants to die._ HT: yy</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breathtaking</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/12/breathtaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 20:04:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/05/12/breathtaking/</guid>
      <description>I was so excited to see how it worked out with Stella and Javier on their tour this year. And this is just soooo beautiful! My piano teacher used to tell me when I practiced the hard parts: don&amp;rsquo;t forget breathing! This left me breathless, so dear reader, unless you can keep your breath for three minutes: don&amp;rsquo;t forget breathing!
  HT: nyctango</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Putting the baby to sleep</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/14/putting-the-baby-to-sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 20:49:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/14/putting-the-baby-to-sleep/</guid>
      <description>I quite recently became a father, and the poor child is exposed to a lot of tango music, naturally. (And I get out to dance less, hence the blog writing.) Before he was born, I used to talk about how we would practice walking together, he and I. Now this is how it turned out:
The scene: Unpatiant 12 days old boy, waiting for his mother to get ready for breast-feeding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confiteria La Ideal en BBC</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/23/confiteria-la-ideal-en-bbc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2008 20:49:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/09/23/confiteria-la-ideal-en-bbc/</guid>
      <description>Another good documentary about tango. I enjoyed it a lot. Some of the interesting scenes are available on youtube, but the documentary itself was quite hard to get hold of. As far as I could determine, it is not available for sale, not even on ebay, so you better know one of them pirates or use your imagination ;-)
I am quite impressed by how ordinary dancers are able to express what tango means to them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>