<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Musician on Simba Tango</title>
    <link>http://simbatango.com/categories/musician/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Musician on Simba Tango</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 17:54:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://simbatango.com/categories/musician/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Los Estilos Fundamentales de Tango 2 | Miguel Caló</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2016/10/01/los-estilos-fundamentales-de-tango-2-miguel-calo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 17:54:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2016/10/01/los-estilos-fundamentales-de-tango-2-miguel-calo/</guid>
      <description>The latest video from the Los Estilos Fundamentales del Tango is up. This time featuring Miguel Caló. Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Los Estilos Fundamentales del Tango 2 | Julio De Caro</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2016/06/19/los-estilos-fundamentales-del-tango-2-julio-de-caro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2016 20:23:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2016/06/19/los-estilos-fundamentales-del-tango-2-julio-de-caro/</guid>
      <description>The video from the seminar last week on Julio De Caro is up. Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Los estilos fundamentales del tango por Ignacio Varchausky | Alfredo Gobbi</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2015/10/26/los-estilos-fundamentales-del-tango-por-ignacio-varchausky-alfredo-gobbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 19:43:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2015/10/26/los-estilos-fundamentales-del-tango-por-ignacio-varchausky-alfredo-gobbi/</guid>
      <description>The Gobbi seminar video is up!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podestá Godoy, cantores | Documentary</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2015/10/07/podesta-godoy-cantores-documentary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2015 13:28:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2015/10/07/podesta-godoy-cantores-documentary/</guid>
      <description>A new documentary on tango singers Alberto Podestá and Juan Carlos Godoy by Daniel Tonelli and Marcelo Turrisi looks interesting. Hope it gets released on dvd or video on demand.
HT: Janis</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Los estilos fundamentales del tango por Ignacio Varchausky | Horacio Salgán</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2015/09/19/los-estilos-fundamentales-del-tango-por-ignacio-varchausky-horacio-salgan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2015 15:40:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2015/09/19/los-estilos-fundamentales-del-tango-por-ignacio-varchausky-horacio-salgan/</guid>
      <description>This time with video. Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carlos Di Sarli Documentary</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2013/03/30/carlos-di-sarli-documentary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 08:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2013/03/30/carlos-di-sarli-documentary/</guid>
      <description>According to Realidad Bonaerense, there is a new documentary about Carlos di Sarli coming out, directed by Alberto Freinquel. No information about dvd or download edition, but there will be several public viewings in Buenos Aires and in Bahía Blanca, I think. The article mentions several dramatized sequences, which makes me a bit sceptical, but I guess you have to do something if there is little historical material available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The &#39;Inventor of Jazz&#39; Plays the Tango</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2010/07/14/the-inventor-of-jazz-plays-the-tango/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2010 20:24:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2010/07/14/the-inventor-of-jazz-plays-the-tango/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ndash;There is this guy&amp;hellip;. and he plays the tango, too. I was at a Christmas party, sharing table with a guy that was writing his thesis on stride piano or pianists. Somehow the topic of tango had come up (strange, isn&amp;rsquo;t it?), and he was delighted to enlighten me about this early tango reference in American music. He promised to make me a copy, but that never materialized.
Nevertheless, I managed to track down the recordings myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>El otro camino</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/19/el-otro-camino/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2009 02:50:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2009/06/19/el-otro-camino/</guid>
      <description>by i_gallagher
Una vez, tocando con una pequeña orquesta en la escuela de música popular -- eran estudiantes; yo me sentí, tocando con ellos, me sentí cómodo. Pero físicamente cómodo, como cuando uno se siente con la ropa de entrecasa. Y dije: &#34;¿Que me pasa? Y de pronto, la orquesta estaba tocando, esa orquesta de la escuela en un concierto y salen a bailar algunas personas. Y yo ví eso y dije: &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technique vs. Feeling</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/27/technique-vs-feeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2008 21:42:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/27/technique-vs-feeling/</guid>
      <description>by my hovercraft is full of eels
Which one is most important? Technique or dancing with feeling? I sometimes get the impression that tango dancers are divided in two camps, the technique camp and the feelings camp. The first emphasizes the technical matters of the dance, the latter paying solely attention to the feeling. As long as we can hug each other, all is well ;-) Both seemingly ignoring the other point of view completely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 Tangos -- Adios Buenos Aires</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/19/12-tangos-adios-buenos-aires/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2008 17:06:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/19/12-tangos-adios-buenos-aires/</guid>
      <description>The documentary 12 tangos was just released in international version on DVD. It is a documentary, and the Adios Buenos Aires part of the title is somehow more accurate with regards to the content of the film. If you are looking for the Buena Vista Social Club of tango, you will be disappointed. There are no interviews with musicians, and only a few of the oldtimers participate in the orchestra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 tangos</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/01/12-tangos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 11:24:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/11/01/12-tangos/</guid>
      <description>Just ordered the new documentary 12 tangos. Will be very interesting to see, it also claims to be a Buena Vista Tango Club, so a shootout between 12 tangos and Cafe de los maestros. 12 tangos has a great advantage in being actually available.
I will get back to it later, in the meantime, the trailer:
[youtube]http://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=mrFklWP6dQY&amp;amp;feature=related[/youtube]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lágrima Ríos &amp; Candombe</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/28/lagrima-rios-candombe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2008 22:13:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/28/lagrima-rios-candombe/</guid>
      <description>I just love the name! Lágrima Ríos is a wonderful artistic name, Rivers of tears.. Re tango, no?
My attention was brought to some of her recordings by Michael&amp;rsquo;s music blog, discussing some available recordings of hers. Luckily, I was able to find them both at emusic for instant satisfaction :-) She is featured in the film Café de los maestros, which I have not yet been able to get hold of (but will eventually!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>¡Ahora, pollo!</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/26/ahora-pollo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2008 21:55:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/26/ahora-pollo/</guid>
      <description>Returning again to Buenos Aires, a lot more experienced and familiar with music and culture than the first time I had read that another Alberto was still live and kicking, Alberto Podestá that would be. We had some tango musicians from our city coming down, and thought it would be an excellent thing to do with them. Podestá is singing at the place La Cumparsita in San Telmo, but for some reason or another we never made it while our musicians were in town.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Café de los maestros</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/13/cafe-de-los-maestros/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2008 13:33:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/13/cafe-de-los-maestros/</guid>
      <description>Always looking out for new films about tango, both dance and music, I must say I am really looking forward to this one: Café de los maestros. It has been described as the tango equivalent to the _Buena Vista Social Club. I already got the soundtrack, so I know the music is excellent. Can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see it. _
When oh when will it become available on DVD? It will never be shown on the silver screen where I live I&amp;rsquo;m afraid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old tango hero</title>
      <link>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/09/old-tango-hero/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2008 20:53:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>simbatango@gmail.com (Simba)</author>
      <guid>http://simbatango.com/2008/10/09/old-tango-hero/</guid>
      <description>On our first visit to Buenos Aires, we rented a room in San Telmo. Right in the neighborhood is the Centro Cultural Torquato Tasso. For some reason we never came around to go there, even if it was by far the closest milonga.
Until one evening, we finally found space in our schedule to visit El Tasso. There was to be live music, and we were quite excited. The place was packed with people, and all of a sudden an old man was announced, and with support from a couple of guys he entered the stage.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>